<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NyNyUA" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/archives/mc_414">mc_414</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of NYU@200 <num>MC.414</num></titleproper><author>Nicole Greenhouse, Rachel Searcy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New York University Archives</publisher><p><date>November 2024</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-02-07 14:23:16 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 2025</date><item>Record updated by Rachel Searcy to reflect accessioning of born-digital projects</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New York University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of NYU@200</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Justice, Robert</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Gordon, Zuri</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Han, Seungkyoo (Peter)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Skorupa, Anna</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">La Vaglio, Michael</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Moorreade, Rofiat</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Francis, Ben</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Villacampa, Isabella</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname source="local">Bunde, Janet</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MC.414</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/resources/3542</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">138.1 Megabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 10 computer files</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2024" type="inclusive">2022-2024</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_54942a1260ca4d0fedfcbe43df1a92ae">The Records of NYU@200 consist of student projects completed for the NYU@200 course offered Fall 2022 and Fall 2023 in the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development. In this course, co-taught by Janet Bunde, University Archivist, and James Fraser, Professor of Education and History at NYU, students explore the history of higher education through a deep dive into the archives and history of New York University in the years just before its bicentennial in 2030. The Records of NYU@200 consist of electronic and web native records representing student projects completed for the course offered Fall 2022 and Fall 2023. Topics of the student projects in this collection include changes in teaching practices over time, the global NYU network, student-led advocacy through clubs and other groups, student protest movements at New York University in 1970, urban development in the Washington Square area, women in leadership at NYU, and the establishment of women's studies programs at NYU.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_3650de6c113b09c07c2b8e975aeefd8d">Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_cb94e006a888cab9686ac39bf9dcc850">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Records of NYU@200 consist of electronic and web native records representing student projects completed for the NYU@200 course offered Fall 2022 and Fall 2023 in the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development. Topics of the student projects in this collection include changes in teaching practices over time, the global NYU network, student-led advocacy through clubs and other groups, student protest movements at New York University in 1970, urban development in the Washington Square area, women in leadership at NYU, and the establishment of women's studies programs at NYU.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_83538830272c45796c8b06e9d71c12a4">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Project files in this collection were transferred by University Archivist Janet Bunde in October 2024 and January 2025. Digital files were transferred to Janet Bunde by Ben Francis, Seungkyoo (Peter) Han, Michael La Vaglio, Rofiat Moorreade, Anna Skorupa, and Isabella Villacampa after the completion of the course. Student work represented in this collection was intentionally transferred to the University Archives by the students, who signed release forms granting researcher access to these materials for noncommercial research, study, and teaching. The accession numbers for these transfers are 2024.077 and 2025.007.</p><p>https://wp.nyu.edu/nyu1970/ and https://nyu.manifoldapp.org/projects/wgsatnyu/ were selected by University Archivist Janet Bunde in October 2024. The accession number associated with these websites is 2024.075.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_fd8eb7f29da3607d12278cacfe673a29">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b502ebda64bbe2dd36fa9f820e6111c6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Student work represented in this collection was intentionally transferred to the Archives by the students, who signed release forms granting researcher access to these materials for noncommercial research, study, and teaching. Any projects without signed release forms are closed for 75 years.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_136cc7b7070137518aa6229fa2d144eb">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6fb3bab9499758b6c15f522ce9458971">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Records of NYU@200; MC 414; box number; folder number or item identifier; New York University Archives, New York University.</p><p>
To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; Records of NYU@200; MC 414; Wayback URL; University Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <accruals id="aspace_f5a7303b6f540f3b8d26d8ae8f0354df">
    <head>Accruals</head>
<p>Accruals are expected.</p>  </accruals>
  <arrangement id="aspace_72a3bb4fe9fe69680f021a4e3f5abaef">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged alphabetically by student name.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2d7f2a0417d8eb57975ccd10d6e283e6">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The Records of NYU@200 consist of student projects completed for the NYU@200 course offered Fall 2022 and Fall 2023 in the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development. In this course, co-taught by Janet Bunde, University Archivist, and James Fraser, Professor of Education and History at NYU, students explore the history of higher education through a deep dive into the archives and history of New York University in the years just before its bicentennial in 2030.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_4b7034c3c632bff00f494b615787cf22">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The archived websites were crawled and described in October 2024. The finding aid was created in November 2024.</p><p>In February 2025, two accessions of born-digital transfers were described on the collection-level, arranged alphabetically, and inventoried at the project-level.</p><p>New York University Libraries follow professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity of the content.</p>  </processinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_36d706d4a7a084f243c00fb658150bb8">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <phystech id="aspace_41d62cd3f37030e5c7c173c1ba35b527">
    <head>Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Student projects.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Protest movements.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women's studies</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anniversaries</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <persname role="fmo" source="local">Bunde, Janet</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ed634092d1860b96cb70bd80528fa24a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Francis, Ben: "The Battle of Washington Square: New York University and Urban Development in the Shadow of Robert Moses"</unittitle><unitid>UA_MC_414_ER_1</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1019711</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2023" type="inclusive">circa 2022-2023</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Francis, Ben: &quot;The Battle of Washington Square: New York University and Urban Development in the Shadow of Robert Moses&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Francis, Ben: "The Battle of Washington Square: New York University and Urban Development in the Shadow of Robert Moses"</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_4127bf1a678dd5a77a48285e70ee62e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gordon, Zuri E.: "Women's Studies at NYU"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1014707</unitid><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2024-10/2024-10">October 2024</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/23526/*/https://nyu.manifoldapp.org/projects/wgsatnyu/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Women's Studies at NYU Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Women's Studies at NYU Archived Website: October 2024</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_261ffef290bf1ec76ee16b7e750d530a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Women's Studies at NYU" is a digital archive on Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies (WGS) programs at New York University. The project was developed by Zuri E. Gordon. This student project traces the emergence of women's studies at New York University and charts the ways in which courses in women's studies were offered (individually and programmatically) over time.</p></scopecontent><appraisal id="aspace_94ce2b4fb5f220a18dcdb1a90fda0449"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nyu.manifoldapp.org/projects/wgsatnyu/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal></c><c id="aspace_ae02df5f22455ab98f77c311aa93b244" level="file"><did><unittitle>Han, Seungkyoo (Peter): "From Hope to Reality: An Introduction to NYU Global Network University"</unittitle><unitid>UA_MC_414_ER_2</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1019716</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2023/2023">circa 2023</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Han, Seungkyoo (Peter): &quot;From Hope to Reality: An Introduction to NYU Global Network University&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Han, Seungkyoo (Peter): "From Hope to Reality: An Introduction to NYU Global Network University"</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_cb2e864307832e47d5d102e2dfa5e9fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Justice, Robert: "Spring 1970 at NYU's Washington Square Campus"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1014706</unitid><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2024-10/2024-10">October 2024</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/23526/*/https://wp.nyu.edu/nyu1970/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Spring 1970 at NYU's Washington Square Campus Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Spring 1970 at NYU's Washington Square Campus Archived Website: October 2024</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5345abb029d39e6a70952b5806c9fdab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The "Spring 1970 at NYU's Washington Square Campus" digital exhibit, created by Robert Justice, provides historical information supported by primary source materials about three major strikes that took place at NYU's campus in 1970. The strikes were led by cafeteria workers, librarians, and student peace protesters. The website includes an overview and timeline of each strike, an analysis of the role of the University Christian Foundation (UCF) in the context of the strikes, and findings based on the research conducted by Justice.</p></scopecontent><appraisal id="aspace_7896d9affd116b42a4bd43601100288d"><head>Appraisal</head><p>Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of wp.nyu.edu/nyu1970/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.</p></appraisal></c><c id="aspace_4b99a7d7b2e64b4dd7dbcdf1a8350172" level="file"><did><unittitle>La Vaglio, Michael: Lesson Plans on "Bates Seven"</unittitle><unitid>UA_MC_414_ER_3</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1019715</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2023/2023">2023</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="La Vaglio, Michael: Lesson Plans on &quot;Bates Seven&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>La Vaglio, Michael: Lesson Plans on "Bates Seven"</p></daodesc></dao></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_7280176c74069bc81a915212a350c50c"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access to these files are restricted until 2098.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="aspace_97cb0f94895f561eb57a10ac19e2983b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Moorreade, Rofiat: "Student-Led Advocacy: Transforming Ideas into Action"</unittitle><unitid>UA_MC_414_ER_4</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1019717</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2024/2024">2024</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Moorreade, Rofiat: &quot;Student-Led Advocacy: Transforming Ideas into Action&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Moorreade, Rofiat: "Student-Led Advocacy: Transforming Ideas into Action"</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_65acd4dde89b9d9eefc0099939c8bd6f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Skorupa, Anna: "New York University's School of Education and Shifts in Supports for Teachers' Learning of Practice through Practice, 1922-1960"</unittitle><unitid>UA_MC_414_ER_5</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1019718</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2023/2023">2023</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Skorupa, Anna: &quot;New York University’s School of Education and Shifts in Supports for Teachers’ Learning of Practice through Practice, 1922-1960&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Skorupa, Anna: "New York University's School of Education and Shifts in Supports for Teachers' Learning of Practice through Practice, 1922-1960"</p></daodesc></dao></did></c><c id="aspace_0f4dce45643d7ea1de3e573ef00d3124" level="file"><did><unittitle>Villacampa, Isabella: "Women in NYU Leadership in the 1970s: Jane Maggin and Ann Marcus"</unittitle><unitid>UA_MC_414_ER_6</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/6/archival_objects/1019713</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2022">2022</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Villacampa, Isabella: &quot;Women in NYU Leadership in the 1970s: Jane Maggin and Ann Marcus&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Villacampa, Isabella: "Women in NYU Leadership in the 1970s: Jane Maggin and Ann Marcus"</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
