<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-F" url="https://findingaids.library.nyu.edu/fales/mss_569/">mss_569</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Collection on Enslavement in Cuba <num>MSS.569</num></titleproper><author>Rachel Searcy</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Fales Library and Special Collections</publisher><p><date>February 2019</date></p></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-11-04 19:03:10 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>September 2022</date><item>Item-level titles and descriptions were revised by Stacey Flatt, Nicole Greenhouse, Rachel Mahre, Anna Björnsson McCormick, Rachel Searcy, Aki Snyder, and Weatherly Stephan to correct inaccuracies, remove racist language, and contextualize collection</item></change><change><date>November 2025</date><item>Revised by Grecia Márquez García to correct item titles and add descriptions</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Fales Library and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Collection on Enslavement in Cuba</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50071701" role="col" source="naf">Fales Library</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>MSS.569</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/resources/2876</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 linear foot</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 2 flat boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1809/1898" type="inclusive">1809-1898</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7451e8cf82fc4b0145c60a6dea6a1184">The time period covered by this collection was the final century of 400 years of Spanish colonization of the island of Cuba. Although Spain and Great Britain agreed to end the trade of enslaved people in Spanish colonies by 1820, an estimated one million enslaved Africans were brought to Cuba by Spanish colonists. Cuba formally ended its participation in the Transatlantic Slave Trade in 1867, and abolished the legal enslavement of people in 1886. Enslaved people endured family separation, harsh manual labor on sugar plantations and in sugar mills, and labor within an enslaver's household. Enslaved women were often victims of sexual assault and exploitation. From 1847-1874, hundreds of thousands of Chinese men were trafficked to Cuba as indentured laborers by the Spanish, French, British, and Americans. The group of Chinese indentured workers, later known as "coolies," were subjected to conditions analog to slavery. This collection consists of documents concerning slavery in Spanish-colonized Cuba between 1809 and 1898, and the infrastructure that supported Spanish and American plantation owners at the expense of enslaved and indentured individuals. Materials include telegrams, contracts, identification papers, travel licenses, birth notices, marriage and baptism records, death and burial certificates, purchase and insurance documents, and manumission records documenting various aspects of enslavement in Cuba, including the economics of the Transatlantic Slave Trade, demographics of Cuban populations, England's abolition of slavery, the transportation of indentured Chinese laborers to Cuba, family relationships in the context of slavery, living and working conditions on sugar cane plantations, and manumission processes.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_61bf3cb71874ef3ea01761aac1890c71">Materials are primarily in Spanish, with some documents in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_0a206c19669ae04faf0269eddaa0aa47">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of documents concerning slavery in Spanish-colonized Cuba between 1809 and 1898 and the infrastructure that supported Spanish and American plantation owners at the expense of enslaved and indentured individuals. Materials include telegrams, contracts, identification papers, travel licenses, birth notices, marriage and baptism records, death and burial certificates, purchase and insurance documents, and manumission records documenting various aspects of enslavement in Cuba, including the economics of the Transatlantic Slave Trade, demographics of Cuban populations, England's abolition of slavery, the transportation of indentured Chinese laborers to Cuba, family relationships in the context of slavery, living and working conditions on sugar cane plantations, and manumission processes.</p><p>Spanish transcriptions of selected documents are available by request to Special Collections staff.</p><p>Glossary of frequently used terms throughout the collection: </p><p>Bozal: A juridical as well as colloquial term used to designate a person who either was recently trafficked from Africa and therefore had not learned the colonial language and customs, or someone who, despite having arrived earlier, had still not given up their own language and traditions, often perceived as not speaking the colony's proper language.</p><p>Carabalí: Also known as Kalabari, or Karabali. People from the Bight of Biafra, parts of present-day eastern Nigeria, Cameroon, Equatorial Guinea, and northern Gabon.</p><p>Cimarrón: Maroon. A person who was enslaved but has run away. </p><p>Colono: Term used to refer to the Chinese indentured workers in their contracts, literally translating to colonist or settler. </p><p>Congo: A person from West Central Africa.</p><p>Criollo: Born in the colony, in this case, Cuba.</p><p>Ganga: Most probably derived from Kanga. Used for people from Sierra Leone.</p><p>Lucumí: Yoruba person from present-day Nigeria, Benin, and Togo.</p><p>Makua: Also referred to as Wamakua; also written Macua. Bantu-speaking people from northern Mozambique and the southern Tanzania border.</p><p>Mandinga: Also written Mandinka. Person from Senegambia.</p><p>Moreno: Dark-skinned. Used to refer to Black people.</p><p>Pardo: Used to refer to mixed people of Spanish and African origin. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_d51090d5a61c2cd062fc67c1c7a119eb">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b72b32d641fd857600cd8f06002395c6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Materials in this collection, which were created in 1809-1898 range, are in the public domain. Permission to publish or reproduce is not required.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_293de416eacdc57022b731eae8a1d52f">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials in this collection were purchased from bookseller Kevin Jackson by Timothy V. Johnson, NYU Librarian for Africana Studies, Anthropology and Food Studies in December 2014; original provenance is unknown. The collection was transferred to the Fales Library and Special Collections in 2017. The accession number associated with this purchase is 2019.010.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b9a4ebd322b9b2c62759df39412b26ce">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Collection on Enslavement in Cuba; MSS 569; box number; folder number or item identifier; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c6436e1f1f72ab95369edf65faa1f336">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Documents with brittle paper were rehoused to prevent immediate loss and documents with ink damage were housed in mylar with paper backing for additional support. Materials were described on the collection-level. The folder-level inventory was created by the collection's seller and modified by an archivist to remove derogatory terms and contextual details not relevant to the items.</p><p>In August 2022, narrative description and individual folder titles were edited to employ the recommendations in P. Gabrielle Foreman's community-sourced document "Writing About Slavery/Teaching About Slavery: This Might Help," as well as the Archives for Black Lives in Philadelphia's Anti-Racist Description Resources. These item-level titles and descriptions were written by non-Spanish language speakers who are not experts in the history of enslavement in Spanish-colonized Cuba. Some spellings are approximate. Future changes to correct inaccuracies or inappropriate language are anticipated.</p><p>Researchers can access previous versions of the finding aid in our GitHub repository at https://github.com/NYULibraries/findingaids_eads/commits/master/fales/mss_569.xml.</p><p>In 2025, the collection materials and collection guide were reviewed by Grecia Márquez García, a short-term research fellow, who provided corrected item titles and descriptions throughout the inventory, and transcribed selected documents in Spanish.</p>  </processinfo>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_92fdc9860ba8d47b2ba8d3a268e7fdc8">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Folder 1 in the inventory contained a grouping of 80 documents related to the case of five enslaved people at a sugar mill in Rio Nuevo who killed a man they believed to be the Governor General of Cuba on July 8, 1842. This item was removed from the collection and cataloged separately as HV6535.C9 C66 1842.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <arrangement id="aspace_1fcecf19a68463defa0bf5da990ebed6">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the seller.</p>  </arrangement>
  <phystech id="aspace_a0741fce8cfc8c8a6f1cac8e69e2dacb">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Iron gall ink present in many documents in the collection has caused paper loss. Some documents are partially legible as a result.</p>  </phystech>
  <bioghist id="aspace_dfc6182a17af5c0d332a17f5cd0e3d68">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The time period covered by this collection was the final century of 400 years of Spanish colonization of the island of Cuba. Although Spain and Great Britain agreed to end the trade of enslaved people in Spanish colonies by 1820, an estimated one million enslaved Africans were brought to Cuba by Spanish colonists. Cuba formally ended its participation in the Transatlantic Slave Trade in 1867, and abolished the legal enslavement of people in 1886. Enslaved people endured family separation, harsh manual labor on sugar plantations and in sugar mills, and labor within an enslaver's household. Enslaved women were often victims of sexual assault and exploitation. </p><p>From 1847-1874, hundreds of thousands of Chinese men were trafficked to Cuba as indentured laborers by the Spanish, French, British, and Americans. The group of Chinese indentured workers, later known as "coolies", were subjected to conditions analog to slavery. In port cities like Hong Kong and Macao, Chinese men were kidnapped or coerced into signing contracts by enslavers posing as recruitment agents. Although the contracts offered freedom after eight years, this freedom was not enforced, and the laborers often died before the term ended due to malnourishment and abusive conditions.</p>  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slave trade -- Cuba -- History -- 19th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Cuba -- History -- 19th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Economic aspects -- Cuba -- History -- 19th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Social aspects -- Cuba -- History -- 19th century.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Foreign workers, Chinese -- Cuba.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Chinese -- Cuba -- History -- 19th century.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Vital statistics records</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Free papers</genreform>
    <subject authfilenumber="(mesh)D063948" source="mesh">Enslaved Persons</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- Colonies</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Forced labor -- Cuba</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_11f459d0369ad63fbded426f81667d2e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cuban Manuscript Concerning the Incarceration of Self-Liberated <emph render="italic">Cimarrones</emph></unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835793</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1858-03-12/1858-03-12">1858</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_23b236bc967b4348b7e83faf28a1fb5d" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_c8bf77d4577f95d759c409d355a7e2bc" parent="aspace_23b236bc967b4348b7e83faf28a1fb5d" type="Folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c92bcbe3e7e70579fedcceec3fd30fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Letter sent by Matías Gallegos to the King, reporting on a previous communication in which Gallegos details the specific characteristics of the <emph render="italic">cimarrones</emph> held in Villa Clara, in accordance with the King's instructions.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_684729ee4d50f475d171ec1663eb9216" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cuban Telegram Regarding Human Trafficking and Slavery</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835794</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857-08-20/1857-08-20">1857-08-20</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_306e9767416d43a8abd290d96a27b0a6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_df2cd3ad24091513a5efff0a29607518" parent="aspace_306e9767416d43a8abd290d96a27b0a6" type="Folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c18510f81523a00645af534c9816ceb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This telegram regarding human trafficking and slavery was sent to the General Captain of Cuba,   by the Governor of Cardenas, Luis Andriani. Andriani reports the disappearance of <emph render="italic">bozales</emph> who were aboard a ship in Cayo Bahia de Cadiz during the 15th and 16th days of the same month.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_671dd44ee783ace8245d4d9d6b8f9ce1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Death Certificate for Estanislao, an Enslaved Chinese Man</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835795</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1872-02-18/1872-02-18">1872-02-18</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_54bee500deb45e6eac70faf057955fe6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_d6017d9444655fe4c6776a9d74beb463" parent="aspace_54bee500deb45e6eac70faf057955fe6" type="Folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a6d6bdaac69c6d3bff82beb0e1b73b57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>According to the death certificate, Estanislao, whose ethnicity here is stated as "asiatico" (Asian), died at Charity Hospital in the city of San Felipe y Santiago. According to the document, he was to be buried in the General Cemetery of the city.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3120d8768e1020f0ebb905502d6b7c43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Insurance Certificate for a Person Enslaved by Joaquin Soler</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835796</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1860-03-01/1860-03-01">1860-03-01</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_3cfb2fa9aee963f7b3809f3e12238f5e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_e10aeb9ffc7c60e6b40a512d0de0e805" parent="aspace_3cfb2fa9aee963f7b3809f3e12238f5e" type="Folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_948d8d410dd1a0cfc0230c62c369211f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This certificate, created by La Protectora Compañia  General Cubana de Seguros Mutuos Sobre la Vida de Esclavos, includes information such as the price of the insurance, the corresponding legal articles, and the signature of the insurance director. It does not appear to include the name of the enslaved person.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bfcfc191ab0c73d18eb9a70afd7a8a30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Two Letters Addressing the Burial of Fetuses</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835797</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1866-08-07/1866-08-07">1866-08-07</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_69ea9f50a46db6f9d957cc28b5897eba" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_9f942acfaf0921129637a80c68ff534c" parent="aspace_69ea9f50a46db6f9d957cc28b5897eba" type="Folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2d8f9a7a2307f0967d7b41ab962ea1f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These letters were issued by the Church of the Holy Spirit and the Church of Monserrate in Havana. They are addressed to the Secretary of the Bishopric and explain the burial and certification of deceased fetuses who could not receive the sacrament of baptism. The first letter mentions a specific case involving the abortion of a Black woman, Doña N.N., "also known as la <emph render="italic">Morena</emph> or <emph render="italic">Parda</emph>." The full name of the woman, and the name of the deceased are not provided.</p><p>Transcriptions of these documents are available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d80da1f4c00e99da6c6e58c422e15a5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document Summarizing Enslaved Peoples Expenditures</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835798</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1818/1819" type="inclusive">1818-1819</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_3680f6369f47ee913e62d039ba78484e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_67c4c141caae663417da521e2b89023f" parent="aspace_3680f6369f47ee913e62d039ba78484e" type="Folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b14b2e39bebb93a6f58583fef36fc2a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The expenses include food, housing and the preparation of the terrain (<emph render="italic">hollar</emph>). The document is signed by Juan de Sosa y Albarado.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3a312d74c7b17217de7c195d111ba01a" level="file"><did><unittitle>La Providencia Insurance Document for an Enslaved Person in Havana</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835799</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1859-09-30/1859-09-30">1859-09-30</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_43670a058a63ce107ad6a02531068e69" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_35564bac17f33959b8c6528badb4b5fe" parent="aspace_43670a058a63ce107ad6a02531068e69" type="Folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3e11ec335012ec4063238dd8146a816"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document is an agreement between José Pardú and La Providencia Company.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_08b41cba6b5367f084ee3b37a93f68e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document Attesting the Baptism of Maria del Rosario</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835800</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1816-12-11/1816-12-12" type="inclusive">1816-12-11-1816-12-12</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_ff00fd1dcc29de3c955e38c54e10fd23" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_907c8f08809f8b43cc1a68c72d72ca00" parent="aspace_ff00fd1dcc29de3c955e38c54e10fd23" type="Folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0f22f2dc802454775aed40b2dfe05802"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This document serves as a confirmation of the baptism of Maria del Rosario, a Black woman enslaved by Juan Garcia de Casares, in order for her to marry another enslaved person. </p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_16062670f2ce2e7e061e2223308f020f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notice on the Escape and Apprehension of a Man in Charge of Transporting Cadavers</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835801</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1819/1819">1819</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_db951dc8c78e528c61e1880df140c236" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_f87af725db41eb48cd1a27ab20f88dae" parent="aspace_db951dc8c78e528c61e1880df140c236" type="Folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_adcdbef43cea844401255c7a91c91424"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Letter signed by Alexandro Ramirez sent to the bishop of Havana informing of the disobedience, escape, and capture of an enslaved man in charge of transporting cadavers to their burial places.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9be659e2b5b2d3e23c577e5c50a5e660" level="file"><did><unittitle>Identity Paper [<emph render="italic">Cédula</emph>] for Dominga</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835802</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1856/1856" type="inclusive">1856</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_04cdfb7d3716812b5277b860ba0d43d5" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_de0f5033712eda8de59dcab56562f5e4" parent="aspace_04cdfb7d3716812b5277b860ba0d43d5" type="Folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3caa3b41f4defd1f61c41298e6cf5353"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Dominga was a 21 year old woman enslaved by Juan Ruiz. This <emph render="italic">cédula</emph> contains twelve articles pertaining to the agreement of the holding of enslaved people.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_373b351745f0d88428781ff0c547cdcb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Identity Paper for Gerónimo Ganga</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835803</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1859/1859" type="inclusive">1859</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_d7d835c6fe256008bfdf804583c21d99" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_9e63d2116e0653ae263afc3c47afdcb6" parent="aspace_d7d835c6fe256008bfdf804583c21d99" type="Folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d921ab22f4f3d8ae7ba4af6ec59f9978"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document contains the Decree of December 19th, 1854, issued by the Civil Superior Government of the Island (<emph render="italic">Decreto de 19 de diciembre de 1854 del Gobierno Superior Civil de la Isla</emph>), as well as the Decree of September 1st, 1857. These decrees outline the conditions for holding, trading, and transporting enslaved persons. This specific document serves to identify 59-year-old Gerónimo, of Ganga origin (now known as Sierra Leone), who was enslaved by Juan Azpeitia.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f366396814425e054b252e3db118f7b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manumission Document for Lelicia Frerejo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835804</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1860/1860" type="inclusive">1860</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_4beaa2101ee0cc7b17695870acdab73d" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_d361c3f546089b25996a96d2c2cdf19c" parent="aspace_4beaa2101ee0cc7b17695870acdab73d" type="Folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7736f9d5cca1453b63a02a40bb140e34"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Lelicia (possible mispelling for "Leticia" or "Felicia") Frerejo was enslaved at the Ingenio (plantation) of Baracoa.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_30f8ddc7321f8452eb0d3a9059c52535" level="file"><did><unittitle>Burial Document of an Enslaved Person</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835805</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1879-08-25/1879-08-25">1879-08-25</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_934df0a1642ac2c0280aefd1f3a1382e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_64f3c8a6926c6848e08f7c2f46261b76" parent="aspace_934df0a1642ac2c0280aefd1f3a1382e" type="Folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e34362a919b0c97df064302f4b96a732"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>According to this document, it was the duty of the patrons (<emph render="italic">patronos</emph>) to cover the burial expenses of their enslaved individuals. Juan S. Aguirre is being required to comply with this obligation after previously refusing to pay. The document does not state the name or number of the deceased.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4a4fc2e82d59192ac334215760249beb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baptism Document for Francisco Herrera</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835806</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1842-07-06/1842-07-08" type="inclusive">1842-07-06-1842-07-08</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_45e9e59fc230e7ceda69b8e880eb7385" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_2dfe6280bb14ca59e05e7fdd84314293" parent="aspace_45e9e59fc230e7ceda69b8e880eb7385" type="Folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4b7467b26d45fe41fd3ff817663f9ada"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document, issued in Matanzas, constitutes a petition for proof of baptism of Francisco Herrera, who was between 25 and 28 years old at the time, enslaved by Pedro Herrera.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9867501a3685a83e7ed5a4af7d99249a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Judicial Trial of Rosa Delgado and Maria de la Luz Delgado for Having Buried an Infant on Unholy Ground</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835807</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849-04-19/1849-04-19">1849-04-19</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_458f9dc13ab277e39b1c39d03e8526fd" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_5328f43ac14e388cdcafc4fc5a06a96d" parent="aspace_458f9dc13ab277e39b1c39d03e8526fd" type="Folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b06216bd1b1bb351b9e65dacbc548bc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This document follows the denunciation made by the Lieutenant Priest of San Jose de las Lajas in which he claimed the two women, both enslaved, engaged in an illicit burial of the child of Maria de la Luz Delgado. Other free Black women testified on their behalf and the case was resolved in favor of the women.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6fb3e0bd3f43315a8828d06746bf943a" level="file"><did><unittitle>La Protectora Insurance Receipt for an Enslaved Person</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835808</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1859/1859" type="inclusive">1859</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_6c03bbad97c3e1e5efe10fb6a66e85b2" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_abdff07822edda9a18fa59cf4824c5e2" parent="aspace_6c03bbad97c3e1e5efe10fb6a66e85b2" type="Folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d8f1fd6b6ed0e017834bb6948e27a49c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Insurance receipt issued in Havana by the Director General to Francisco Equileos regarding the purchase of an enslaved person.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7e686fe10ae75949e85508e3bbe1917b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Telegram Concerning the Persecution of Trading Enslaved People by the Lieutenant Governor of Cuba</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835809</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1865/1865" type="inclusive">1865</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_ff9bcb709592eecd9eff1d45644106a2" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_3ef2f05bf33d9d296924f061e836c1d1" parent="aspace_ff9bcb709592eecd9eff1d45644106a2" type="Folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba510150f2d5c3fc8c648dfde620f32c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Telegram sent by the Lieutenant Governor of San Cristobal, Francisco Fernandes de la Reguera, informing the Governor of Havana he will conduct an inspection of the coasts of the locality of San Diego.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4f448db3650fccb79cd1939716f75ac8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Judicial Deposit of Enslaved People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835810</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851-10-30/1851-10-30">1851-10-30</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_7800afe5c093ba16e70c3346eae13707" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_a35d5372c458f1775dd78faf7d8d070b" parent="aspace_7800afe5c093ba16e70c3346eae13707" type="Folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_73f5d5a89dd2ce0a727d78add13c8fcd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document states that Nicolás "Criollito," who was enslaved by Marcos Albares, was handed over to Carlos Criado as a result of a dispute. The word "Criollito" possibly refers to Nicolás as being <emph render="italic">criollo</emph>.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e050975f2738e7d687039ac2cfb72af7" level="file"><did><unittitle>La Protectora Insurance Receipt for an Enslaved Person</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835811</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1859-05-18/1859-05-18">1859-05-18</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_941856178607f486cf52d5285281d81d" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_df3978eef65b036cf7f622558d26f9db" parent="aspace_941856178607f486cf52d5285281d81d" type="Folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b91411041f64844bff20a41be71fd6c1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This insurance, corresponding to a 1% fee of the total capital reported by the enslavers, was established on May 9th of the same year as a precaution against any incidents that might occur throughout the year. The document is signed on behalf of the slaveholders Martínez y Barrera.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5a18a080da2be467a8cf9d9244ac60bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stamped Document for Renting Out Two Enslaved Persons</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835812</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1872-02-20/1872-02-20">1872-02-20</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_fd9443099ca13f7dae5ab3b139ee87b3" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_66524e091ecf5d6013bc91a99fbca6a3" parent="aspace_fd9443099ca13f7dae5ab3b139ee87b3" type="Folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_40919a4157b5d7dfb61d145cad401194"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document was issued in Matanzas. The family who rented the enslaved individuals had the last name Arzauregui Gonsales. The receipt does not state the names of the enslaved, who were in the service of the other party for twenty days.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_142fee519769512a0fcb0552734bbd1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal Agreement Regarding Deposit of Francisco Carabalí</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835813</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847-05-04/1847-05-04">1847-05-04</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_e798e8c49b02f32da8a2c1f32b5faf3a" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_78e44621f450e8b3fa7c44c8117e8a33" parent="aspace_e798e8c49b02f32da8a2c1f32b5faf3a" type="Folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_12b2871740432c2fa69ab0a48728b6d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The legal agreement states that power over Francisco's life is being transferred from Juana Franchi de Alfaro, the widow of Francisco Franchi de Alfaro, to the Fourth Mayor, for him to exercise at his discretion. </p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_80fb9735e98a3ae98b925818cf56f27d" level="file"><did><unittitle>La Providencia Receipt for a Fee Paid for Incidents Associated with the Holding of Enslaved People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835814</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1856-04-15/1856-04-15">1856-04-15</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_a8e0d9579853f70ace18a706efed5559" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_f683ebfc7b2ece7714ea6eb885d8e7ef" parent="aspace_a8e0d9579853f70ace18a706efed5559" type="Folder">23</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c742b0d98a8902ad81fc8cff04cf6666"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Receipt for fee paid to La Providencia insurance by enslaver Francisco Alonso. The fee is said to cover incidents that occurred from January until March 31 of the same year.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1a1383fac3346acc75fa63cb65671abd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Identification Paper for Guillermo Ceta</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835815</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1859/1859" type="inclusive">1859</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_302350f807649f57eeae5e7c848f1f61" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_23b0ab5ecda72546621f7f3beb8c0b78" parent="aspace_302350f807649f57eeae5e7c848f1f61" type="Folder">24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4942a09d88c97e4e3ba5dbf7e978393b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Government identification paper permitting the travel of Guillermo Ceta, a man enslaved by Cristobal Alonso of La Habana, to Pueblo.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c84b2471e950a5f1b7927aa78d19ddb6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memo on the Presence of Enslaved African People in Cienfuegos</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835816</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864-03-12/1864-03-12">1864-03-12</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_990adc412cdaa48a986a856f7a3143df" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_dda3d31b114035195304da6ea3df3cb0" parent="aspace_990adc412cdaa48a986a856f7a3143df" type="Folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_685cf6859cec018b731a1efb7842d4b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Short note inquiring about the presence of newly arrived enslaved African people (<emph render="italic">bozales</emph>) in the vicinities of Cienfuegos, specifically in Yaguaramas and Cartagena. Sent from Habana.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4e5bcbbed31e0b54e7d82eeed7075e03" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proof of Bachelorhood and Christianity of Enslaved Manuel Maria Clavel in Order for Him to Marry Maria Luisa, Also Enslaved</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835817</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1809-04-08/1809-04-08">1809-04-08</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_6eb8b648b09316fb53fe31e6bc8603fb" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_2651fa7925343226202ce7019d45790f" parent="aspace_6eb8b648b09316fb53fe31e6bc8603fb" type="Folder">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_921f06c082f116b43ff9c0a24a302a10"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These series of documents issued in Santo Domingo serve as proof of the single status and christianity of Manuel Maria Clavel, as well as his lack of blood kinship with Maria Luisa. Both individuals were enslaved by the colonel Martin Ugarte. Two freed individuals and one enslaved person testify in favor of Clavel, stating they had known him since their youth in Santo Domingo.</p><p>Transcriptions of these documents are available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e8cd41a5836ad2b614bd2026841b6806" level="file"><did><unittitle>Telegram to the General Captain of Havana from Francisco F. de la Regera</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835818</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864-09-21/1864-09-21">1864-09-21</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_8dadab3e05b6ce5b19588e8eea6192f7" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_52f4f4cde045eb0c677b2dc67c623543" parent="aspace_8dadab3e05b6ce5b19588e8eea6192f7" type="Folder">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4d89878c6af814efc35daa355521c11"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Telegram sent to the General Captain in Habana from Francisco F. de la Regera concerning the contraband of enslaved Africans (<emph render="italic">bozales</emph>) in San Diego.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7c18281ccfc01df9ee639722259f0fec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proof of Baptism of the Enslaved Person Rafael, Lucumi, in Order for Him to Marry a Woman Enslaved by the Same Individual</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835819</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1816-12-20/1816-12-20">1816-12-20</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_0234d16c7ae48e9db7d9b3fbde84af81" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_fe6005eb4b39ff24b70935dbab647790" parent="aspace_0234d16c7ae48e9db7d9b3fbde84af81" type="Folder">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e845bd7d1c4612823d8b411e8170f2b5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This document serves as proof of the baptism and christianity of Rafael, of African Lucumi origin, enslaved by Agustin Lopes in San Juan de Jaruco, in order for him to marry another woman enslaved by the same man; her name, although not entirely clear, appears once and is shortened as Sūa. </p><p>A transcription of this document is avaialble by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0be18d0def001bcda9104fbe5b9de7a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>La Providencia Receipt for Insurance of Enslaved People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835820</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1860-01-01/1860-01-01">1860-01-01</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_5fcd80663a5fbf01b452cd6abd09cf1b" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_2f4fcf2c362e46ae9bc1d2b95ac0c948" parent="aspace_5fcd80663a5fbf01b452cd6abd09cf1b" type="Folder">29</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67872dc013194a37174850b6eed44c8a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Receipt for the "medio por ciento" fee paid by enslaver Ambrosio Maria Rendon to La Providencia insurance.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7c5b83e2a7b6c0aa785cb7245222683d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marriage Contract between Two Emancipated People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835821</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1817-08-17/1817-08-17">1817-08-17</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_3224ee5538b5ffb06274a215e8db617f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_1f93b7c291f060fbf1160d2fb267d26c" parent="aspace_3224ee5538b5ffb06274a215e8db617f" type="Folder">30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fa473556b46d951652bf55975463c37c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Marriage contract between Francisco Andrade, of possible Nigerian origin (stated here as "de nación caravali,") and Marcelina Ximenes, both free people.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_1b8ddcd7aa03aa5f955701437e5ce959" level="file"><did><unittitle>Telegram Concerning Surveilling of Punta de Cartas Sent by Ramon Menduiña</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835822</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1865-09-30/1865-09-30">1865-09-30</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_25f470f084dc3e8148fa589cfb28a142" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_f83746b58112358e614b3d5664db3a08" parent="aspace_25f470f084dc3e8148fa589cfb28a142" type="Folder">31</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_95f96723e9c68bedf4546b75f0b818cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Ramon Menduiña, lieutenant governor of Pinar del Río, informed the governor of Havana he was leaving La Coloma in direction of Punta de Cartas in order to surveil the coast.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_10686bcdb9e468963e364247cf3e76c5"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Born in Salamanca, Spain, in 1815, Ramón Menduiña López was a field marshal and knight of the order of San Fernando who died in 1890 in Madrid. After having participated in many battles throughout the Spanish kingdom, he was sent to Mexico, where he served under General Prim. When that campaign ended, he remained under the authority of the Captain General of Cuba, who appointed him military commander of Bayamo in August 1862. After being promoted to colonel in March 1864, he assumed command of the Disciplined Militias Regiment based in Güines. In September 1865, he was appointed military commander of Pinar del Río. He became commander of Bayamo, where he exercised control until 1879 when he was declared commander-in-chief of Port-au-Prince (Haiti). He returned to Spain in 1883, where he remained until his death.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_9556f7949b44be7e37bf67cf577a96e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documents Regarding the Death and Burial of Felix</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835823</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854-07-17/1854-08-07" type="inclusive">1854-07-17-1854-08-07</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_e1fd6179b6ca3e45ce2ef1ab7e8c6986" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_2160a969e10e2fe0724b2096dcdf0b9b" parent="aspace_e1fd6179b6ca3e45ce2ef1ab7e8c6986" type="Folder">32</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e4a7fcc155c92d73ea053904c3f62622"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Felix, a Black <emph render="italic">criollo</emph> man, enslaved by Juan Delgado, drowned in a well in June 12, 1854, in Bainoa. Felix was 30 years old. These documents refer to the processing of the death certificate and burial permit.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_faacf16c3146fd334522e1073ecec8e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence regarding the grave of Felix</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835824</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854-06-12/1854-06-12">1854-06-12</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_739b1bcab28940a6c94554ac0fc7dd62" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_b61b3cb82e6992cb76fcccaf1911dd23" parent="aspace_739b1bcab28940a6c94554ac0fc7dd62" type="Folder">33</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21fbf3fba234b2186c10318a7a45ea6c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>June 12, 1854. Felix, a Black <emph render="italic">criollo</emph> man enslaved by Juan Delgado, drowned in a well in 1854. Felix was 30 years old. In these letters, Juan Serafin Delgado, son of Juan Delgado, and Antonio Martin ask the priest of Bainoa for his permission to bury Felix in the local cemetery. Delgado's letter also states that Felix's death was "casual" ("<emph render="italic">muerto de una muerte casual</emph>").</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_91fa692e1b033eec6e656c7dbd65651d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document Referencing the Emancipation of Blas</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835825</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1842-10-19/1842-10-19">1842-10-19</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_7979a5858a99a98a024b455c725dfe65" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_4e77ea63829d8d1cdbc253591a6fbc24" parent="aspace_7979a5858a99a98a024b455c725dfe65" type="Folder">34</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db2ba03978919202e44aa52a595aa8bb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document, signed by Francisco Rodriguez and addressed to the archbishop of Guatemala (Cuba), constitutes a petition to include in the baptismal record Blas (of unknown surname) his manumission from the plantation Manuelita and the enslaver María de Jesús García.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b4d7bd0dcae9ace358f48282e54d1f84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Petition of Marriage for José Ramón and Maria Anta Gonzalez, Both Enslaved</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835826</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1815-11-06/1815-11-06">1815-11-06</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_1fcb22834d4615320acb2126d07a940e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_a9ca1ae9108db499962f0b98eb03919e" parent="aspace_1fcb22834d4615320acb2126d07a940e" type="Folder">35</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9a846f155d75335685036f0d8083d1a4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the town of Regla, Federico Pau gives his consent for José Ramón, of Mandinga origin and enslaved by him, to marry Maria Anta (possibly Antonia) Gonzales, who was enslaved by Santiago Espinola.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5cd2ac0da3f6de2d40546f6f41f55908" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificate of Indenture for Chinese Laborer Anselmo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835827</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1863-05-04/1863-05-04">1863-05-04</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_def276eb963710950a8e6db2616c3775" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_af38004c4a0e60cbd86618c4377d8143" parent="aspace_def276eb963710950a8e6db2616c3775" type="Folder">36</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7106ff669d67a90c8d0e40c30e6b0984"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This document states that Anselmo, a 23-year-old laborer from China, was contracted to work in a quarry for eight years and for Carmen Herrera for an equal amount of time. The document also includes articles 2, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 and 11 of the decree of June 5, 1855.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_210d7edd2a5a304ddf10675d011cbbf9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contract Enslaving Francisco Real</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835828</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1852-09-02/1852-09-02">1852-09-02</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_a9f7164ec999dbe3d94c08378cc18ec5" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_151a63d6c322c0ca5ac9c62de7bc8290" parent="aspace_a9f7164ec999dbe3d94c08378cc18ec5" type="Folder">37</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aee3310aa115500aa32c8806a2be5f8c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>La Comision de Poblacion Blanca one-year contract regarding Francisco Real, a 20 year old man from Palma, Canarias, who was indentured by Aur [possibly Aureliano] r Suares de la Rosa. The contract also specifies that Francisco would work in the fields and the payment and conditions to which he was subjected.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_abc91734d603e37796f24b9ad07788d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contract Enslaving Justo Asivea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835829</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-06/1868-06">1868-06</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_b26354d06d948d3a2ad01dd3ebcd0d9c" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_698d60f00d635575fdd0dbd9896ba28d" parent="aspace_b26354d06d948d3a2ad01dd3ebcd0d9c" type="Folder">38</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_79351f24f237f70bd9fd5ad18cb655a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Tenencia de Gobierno de Guanajay one-year contract regarding Justo Asivea, a 28 year old Chinese man who was enslaved by Andres Fin. The contract  specifies the type of job in the fields, the payment, and conditions to which Justo was subjected.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9109afebce255b40f1118e5f75c3042d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contract Enslaving Emeterio Sau Achin</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835830</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-05-29/1868-05-29">1868-05-29</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_e3871d7abb68bb1391b803d98b14ac6e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_f1e5d720aae897aa3103c9c017582160" parent="aspace_e3871d7abb68bb1391b803d98b14ac6e" type="Folder">39</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_87e72e47d9ec288dc46690a4cc495d9c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Tenencia de Gobierno de Guanajay contract regarding Emeterio Sau Achin, a 28 year old Chinese man from Canton formerly enslaved by Manuel Martinez and enslaved by Paulino Ligarreta per this contract.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_48f7973ad4d705411bb02b3277bcb469" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document of the Death and Burial of Domingo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835831</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1876/1876">1876</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_32d507d4c7587738b6806668cd65133e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_b7c5c799a1fb4f3754a00f5860302979" parent="aspace_32d507d4c7587738b6806668cd65133e" type="Folder">40</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_60e129dd3828b747197633fda0922f0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>According to the document, Domingo was an enslaved Chinese man.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a0ce422788b475109c7ed621b0d7235d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contract for Julian Aguat</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835832</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1866/1866">1866</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_4a6dca5da8d687e5dcb6024413de16b8" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_ebbd0b4f50a14cbaf7c1d14b9efee2bd" parent="aspace_4a6dca5da8d687e5dcb6024413de16b8" type="Folder">41</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72d1f36801dd7a1193abcc3a8f75c19a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Gobierno Politico de la Habana contract regarding Julian Aguat, a 28 year old Chinese man from Macao who was an indentured laborer for Manuel Dorado.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_52f649fd0011e02c0ca0d655d7ce6646" level="file"><did><unittitle>Identification Document for Leopoldo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835833</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1863-03-03/1863-03-03">1863-03-03</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_75d7714a64cd28d2962bce6eceb5f90d" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_8cc2b4892d093414e0d75d97c7e2d097" parent="aspace_75d7714a64cd28d2962bce6eceb5f90d" type="Folder">42</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b19e17a048f0e226b03967ec8f63be4e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Gobierno Politico de la Habana identification document regarding Leopoldo, an indentured 24 year old Chinese man from "Sunhen" who worked for M.B. Pereda for a period of eight years at a quarry. The document states Leopoldo is now under contract with Mayoral and Buquis, residents ("hacendados y vecinos") of El Calvario.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e255ae4376052ec8e183fd96f403e396" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contract Enslaving Nine Spanish People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835834</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854-01-31/1854-01-31">1854-01-31</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_ae71c8151dd44edf00d0f7a2ccf6d1cd" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_f27cd92016ae3d12c9cb2c0cac35a5d9" parent="aspace_ae71c8151dd44edf00d0f7a2ccf6d1cd" type="Folder">43</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_331ac588f6025154c1f883e3e64bc01e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Real Junta de Fomento de la Isla de Cuba contract regarding nine Spanish people who were indentured by Gaspar Hernandez: Jose Hernandez; his wife Bernarda Rodriguez; their sons and daughters Nareisa, Antonio, Maria, and Gregorio; Novento Luis Garcia; Antonio Calaturio; and Silvestre Juan Rodriguez. The documents ends with a note stating that, while most of the listed people are under 12-month contracts, some are only going to serve for eight months, and that the cost of food for the women is lowered in accordance to the agreement of the board of October 26.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8c1dca8888aa495cb04fc86c68a12137" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document Regarding Enslaved People Who Escaped from a Ship</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835835</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1842-08/1842-08">1842-08</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_b57f56dc1ab84f7b00886707707fc558" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_a4799af39840767f170915d71dbabef3" parent="aspace_b57f56dc1ab84f7b00886707707fc558" type="Folder">44</container></did><bioghist id="aspace_6985263f99bdccf6cd6b3e1643b5ba3e"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Gerónimo Valdés (1784–1855) was a Spanish military figure and administrator. Born in Villarín, in Asturias, he participated in the battle of Ayacucho (1824), which was a defeat for the Spanish. He served as Viceroy of Navarre from 1833 to 1834 and also served as Minister of War. He fought on the Liberal (Isabeline) side in the First Carlist War. Valdés lost the Battle of Artaza (April 22, 1835). Valdés signed the Lord Eliot Convention soon after, regulating the treatment of prisoners during that war. He later served as captain-general of Valencia, and of Galicia, and served as governor of Cuba from 1841 to September 1843.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_3f4527362b03eedf6b15cd8b85290018"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This printed memo was issued by the Captain General of Cuba, Gerónimo Valdés. It accounts that, according to British deputies, there was an illegal disembarkation of escaped enslaved people who hid in a farm near Matanzas. Valdés also states that, in agreement with the dictum of the general counsel, farms should not be registered.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_77c0809ac19e65e0623c5ea066e7ff95" level="file"><did><unittitle>Documentation Regarding Sale of the La Constancia Sugar Mill and List of 72 Enslaved People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835836</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1856-02-12/1856-02-12">1856-02-12</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_3fcd847e8851f2aa60a73df6f8200f99" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011467]" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_ac04125891808772edf5c3fac5d32be1" parent="aspace_3fcd847e8851f2aa60a73df6f8200f99" type="Folder">45</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72c429ca2c6126bf12ca2e6a073443b1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>List of people enslaved at the plantation la Costancia: Bernardo of Ganga (now known as Sierra Leone); Fernando; José Maria; Domingo of Lucumi; José Maria; Antonio; Ysidro; Ramon; Miguel; Alejandro; Nicolas; Juan Bautista; Pablo; Martin; José de la Luz; Julian; Pascual; José de Jesus; Juaquin of Abcinia (possibly Abisinia, now known as Ethiopia); Manuel; Carmelo of Macua; Gerbasio; Facundo; Rafael of Congo; Domingo; Antonio Peña; Remigio, <emph render="italic">criollo</emph>; Luis; Cristobal; Roque; Eusebio; José del Rosario; Juan; Simon, <emph render="italic">criollo</emph>; Abraham; Lorenzo; Juaquin; Candelario; Salustiano; Miguel; Juan de Mata; Eugenio; Fernando; Gregorio; Antonio; Hilario; Regino; Carlos; Juliana of Ganga (now known as Sierra Leone); Josefa; Antonia; Paula; Matilde; Maria de Jesus of Congo; Victoria of Abcinia; Asuncion; Catalina; Vicenta of Carabali; Basilia, <emph render="italic">criolla</emph>; Barbara; Ynés; Petrona; Asuncion; Ana Maria; Luisa; Eulogia; Marcelina, <emph render="italic">criolla</emph>; Zacarias; Ynes, Rosa, Florentina, <emph render="italic">criolla</emph>, Olaya.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_398b1fd10bbc8cf88df59ee56a285eed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Priest's Formal Declaration of Baptism of Emilion Esteban, a Freed Person</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835837</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1861-12-23/1861-12-23">1861-12-23</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_2db565307be6201b277a23d774ee3ccc" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_81c39cc0276e8f7496a02f33fc3074cd" parent="aspace_2db565307be6201b277a23d774ee3ccc" type="Folder">46</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7f57ee32ae136b853969503997bf257f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Emilio Esteban, the son of Sebastiana, was baptised on a March 28th. The note also states there was an oral judicial procedure between Sebastiana, represented by Jose Bruzon, and Ysabel Peres, to determine Emilio Esteban's status. The baptismal record is retrieved as proof of his free status. </p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0079d7d78021cab0f8eaaac66bbfbb09" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contract in Guanajay between Felis Bambul and Laborer Vicente Vega from China</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835838</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-05-26/1868-05-26">1868-05-26</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_6736dbe4f5873e88200f962e31899635" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_8fbfa4b18cecdd48fd718fadbfc60336" parent="aspace_6736dbe4f5873e88200f962e31899635" type="Folder">47</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b493217c856ec79261475162d9419d09"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Government Department of Guanajay, Felis Bambul, 28 year old laborer from Canton (China), entered into a contract Vicente Vega for two years. According to the contract, Vega was to be paid a salary of eight pesos.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eeaa06b8b9bb5478190ef1a9ec109e0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cuban License Issued by Vicente Molina Giving Permission for Five Congolese Enslaved People to Travel by Train</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835839</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1845-10-12/1845-10-12">1845-10-12</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_3b053376876e87364e3215bd2b6d0fd1" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_30df72de52cc7402630af5d5cb46d135" parent="aspace_3b053376876e87364e3215bd2b6d0fd1" type="Folder">48</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a15004b80d5620143420cff66169fb05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Enslaved people listed are: Pedro Criollo; Jose and Joaquin Lucumi; Cristobal from Ganga (now known as Sierra Leone); and Florencio Congo. They were sent to Wajay to work in construction under the command of Jose Maria Peres. Document is signed by Governor Leopold O'Donnell granting the travel license.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_abc8cc41369d28b48899be9ae012c37b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cuban License Giving Permission for 36 Enslaved People to Travel by Train</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835840</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1845-10-31/1845-10-31">1845-10-31</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_460db37d5d873d76bb3df7de963a24d7" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_157c8a16c3ef2486ed5d976b99156929" parent="aspace_460db37d5d873d76bb3df7de963a24d7" type="Folder">49</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c65bc152085fb6db78bb9ef454155587"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Cuban license to travel freely by train to work on a sugar plantation. Enslaved people include: Antonio Criollo; Jerman; Francisco; Camilo; Hepomuceno; Cirilo; Domingo; Palomo; Francisco; Prospero Criollo; Isidro; Miguel Ganga (now known as Sierra Leone); Matilde; Canuta; Ynes; [illegible name]; [illegible name]; Serefina; Maria Francisca; Dominga; Joaquina Ganga (now known as Sierra Leone); Maria de la Cruz; Andrea; Ignasia; Francisca Carabali; Damiana; Gregoria from Conga; and Julia. Document is signed by Governor Leopoldo O'Donnell.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7d6f6bfffc3ce52c50d78379e989be85" level="file"><did><unittitle>Document from Spanish Officials to Cuban Government Regarding Fine for Enslavers of Escaped Enslaved People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835841</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1863-04-26/1863-04-26">1863</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_136fd4f9576d6a30fe240f8a0c3e47d5" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_d09cf737beed1142d213cf4a0b633e3b" parent="aspace_136fd4f9576d6a30fe240f8a0c3e47d5" type="Folder">50</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c7a6c687a44e40b56662047d2566e627"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Document was written in Aranjuez, Spain during the Presidencia del Consejo de Ministerio de Ultramar and addressed to the Captain General of Cuba Domingo Dulce y Garay, who signed it upon receipt in Havana. The document discusses a fine of 30 pesos for owners of escaped enslaved people.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_8e0b88cb6b5f1ce5a9991c8a24b58130" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor Contract Issued for Felipe Alvares Lozano and Dolores Castillo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835842</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1852-09-01/1852-09-01">1852-09-01</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_16db582134ef9833d987a6912baa0062" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_d69dd6be90f0acaefb3e35dfafe6d79f" parent="aspace_16db582134ef9833d987a6912baa0062" type="Folder">51</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3fec9452098971158c1fba9067426eef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contract valid for a year between the laborers Felipe Alvares Lozano and Dolores Castillo (from Canarias) with Pedro Lopes. They contract states they were to be paid 4 pesos for doing domestic labor. The contract is signed by Salvador Carrillo, the deposit's (escrow) administrator and Miguel de Cárdenas y Cárdenas, chief of the commission.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e864309a9d1de0230d01c563c5d89cd7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Labor Contract issued for 28 Enslaved People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835843</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1852-08-31/1852-08-31">1852-08-31</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_bfd33fba367815d619fa809bcad11f00" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_f2287e00e297f446adc11a0672b992b8" parent="aspace_bfd33fba367815d619fa809bcad11f00" type="Folder">52</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b29f11f407b83e0bc951ad79ed6d2cf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Enslaved people include Arturo Garcia Perez, Ignacio Perez Martin, Antonio Cabrera de la Cruz, Domingo Lopes de Lopes, Juan Antonio Medina, Augustin Martin Sanches, Jose Maria Guerra Hernandes, Alejo Acosta, Juan Remedio Rodrigues, Juan Delgado Pinto, Nicolas Sanches, Juan Ventura, Jose Rodriguez, Jose Gabriel Ortega, Clemente Perez Hernandes, Ysidro Estrella Bentura, Luciano de la Coreya y Esposito, Juan de la Cruz Bello, Augustin de la Cruz Bello, Jose Hernandez, Portirio Luis Sanchez, Francisco Perez Martin, Viciente Diaz, Franco Perez, Mateo Carpio, Jose Manuel Remedio, and Geronimo Hernandes. Most of the listed persons originate from La Palma, La Victoria, Güimar and Santa Ursula, all in Tenerife. Another name  appears crossed out in the list, possibly Ysidro Llamas; next to his name is a note that says he was on a different ship.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9dcc88e634b40506957e300483781bc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Identity Paper for Luis in Puerto Rico</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835844</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-12-31/1868-12-31">1868-12-31</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_1dce86ca573da009d3dece972974f0f3" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_5e859818fd5173d9f4de612e3c273db5" parent="aspace_1dce86ca573da009d3dece972974f0f3" type="Folder">53</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_26344e4c6727d35f3ba57a357c9ed96c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This document identifies 3 years old Luis, son of Firmina, enslaved by Sebastian Viñas in the neighborhood of San Felipe, vicinity of Arecibo (Puerto Rico). The document is signed by Ramon Viñas as the commissioner.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b13961cb14b04aebff64826e313c5a23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Neighborhood News Bulletin on Miguel, an Enslaved Man Arrested for Robbery</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835845</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1879-11-25/1879-11-25">1879-11-25</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_89bfb739ad85ea05688dd2a5ffe47699" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_32e9de98c88e58a3bde68e420cd9eb88" parent="aspace_89bfb739ad85ea05688dd2a5ffe47699" type="Folder">54</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bdb5d7e90a5927cb6fbb850f49691316"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In Matanzas, Miguel, enslaved by José Sainz, was apprehended and sent to prison for having hurt and stolen two pesos from Tomás, who was enslaved by  Joaquín Robledo.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2827679b6f37543f658631abceaae0af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baptismal Declaration for Luis from Congo and Ricardo from Macua, Enslaved by Alejandro de Castro</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835846</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1839-06-09/1839-06-09">1839-06-09</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_42eeb6b67b967bcef978ca6049b3e4a9" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_f1b59e1c4f40a00bd72c45074b7f88f2" parent="aspace_42eeb6b67b967bcef978ca6049b3e4a9" type="Folder">55</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5361d3049430dee8c983621bddd3b1e2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Both enslaved by second lieutenant Alejandro de Castro, Luis from Congo was 17 years old, and Ricardo was 12. De Castro was their godfather.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_52cefd147939003b378340fbd9eacc62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Declaration for Miguel, Born to Freewoman Agueda Valdes</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835847</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1869-07-05/1869-07-05">1869-07-05</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_4ac606c9f625384c5e12e03e6fe33267" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_455cbf89abffd88f42b966020833fca1" parent="aspace_4ac606c9f625384c5e12e03e6fe33267" type="Folder">56</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc29ce43a8c220dd979f9357c953b29c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Document issued in Havana. Miguel was the son of Agueda Valdes. His father was unknown. His godmother was Manuela Martinez Rubio.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5a0f16bb58291210df2034d496ade1ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baptismal Declaration for Juan of Lucumi Origin</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835848</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1836-05-08/1836-05-08">1836-05-08</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_27153251498399c17e97bb5760db84cd" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_63499de76af22fb580f57e73b831be31" parent="aspace_27153251498399c17e97bb5760db84cd" type="Folder">57</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db95a84b951e91858dfce025e49c1eb1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Document issued in San Salvador de la Prensa Barrio del Serro. Juan, of Lucumi origin, was enslaved by Pedro Martirn Rabell, his godfather, Alejo, was also enslaved by Jose Calasano Bilardebo.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_890c43aa2543e89797c29ac681a067b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice for the Child of Two Enslaved people, Nestor and Ramona</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835849</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847/1847">1847</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_b63cd815977cf8e66cebb2679c46417b" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4661c769714fdaaada4bae23a466c238" parent="aspace_b63cd815977cf8e66cebb2679c46417b" type="Folder">58</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f14ddcfca831204f4facea88f5a1f657"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document indicates that the father, Nestor, is from Congo and the mother, Ramona, is from Ganga (now known as Sierra Leone). Both parents were enslaved by Leon de Martiartu. The son, Nemesio, was declared as a legitimate child and his godmother, Ynes Martiartu, was a free woman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3c6a17625feb6d46f5a27dac2327f35f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Request to Have a Newborn Child of an Enslaved Woman and Unnamed Man Baptized</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835850</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1852-10-22/1852-10-22">1852-10-22</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_4a34b33acfcc77ab35ecac91c20b735a" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_2406bc20eb6b66061c00836f19d6c879" parent="aspace_4a34b33acfcc77ab35ecac91c20b735a" type="Folder">59</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0600398770300aa1120ea47dfe1b0335"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Petition to the local priest of Cerro to baptize the enslaved son of Ynes, also enslaved by Francisco A. Cabañas. The name of the son is illegible.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a662329fdeb8127d130fdd05d557edf4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statement of Baptism for a Congolese Enslaved Person who Belongs to the "Commission of the Railroad"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835851</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1836-03-27/1836-03-27">1836-03-27</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_567bfaef256ebfb12071b0cc9b7a578e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_b9a9ddb4fc1815a1b59421ea88423fb1" parent="aspace_567bfaef256ebfb12071b0cc9b7a578e" type="Folder">60</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2efee9c08efb19e6905f9409a6be4976"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Statement issued in San Salvador del Cerro documenting the baptism of Pablo, a person of the Congolese nation. The godfather is listed as Zeferino Carabali, who was to pay the rights for the ceremony. Signed by Domingo Alvarez.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bd9d214a6a52d2b325203e1b50b1a835" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscript Concerning the Capture of Escaped Enslaved People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835852</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-05-05/1868-05-05">1868-05-05</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_62a652c9b543877c57ca09c627154b79" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_bbee6588ea11f028d5389856bbf3d0f0" parent="aspace_62a652c9b543877c57ca09c627154b79" type="Folder">61</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c83ff51a35926ab0c632666e08b7f0ba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The document concerns the escape of Luis, an enslaved person from Congo, and Anastasio, another enslaved person, both captured by Simon Garcia in Canasi. Their enslaver was Dolores Pebles de Pimienta. The document notes they were sent to the deposit of the maroons, and is addressed to the governor of Matanzas.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_83e751c940c5c53f5cb5babb238016f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Declaration that the Sacred Sacrament is Being Given to an Enslaved Person</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835853</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847/1847">1847</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_5939e3335c77bc8345c481b7e2ff7b5e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_0d43905a337b2633ce6ecc0246189ba4" parent="aspace_5939e3335c77bc8345c481b7e2ff7b5e" type="Folder">62</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_933ae26e145bec3fe6f1e7d9e7a34fb6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The enslaved person, Aguenda, is described as Black <emph render="italic">criolla</emph>, daughter of Fumasa (surname illegible) and enslaved by Ygnacio de Arrieta. The godmother's name appears to be Maria Anta (possibly Antonia) Carabo.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fef5a7fea31ec669dfc658439fa2d0ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice for the Child of an Enslaved Mother</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835854</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1877-12-05/1877-12-05">1877-12-05</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_fc046870d27d96fad6ca0d232c1ccc09" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_96b53d717817fa2675cf7cb714a30584" parent="aspace_fc046870d27d96fad6ca0d232c1ccc09" type="Folder">63</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d74ee5a6ce5dd2f2d34639114ed8f0eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The child, Francisco Santiago de la Trinidad, was son to Sixta, <emph render="italic">criolla</emph>, enslaved by Alejandro S. Juste. The godparents were Carlos Alfonso and Merced Vercuses (uncertain).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6f52161cc0fe808bb4c0b8e1c85f6316" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice for Merced Candelaria</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835855</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847-04-11/1847-04-11">1847-04-11</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_d730a36c1391a9a043f353c7e10c6972" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4b9259431b2de4b16df2bd92b4d7588f" parent="aspace_d730a36c1391a9a043f353c7e10c6972" type="Folder">64</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d0b8358731e2c631a6d9a84c826a8d4b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This document describes the birth of Merced Candelaria on February 2, 1847. Merced's mother was named Eusebia de Torre, her father was unknown, and both Merced and Eusebia's control over their lives was inherited to Fercia de Torres. Merced's godmother's name was Trinidad Pastrana, <emph render="italic">criolla</emph> enslaved by Concepcion Miranda.</p><p>This document was produced in San Salvador del Cerro.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_207e377e6bc5b21f0cd0243e2e31043e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statement on Martina Abasi</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835856</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1860/1869" type="inclusive">circa 1860s</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_c127c66eb67285cb66cd8a7a4513acae" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_57f9e5f1875629f563803e0cc8a9bc92" parent="aspace_c127c66eb67285cb66cd8a7a4513acae" type="Folder">65</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77ec503f575dbd8839d1d7675c7d3b16"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Martina Abasi, a free woman of color of Carabali origin, is identified as the godmother of emancipated people.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_21b1bef7c2d780c40854504e36307e5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of the Child of Juana Albarez</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835857</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1859" type="inclusive">circa 1850s</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_81cb0933676bc8898472f68803c58318" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_a5bbe0af42345b8720aca59927c0448c" parent="aspace_81cb0933676bc8898472f68803c58318" type="Folder">66</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3e5045fdf32443be8c396b5791aeeb6e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Note on the birth of Jose de los Santos, the child of Juana Albarez, a free woman of color, on All Saints Day. The child is the grandchild of Antonio Albarez and Rosalia Carrosa, also free people of color, and the godchild of Anselmo Garcia and Ysabel Angel, both identified as <emph render="italic">criollo</emph>. The father is unknown.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_119bdb7f34a17927da29c005bcf398a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Maria Manuela</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835858</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1877-01-20/1877-01-20">1877-01-20</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_dc6daac59eb8a1720a9d2d6e055bcba1" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_3221c7336138a1b3d528328d343ae5a1" parent="aspace_dc6daac59eb8a1720a9d2d6e055bcba1" type="Folder">67</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_31dbc32d69fc81a3c926cf32c7ccb901"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Note on the birth of Maria Manuela, to Emilia Dias (born Guines), maternal grandmother Eusebia Dias, and godmother Dominga Valdes, in Cerro.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f3f9e520c028136b2e1944530053cb40" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baptism Notice of Pastoria Maria del Rosario</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835859</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1862-06-14/1862-06-14">1862-06-14</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_9686b571d320947674fc99a650168c3f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_538898f8308b92bf342fdc28f3b73596" parent="aspace_9686b571d320947674fc99a650168c3f" type="Folder">68</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5d831a43ef923c25ebae38cc95a61283"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Notice of the baptism in Cerro of Pastoria Maria del Rosario, a <emph render="italic">criolla</emph> child born on March 30, 1862 into enslavement. She was the daughter of Polonia, a <emph render="italic">criolla</emph> woman, and an unknown father. Both parents were enslaved by Ygnacio de Vildosola. The godmother of the child is listed as Asunsion, a <emph render="italic">criolla</emph> woman enslaved by Josefa de Osmal. The document is signed by Nieves Gonzalez de Vildosola, administrator and heiress of Ygnacio de Vildosola, and addressed to the local priest of Cerro.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_340ca355e40f6777e952a085a18d0ab2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Serafin Urvano de Jesus, and Proof of Baptism of José</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835860</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864-07-10/1864-07-10">1864-07-10</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_3289b6cb5ce320941fc9c7035f55784b" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_997d7f95c6b9d535455d9e38a932ad60" parent="aspace_3289b6cb5ce320941fc9c7035f55784b" type="Folder">69</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_053252a35e9731684104293ac5b59398"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Notice of the birth of Serafin Urvano de Jesus on May 25, 1864 in Habana. Serafin was the legitimate son of the bachelor (<emph render="italic">bachiller</emph>) Rafael Pelaez, from Havana, and Ysabel Maria Hernandez, born in Managua, godchild of Serafin Pacheco, knight of the royal order of King Carlos III.  A signed statement follows declaring proof of baptism of José, an emancipated seventeen-year-old Congolese person, formerly enslaved by Colonel Antonio Garcia Rizo. José was also the godchild of Manuel, a person enslaved by knight Serafin Pacheco.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_5f35b1abc936a5bc1f036a4b00dfd035" level="file"><did><unittitle>Neighborhood News Bulletin Describing a Robbery</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835861</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1879/1879">1879</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_04dde7899144d7967007d58bf664d73e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_7eec580fbf7bcb597a6a6f3c21b043d0" parent="aspace_04dde7899144d7967007d58bf664d73e" type="Folder">70</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_86588505c963cb392758956e30d6498c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Manuscript news bulletin announcing the robbery that allegedly happened to Camilo Macua, an emancipated man. He claimed his identification papers and money were stolen.</p><p>A transcription of this document is avaialable by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_837dc59b6c11a2612b79ad49bf43dc5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Maria Laurecia</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835862</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1877-07-04/1877-07-04">1877-07-04</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_f998b935d4092ee49c66d3b6b539b239" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_96d6051051e951f28a8b97aebabe4aad" parent="aspace_f998b935d4092ee49c66d3b6b539b239" type="Folder">71</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e66359af6fc0eeccc0597ee63f6c41f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Notice of the birth of Maria Laurencia, in the community of Cerro. Lucrecia was the daughter of Vicenta, a <emph render="italic">criolla</emph> woman, and an unknown father who was enslaved by J. Godinez. The child's godmother was Maria Rincheta, a <emph render="italic">criolla</emph> woman enslaved by Sofia Perran.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ed77a7e7751cfec97b8f059f93220231" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscript Concerning Two Enslaved People Not Listed on Ship Manifest</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835863</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1809/1898" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_b94d441c70d5acac078b7e29bd61cbe9" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_a83dafc42e87ef794c2378e639c15df5" parent="aspace_b94d441c70d5acac078b7e29bd61cbe9" type="Folder">72</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2def83b675ea27020111bbaedbf82a85"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Manuscript concerning two enslaved people at Cabo Yndio named Ynes and Raimunda, both of Lucumí origin, not listed on ship manifest. Place and year of issue is unknown.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e8d61f2bcceabdc54c4587778d7cf9dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Arnalda</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835864</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847-05-13/1847-05-13">1847-05-13</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_f9e6d73c1a65963f8bba9d761a279071" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4e52748890862c81ef2737a78e697793" parent="aspace_f9e6d73c1a65963f8bba9d761a279071" type="Folder">73</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85e68551ebbe7398466cad02137b189b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Notice of the birth of Arnalda, a <emph render="italic">criolla</emph> girl. Arnalda is the legitimate daughter of Nestor from Congo and Ramona from Ganga (now known as Sierra Leone), both enslaved by Leon de Martiartu. Her godmother is Josefa Martiartu.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_30431246750084a6b2ae0e6c0211c832" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscript Concerning Eulogio, an Emancipated Congolese Person Pursued by Law Enforcement</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835865</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846-09-04/1846-09-04">1846-09-04</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_5676f3b7692e2c07e0b4cf58d0987c51" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_a11fd4e56028725307415853dda7bd7b" parent="aspace_5676f3b7692e2c07e0b4cf58d0987c51" type="Folder">74</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d3cfbfe56c3e8cc4b69ecb4f535c947b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>According to the document, Eulogio, an emancipated man, had run away since he was afraid of the punishments foremen were giving to him. He was captured, had his body examined in search of any marks that would serve as evidence of said punishments, and after not having found any sigfniciant marks, was held and placed at the disposal of the governor in Matanzas.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f7a63b6bcebe5461971e583e1c7cf2ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Emancipation Document for Five People</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835866</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1886-10-09/1886-10-09">1886-10-09</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_d0639d2d7f94d82dcb49484120ed1036" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_975f9cf20aa5b11e56548a82d523f2b6" parent="aspace_d0639d2d7f94d82dcb49484120ed1036" type="Folder">75</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_caf2dac47e76bf67f1bb005e63b40f52"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Emancipation document for five people in Bolondron: Guadalupe, Silvestre, Ricardo, Ruperto, and Eduardo. Among the causes for emancipation are listed "of mutual agreement", "out of grace," and indemnification.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_15998165204f2cb49e2b776621f1c443" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manumission Document for Higinio Guillermo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835867</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1860-10-09/1860-10-09">1860-10-09</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_3724e7027a286d6a9b452da62aff8101" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_6736dfc24b19e28a27f92e8a50d14a4a" parent="aspace_3724e7027a286d6a9b452da62aff8101" type="Folder">76</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_05fb4f778b6ef0f9e38c60cfb7d99fb5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Manumission document for Higinio Guillermo, a boy in Habana born to an enslaved woman named Juana Paula. Higinio Guillermo's father is not named. Higinio Guillermo's former enslaver was María de Jesús Meza. The document was witnessed by Manuel García, Antonio Fernández and Felipe Maria Soya.</p><p>A transcription of this document is available by request.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_69ccab387e1cecbdcd8aa28d540f42d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Death Certificate for Domingo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835868</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1876/1876">1876</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_4510769619c2426fe10acff98733cab9" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_b75035cce4a8c1d50ac6debdd4822ed4" parent="aspace_4510769619c2426fe10acff98733cab9" type="Folder">77</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_90808730d913886765ab4818066061d4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Death certificate for Domingo, a man described as an escaped enslaved person originally from Asia. Domingo died from fever at the age of 30 at the Hospital de Caridad de San Felipe y Santiago on August 23, 1874. The document is dated December 23, 1776, but the year is likely incorrect.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6254ab31223965db3d976a23e7c23d34" level="file"><did><unittitle>Emancipation Document for Five Persons</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835869</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1881-01-31/1881-01-31">1881-01-31</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_828b2b896845586b2d88e61d6431a0fb" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_ee05315f912a7d3d21c741d99ad9f645" parent="aspace_828b2b896845586b2d88e61d6431a0fb" type="Folder">78</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4ee910190966608ed91a0979e7e70e39"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Issued in Matanzas. The emancipated persons were Maria Nicolasa, born in Cuba, formerly enslaved by Enrique García and Oña; Valentín, of Lucumí origin, formerly enslaved by Socorro de Armas; Gregoria, <emph render="italic">criolla</emph>, formerly enslaved by Juan G. Lavin; Luisa, formerly enslaved by Oña and sisters; and Matilde and her daughter Perfecta, <emph render="italic">criollas</emph>, formerly enslaved by Micaela Leiva.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e1ff44c1e6a0b2610e5b240f42e0ca5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notice that an Emancipated Man was Seen in a Havana Warehouse</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835870</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-06-23/1868-06-23">1868-06-23</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_b37510c0fea4e27c69aa4aea59bc6379" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_52924f3bbf45694fd895754086ae591e" parent="aspace_b37510c0fea4e27c69aa4aea59bc6379" type="Folder">79</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3506cc4390779b0821e17b196306d686"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The man located in Havana was Juan Macías, formerly enslaved (then emancipated) by Ygnacio de Cárdenas in Matanzas. The document is signed by Manuel Y. Madrigal.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c7032d4e814bd2cb4bfb2ee1982184e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Angel Custodio</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835871</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851-10-26/1851-10-26">1851-10-26</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_52c3ef0641e395f622a59ae229a6e52f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_6681d105e44c22f126cebac5501a2763" parent="aspace_52c3ef0641e395f622a59ae229a6e52f" type="Folder">80</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ef832ed06abb11bb9e00fc5a2da6ccab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the vicinity of Cerro, on October 2nd, Angel Custodio was born to Damiana Escoto, born in Cuba, and Rafael Galarraga, Lucumí, all enslaved by José Antonio de Galarraga. The godparents were José Antonio Cárdenas and Andrea. The document is also signed by Maria Lusia Meza de Galarraga.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_d4967b318a291c21dab235a090b8d59b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Maria Micaela Garcia</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835872</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1898-04-26/1898-04-26">1898-04-26</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_7c3df9ffc4d31aedbbdd31e564a1f397" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_10872e434bc015cb7d3685a9febaf9ff" parent="aspace_7c3df9ffc4d31aedbbdd31e564a1f397" type="Folder">81</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_804dc026dadd14b391537efa5bb90396"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the vicinity of Cerro, María Micaela García was born to Micaela García. María's maternal grandmother was Federica Piedra, and her godparents were José Matilde Cordovés and Carlota Cordovés.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_be777e506db12acae516f04c148cc44f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Francisca Beatriz</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835873</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838-12-09/1838-12-09">1838-12-09</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_d0acbb592213120936c2fc64bd75083e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_6b91a2b0dd26d76dad4480cadcd6d3c6" parent="aspace_d0acbb592213120936c2fc64bd75083e" type="Folder">82</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f82ade45b781ef1b818690d855e2fb70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>On July 27, 1837, Francisca Beatriz was born to José de Zayas Basan, born in Wajay, and Ana de Pabia, born in Cuba. Francisca Beatriz' paternal grandparents were Pablo de Zayas Basan and María de Jesús Sanmartin. Her maternal grandparents were Agustín and Bernarda Acosta. Her godparents Agustín Ferrera and Francisca Valdes.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7cf6fd5e7aa563bec8ca62d013b99a06" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Maria Ca[ndel]aria</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835874</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847-04-17/1847-04-17">1847-04-17</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_0f1ae4442bb56aedc82f723f117a825e" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_7603a8072d821d3d4c242741d0e7f76f" parent="aspace_0f1ae4442bb56aedc82f723f117a825e" type="Folder">83</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8762eb93f90555872aee8d05929afd6e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>On February 2, Maria Candelaria was baptized. She was legitimate daughter of Antonio Vidal and Asuncion Dias, both born in Havana. Her paternal grandparents were José Vidal and Caridad de Laya. The maternal grandparents were Francisco Dominguez and Rosario Diaz. Her godmather was Luisa Martine.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_40103c57d4101625d00c57f420518253" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Calletana</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835875</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1848-08-20/1848-08-20">1848-08-20</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_fd297eced8da7d941113b64d3a32f32c" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_bd816376ea607887cf3e2d9b7f519945" parent="aspace_fd297eced8da7d941113b64d3a32f32c" type="Folder">84</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_750fba6c703d7521dd5cb31673c31dcb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This document is a birth notice of a child, Calletana, who was likely enslaved. Her godmother's name was Luisa. The document was issued in Cerro.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b4473bae1a661dc8ebaa6d118bcd1f79" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Notice of Aparicio, Ganga, on the <emph render="italic">Aurelia Feliz</emph> Schooer (<emph render="italic">Goleta</emph>)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835876</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1844-07-28/1844-07-28">1844-07-28</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_e1d15697484861770cff640875453a04" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_d6931afc9ec80bb04db7e4982ea65772" parent="aspace_e1d15697484861770cff640875453a04" type="Folder">85</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_295770a4a0d8830b991da5ce6b176232"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In the Villanueva station of the Camino de Hierro (railroad), a child, Aparicio, of Ganga origin, was born on the goleta <emph render="italic">Aurelia Feliz</emph>. The child's godfather was Leoncio, of Lucumí origin. The document is signed by M. Machado.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4fece2a0dbe00f40d60488199de34b46" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscript of Priest Presenting Two <emph render="italic">Criados</emph> for Domestic Labor</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/archival_objects/835877</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1836-06-05/1836-06-05">1836-06-05</unitdate><container altrender="Flat Box - 12 x 15.25" id="aspace_4d58fb29959a81d363fffd7f36b216eb" label="Mixed Materials [31142063011459]" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_96cc9f1613cd0d27b910ca42c2e10ac6" parent="aspace_4d58fb29959a81d363fffd7f36b216eb" type="Folder">86</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3f00086a0fd995c5099addd4ddd53a4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The priest authorized for Pedro and Pio to be enslaved as servants for Bernardo de Abas. The document is signed by Francisco Enriquez.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
