<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="findingaid" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="https://findingaids.library.nyu.edu/tamwag/alba_graphics_001/">alba_graphics_001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Spanish Civil War Poster Collection <num>ALBA.GRAPHICS.001</num></titleproper><author>Johanna Blocker, 2006, and Erika Gottfried, Gail Malmgreen and Sarah DeMott</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><p><date>2011</date></p><address><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>Business Number: (212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-06-09 19:48:01 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>August 2017</date><item>Updated by Megan O'Shea to incorporate artwork being sent to offsite art storage in September 2017.</item></change><change><date>June 2025</date><item>Updated by Weatherly Stephan to note closure of collection</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Spanish Civil War Poster Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n50068362" source="naf">Tamiment Library</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>ALBA.GRAPHICS.001</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/287</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">234 items</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/2003" type="inclusive">1936-2003</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1939" type="bulk">1936-1939</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8f237d71db74940889fe2d006a0e43a2" label="Abstract">This collection is comprised of two separate, but related, groups of Spanish Civil War posters held by the Tamiment Library.  Although the two groups are stored separately, and are of different provenance, their closely related contents warranted bringing them together in a single collection guide. Series I: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, 1936-2003: The core group of posters in this group came to the Tamiment Library as part of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Collection, which was acquired by New York University in 2001. Other posters have been donated since, and the collection continues to grow. Spanish Civil War Posters were published by a variety of organizations representing both sides of the conflict, but best known, and most numerous, were those produced by the government of the Spanish Republic and its various divisions and allies -- government bodies, political parties, trade unions, and other groups ranging from Socialist, Communist and Anarchist parties to art collectives, youth groups, and aid organizations. Of the more than 230 posters in the ALBA series most were produced and published in Spain by groups that supported the cause of the Republic. But the series also includes posters published in the United States, Italy, Mexico, Cuba, France, and Germany, either in support of the Republican cause, or, in later years, to publicize commemorations, anniversaries, exhibits, film screenings, and other events relating to Spanish Civil War history. Series II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection (TAM Graphics 002), 1936-1938: This group of posters is part of the Library's general poster collection.  It is an open collection, acquired by the library over many years, from many sources.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <altformavail id="aspace_648a02dbfc378d829b5f59e989dda486">
    <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
<p>Most of the images in Series II may be viewed online--both on-site and remotely--via the ARTstor website at http://library.artstor.org/library/welcome.html by researchers who are affiliated with New York University. Researchers not affiliated with New York University may view these images online only while visiting the Tamiment Library.</p>  </altformavail>
  <custodhist id="aspace_d71142a49b133d54c446abb9796b5528">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>Series I: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, 1936-2003. The core group of posters in this group came to the Tamiment Library as part of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, which was acquired by New York University in 2001. Other posters have been donated since, and the collection continues to grow.</p><p>Series II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection (TAM Graphics 002), 1936-1938. This group of posters form part of the Library's general poster collection.  It is an assembled collection, acquired by the library over many years, from many sources.</p><p>The accession number 1950.157 is associated with this collection.</p>  </custodhist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_552ce8c35e7f19f71b144e0207004177">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Access to this collection is restricted until September 2025 for reprocessing. Following reprocessing, the collection will undergo conservation treatment and may remain closed.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_59355bc16df8235e8790071def65bba8">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the collection. Copyrights held by original creators of individual items in the collection are expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. Any rights (including copyright and related rights to publicity and privacy) held by the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) were transferred to New York University in November 2000 by the ALBA Board of Governors. Permission to publish or reproduce ALBA materials must be secured from the Tamiment Library &amp; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. For more information, contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_614425cfefdd6e0a9375a06afc8b4625">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form: <lb/><lb/>Identification of item, date (if known); Spanish Civil War Poster Collection; ALBA GRAPHICS 001; item number; Tamiment Library; New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5c142d2fde362a366447a154134f060b">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Political posters' essential role in propaganda and sustaining morale of both combatants and civilians during the Spain's Civil War of 1936-1939 has been well-documented in numerous books, exhibitions and catalogs. They were published by organizations representing both sides of the conflict, but best known, and most numerous, were those produced by the government of the Spanish Republic and its allies. These posters, published by political parties, labor unions and federations, and other entities, reflect deep divisions between the Republic's supporters -- ranging from the Socialist, Communist and Anarchist parties, to smaller splinter groups, collectives, aid organizations, youth groups, and regional militias.</p><p>Their striking graphic qualities and propaganda value, which observers noted during the War and have attracted art historians and collectors ever since, served very practical ends. Posters were aimed at, and competed for the attention of, viewers who were often literally under fire. The large numbers of posters that were produced (an estimated 1,500-2,000 posters appeared, many printed in editions of 3,000 to 5,000, in the brief period 1936-1939) made them "an essential part of the visual landscape" of the war, as one scholar has observed. Posters were also used to garner support for the Republic, and for the International Brigades of volunteers that came to its defense, in other countries around the world.</p><p>In the years after the War's end, posters continued to be used to publicize history of the Republic and its legacies. Posters protested the authoritarian rule of General Franco (whose rebel forces had defeated the Republic), memorialized the War and the Republic, advocated for refugees and veterans, and eventually celebrated the return of a democratically-elected government to Spain after Franco's death in 1975.</p><p>Sources:</p><p><list><item><emph render="italic">La guerra civil en 2000 carteles: república-guerra civil-posguerra</emph>, compiled by Jordi Carulla and Arnau Carulla. [Alternate title: <emph render="italic">Guerra civil en dos mil cartels</emph>] Barcelona: Postermil, 1997.</item><item>The visual front: posters of the Spanish Civil War from UCSD's Southworth Collection. (http://orpheus.ucsd.edu/speccoll/visfront/vizindex.html)</item></list> </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9c325070a037d22f933662b174e7114b">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection is comprised of two separate, but related, groups of Spanish Civil War posters held by the Tamiment Library.  Although the two groups are stored separately, and are of different provenance, their closely related contents warranted bringing them together in a single collection guide.  Researchers should note the item numbers of any posters requested, since these numbers reflect the locations of individual posters.  Each poster has an item number consisting of two letters, followed by a number. The two letters denote the country in which the poster was produced: CU=Cuba, DD=Germany, ES=Spain, FR=France, IT=Italy, MX=Mexico, US=United States.  Poster locations are indicated by flat file case (FFC) number and folder number.</p><p><emph render="bold">Series I: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Collection, 1936-2003.</emph> is divided into four sub-series, as follows: 
Subseries I:A: Civil War Era: Spain, 1936-1938.
Subseries I:B: Civil War Era: Other Countries, 1937-1943.
Subseries I:C: Post-Civil War Era: Spain, 1976-1997.
Subseries I:D: Post-Civil War Era; Other Countries, 1966-2003.</p><p>The majority of the posters in this series were produced and published in Spain by organizations (political parties and their subgroups, national regional and local government agencies, military authorities, trade unions, aid organizations, collectives, etc.) supporting the cause of the Spanish Republic, but the collection also includes posters published during the war years and after in the United States, Italy, Mexico, Cuba, France, and Germany. Identified creators of the posters include thirty-three artists, the best-known of whom are Jose Bardasano, Josep Renau, and the Hungarian-American, Hugo Gellert.  About half the poster artists are not identified.</p><p>Civil War era posters were published by a wide variety of organizations, including, but not limited to: the Socialist-leaning Union General de Trabajadores (UGT); the anarchist Confederación Nacional del Trabajo (CNT) and Juventudes Libertarias; Partido Comunista de España; Front Popular de Catalunya; Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid; El Grupo Sindical Socialista de Radiocomunicacion lleguara a la URE. a la Victoria; Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes, UGT; and the parallel (and rival) aid organizations, Socorro Rojo Internacional (aka International Red Aid, sponsored by the Communist International) and Socorro Rojo de España (sponsored by the Partido Obrero de Unificación Marxista, [POUM]). Organizations based outside of Spain include the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade and the Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee.</p><p>The post-Civil War era posters, also divided between those produced in Spain and in other countries, were produced to commemorate anniversaries; to honor the veterans; and to publicize film screenings, theatrical performances, conferences, and other events relating to Spanish Civil War history.</p><p><emph render="bold">Series II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection (TAM Graphics 002), 1936-1938.</emph> This is an open collection, acquired by the library over many years, from many sources.  Subjects and artists represented are similar to those in Subseries I:A.</p><p><emph render="bold">NOTE:</emph>Access to this collection is closed through September 2025 for reprocessing.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_60fe10e0e0950a5ebc103dcb2cda91b0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Items are arranged alphabetically by artist's surname, followed by items arranged alphabetically by title (posters for which the artist's name is unknown).</p><p>Organized into two series: I:Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, 1936-2003; II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection, 1936-1938.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2939c7938f932ba5afcc16ec9216c799">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In August 2017, one item was prepared to be moved to offsite art storage in September 2017.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Posters.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Posters</geogname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n80146702" rules="dacs" source="naf">Confederación Nacional del Trabajo (Spain)</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr99000072" source="naf">Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr98043919" source="naf">Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2009098484" source="naf">Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no94026152" source="naf">Federación Ibérica de Juventudes Libertarias</corpname>
    <persname source="local">Calandin, José</persname>
    <persname source="local">Clusellas, Enric</persname>
    <persname source="local">Espert, José</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Amster, Mauricio, 1907-1980</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Bardasano Baos, José, 1910-1979</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Bon, 1886-1967</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Briones Martinez, José</persname>
    <corpname source="local">Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr94022789" source="naf">Juventudes Libertarias (Spain)</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Renau, Josep, 1907-1982</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Melendreras, Emeterio</persname>
    <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Unión General de Trabajadores de España</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2005073712" source="naf">Socorro Rojo de España</corpname>
    <persname source="ingest">Xirinius Juez, Juame.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Vila Gimeno, Vicente, 1908-2009</persname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Nicome Jos Gomez</persname>
    <corpname source="local">Front Popular de Catalunya</corpname>
    <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Obiols, Ricard</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Goñi, Lorenzo</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n80113977" source="naf">International Red Aid</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid</corpname>
    <persname source="ingest">Puyol, Ramón.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
