<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_837">tam_837</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Records of the A/P/A Voices A COVID-19 Public Memory Project <num>TAM.837</num></titleproper><author>Shannon O'Neill, Rachel Searcy, Asian/Pacific/American Institute, Amita Manghnani, Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk, Cynthia Gao, Diane Wong, Emma Callahan, Lena Sze, Linda Kuo, Loubna Qutami, Mi Hyun Yoon, Minju Bae, Preeti Sharma, Rochelle Kwan, Ronak Gandhi, Rosario Joaquin, Sarah Lin, Sarah Nguyen, Tomie Arai, Vivian Truong, Zaim Alam, and Aki Snyder</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><p><date>June 2024</date></p><address><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>Business Number: (212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-04-22 17:13:16 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>January 2025</date><item>Record updated by Rachel Searcy to reflect 2025 accretion</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Records of the A/P/A Voices: A COVID-19 Public Memory Project</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n2003031517" source="naf">New York University. Asian/Pacific/American Studies Program and Institute</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n2003031517" role="dnr" source="naf">New York University. Asian/Pacific/American Studies Program and Institute</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.837</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/3522</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 3 folders in shared manuscript box </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">106 Gigabytes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 450 computer files</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2024" type="inclusive">2019-2024</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_1064d4c7eb7cc04233b79c6846c170a1">The A/P/A Voices: A COVID-19 Public Memory Project is a documentation project focused on the COVID-19 pandemic, specifically the ways the pandemic impacted Asian/Pacific/American (A/P/A) communities in New York City and nationally. The core principles guiding the project include intersectionality and cross-racial solidarity with other communities of color who suffer the effects of structural racism and state violence. The Records of the A/P/A Voices: A COVID-19 Public Memory Project (dated 2019-2024) consists of materials created and collected by the A/P/A Institute at New York University, in collaboration with Tomie Arai, Lena Sze, Vivian Truong, and Diane Wong. Materials include oral history interviews, zines, poetry, fliers, brochures, photographs, and short videos. The collection also includes a copy of <emph render="italic">Bittersweet: A Pandemic Sketchbook</emph>, a comic by Nuyên Khôi Nguyễn, and ephemera documenting the activities of Khmer Girls in Action (KGA).</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8c05bd89d60de49668e2ccff39c2d1e2">The majority of materials are in English, but some materials are in Chinese and Korean.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2a2b79bdd7d6501904987f758103ce7a">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The A/P/A Voices: A COVID-19 Public Memory Project is a documentation project focused on the COVID-19 pandemic, specifically the ways the pandemic impacted Asian/Pacific/American (A/P/A) communities in New York City and nationally.  The project was developed by the Asian/Pacific/American Institute at New York University, in collaboration with Tomie Arai, Lena Sze, Vivian Truong, and Diane Wong. The project's goal was to account for a gap in documentation about the experiences of A/P/A communities in relation to the COVID-19 pandemic, as well as a historical pattern where the experiences of A/P/A individuals and communities were often un- or under-documented. The core principles guiding the project include intersectionality and cross-racial solidarity with other communities of color who suffer the effects of structural racism and state violence. The killings of George Floyd, Tony McDade, Ahmaud Arbery, Breonna Taylor, and many other Black people by police, and subsequent protests in response to these events, were significant and an explicit context of the project.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_a864686c1c42ddbe9dd14fa3bd0c10ac">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into a single file listing in alphabetical order by name or organization.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_db265735f9ed9d64fdfdad0db54ad504">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Records of the A/P/A Voices: A COVID-19 Public Memory Project (dated 2019-2024) consists of materials created and collected by the A/P/A Institute at New York University, in collaboration with Tomie Arai, Lena Sze, Vivian Truong, and Diane Wong. The interviews and supplementary materials found in the collection document the experiences of Asian/Pacific/American (A/P/A) community members as subjects of their own stories and offer opportunities for parallels and possibilities for solidarity across communities. Other subject areas include the increased anti-Asian violence and xenophobia of the pandemic, and the ways COVID-19 disproportionately impacted Pacific Islander communities, as well as Asian immigrant services and healthcare workers. The presence of materials connecting growing anti-Asian fears during the COVID-19 pandemic to the Black Lives Matter movement also highlights the ways racial discrimination united these communities.  </p><p>Materials in the collection include oral history interviews and transcripts; artistic works, zines, and poetry; fliers and brochures; and photographs and short videos. Not all oral histories are accompanied by digital ephemera and not all ephemera relates to a particular interview. </p><p>The collection also contains physical materials including a copy of <emph render="italic">Bittersweet: A Pandemic Sketchbook</emph> (a comic) by Nuyên Khôi Nguyễn, and ephemera documenting the activities of Khmer Girls in Action (KGA).</p><p>When available, biographical information about project participants has been included in the inventory. A brief description of what each participant contributed to the project has also been noted in the inventory, when information is available. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_cbbb2c9baf5265779858fe7e536590c9">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Access varies across the collection for the oral history interviews and the conditions governing access to those materials are documented at the level of the individual narrators. Other non-oral history interview materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3695cd2a0222e852bcc75ede326a20d5">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The materials in this collection are protected by copyright and/or related rights, which are held by individual donors. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_dec72a8753b7e3b2c01d53aee560a2b9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the Asian/Pacific/American Institute in May 2024; the accession number associated with this gift is 2024.035. Physical materials were donated by Khmer Girls in Action and Nuyên Khôi Nguyễn to A/P/A Voices coordinators and transferred to Tamiment in August 2024; the accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2025.008 and 2025.009, respectively.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_56404360fbacf330efa47e1027b2a4c0">
    <head>Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.</p>  </phystech>
  <prefercite id="aspace_92447ffb5eb19c22c8ba438d96dbedac">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Records of the A/P/A Voices A COVID-19 Public Memory Project; TAM 837; box number; folder number or item identifier; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_48c065bae407411f5b22f12d013a9cdf">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, directories for collection material (oral history interviews, supplementary digital ephemera, interview transcripts, and field notes) were copied from their temporary donation directory to a digital workspace dedicated to accessioning and processing. Materials were described on the collection-level. Physical materials were rehoused in archival folders and a box; incorporated into the collection-level description; and inventoried on the folder-level.</p><p>New York University Libraries follow professional standards and best practices when imaging, ingesting, and processing born-digital material in order to maintain the integrity and authenticity of the content. Born-digital files were transferred to NYU and placed in the preservation repository. Born-digital files were forensically imaged, analyzed, and arranged using Forensic Toolkit; and the electronic records were intellectually incorporated into the finding aid.  </p><p>The collection was processed and described by an archivist in March 2025. Paper materials were kept in their archival folders and placed into a shared legal manuscript box. The collection, which is predominately digital, was then arranged into a single file listing in alphabetical order by name and organization. Due to the collaborative nature of this project and diverse range of participants, when available, biographical information and descriptions about each participant's donation was noted in the inventory. </p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (literary works)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">COVID-19 (Disease)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Solidarity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Racism -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination against Asian Americans.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Political activity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Race identity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Social conditions.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Zines</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Video recordings.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n2003031517" role="dnr" source="naf">New York University. Asian/Pacific/American Studies Program and Institute</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_9ea4032b3390460772a6789f6f86c675" level="file"><did><unittitle>#IAMNOTAVIRUS </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_1</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019516</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="#IAMNOTAVIRUS " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>#IAMNOTAVIRUS</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_1e776c5be79b3ae5f4887292905988a6"><head>Historical Note</head><p>The #IAMNOTAVIRUS Campaign was part of an artist led grassroots initiative founded by Mike Keo. The initiative's goal is to perform impactful work on inter-ethnic solidarity and an interracial coalition by connecting Black, Indigenous, and People of Color (BIPOC) communities through storytelling. The #IAMNOTAVIRUS Campaign reclaimed the Asian American story, displayed it through an equity lens, and brought together a community of intersectional solidarity.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_30dfde71d1daebfd4194b1d616a36b0b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include #IAMNOTAVIRUS posters, a public service announcement video by Mike Keo, and a copy of <emph render = "italic">A Mental Wellness Activity Book for Asian Americans</emph> sponsored by #IAMNOTAVIRUS and the University of Connecticut's Asian and Asian American Studies Institute (AAASI).</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_bff44d07ba6fa9654f6523968a1d0f9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ali, Shirin</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_2</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020803</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Ali, Shirin" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Ali, Shirin</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a53da5215b1cc2fa0a2ac43be88fad8f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Lena Sze on August 6, 2020. In her interview, Shirin Ali, an Indian American Muslim partnered woman, psychiatrist, and psychoanalyst in New York City spoke about her experiences as shaped by those identifications. Other topics in the interview include her experiences of treating patients' mental health during the pandemic, particularly during the intense wave of COVID-19 in New York City in March and April 2020, and during the George Floyd protests. Ali also discusses her experiences volunteering remotely at a hospital in the Bronx and discusses her observations of the disparate level of resources at different institutions. Finally, Ali discusses her feelings of staying in New York City during COVID-19; being in the health field; and the possible long-term effects of this pandemic, i.e. grief and trauma, on health care professionals and society at large.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_f21d5e912360f8aa404427c5ae505424"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_62632e382822bc22a225eebf96b4e5d1"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Shirin Ali is an Indian American Muslim woman, a psychiatrist, and psychoanalyst in New York City.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_58a18a3961618053252375eb905f5747" level="file"><did><unittitle>Arai, Tomie</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_3</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020805</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Arai, Tomie" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Arai, Tomie</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_62bba9cf22c671c2520bd83673e47338"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Lena Sze on April 8, 2021. A "Stay Strong" poster, which was created for W.O.W. Project's "Love Letters to Chinatown" project is also included. </p><p>In her interview, Tomie Arai reflects on her experiences during this pandemic. She offers her views of the protests following the murder of George Floyd; the tactical differences between 1970s activists and current activists, especially abolitionists, whom she is inspired by; anti-Blackness within Asian American communities; Black-Asian solidarity and incidents of anti-Asian violence; and some of the internal politics of Manhattan's Chinatown. She also reflects on aging; her and her friends' vulnerability as older people to COVID-19; and COVID-19's health and emotional impact on her as it has caused her to think about her own mortality and body of work.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e51589c1cfce92164c2bbd26935c6418"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_c29a44730e1bdd328c6486efcdff0884"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Tomie Arai is a New Yorker and Japanese American artist living on the Upper West Side of New York City. She is a long-time artist involved in social movements and community-based organizing. She has been involved in some pivotal Asian American cultural collectives such as Basement Workshop. Arai also collaborates with local communities to create visual narratives that give meaning to the spaces we live in. Along with Betty Yu and Mansee Kang, Arai is a co-founder of the Chinatown Art Brigade and was a 2020 Transnational Fellow with Monument Lab, an initiative that reimagines public space through stories of social justice and equity.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_5e17eca777bb6f3873fd553b81369d8e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asian American Bar Association of New York (AABANY) </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_4</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019519</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian American Bar Association of New York (AABANY) " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian American Bar Association of New York (AABANY)</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_4ce5d8e8f27068f3d4a3c207c047794e"><head>Historical Note</head><p>The Asian American Bar Association of New York was formed in 1989 as a not-for-profit corporation to represent the interests of New York Asian-American attorneys, judges, law professors, legal professionals, legal assistants, paralegals, and law students. The mission of AABANY is to improve the study and practice of law, and the fair administration of justice for all by ensuring the meaningful participation of Asian-Americans in the legal profession.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e0aff2bfb7f62ebdd068ad1cd31a7d02"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include legal relief flyers in English, Korean, and Chinese; and reports on anti-Asian hate during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3f5fd72c583fef12d713626da5703b91" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asian American Feminist Collective </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_5</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019520</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian American Feminist Collective " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian American Feminist Collective</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f0fab930a2fc547cf146f5bcb1549f86"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include copies of the zine, "Feminist Antibodies: Care in the Time of Coronavirus." The zine was an attempt to find meaning during the coronavirus crisis through long-standing practices of care that came out of Asian American histories and politics. To create the zine, the Asian American Feminist Collective gathered first-hand accounts and analyses from their communities including: health, service workers, and caregivers on the frontlines; students, journalists, and organizers; and people living with chronic illness. Together, this collection of stories, essays, and artwork attempted to illustrate how this community experienced, resisted, and grappled with a viral outbreak that had been racialized as Asian.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4d5a4d4ca68ca7f825bb3d357add3eaa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asian American Writers' Workshop (AAWW) </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_6</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019521</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian American Writers' Workshop (AAWW) " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian American Writers' Workshop (AAWW)</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a34e879418a0d57fd1d47beeaa989ab7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a video entitled "Lit Lunch," which was an interview series featuring writers, journalists, and organizers who talked about their work. This event occurred on May 27, 2020 and featured Huiying B. Chan and Emily Mock.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_acc367ea5da13ea287b4c824e2f8bdd4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asian Pacific Environmental Network (APEN) </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_7</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019522</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">circa 2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian Pacific Environmental Network (APEN) " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian Pacific Environmental Network (APEN)</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_075f992d27d9ab2f07777e2510f84970"><head>Historical Note</head><p>APEN's mission is to bring together a collective voice to develop an alternative agenda for environmental, social, and economic justice. Although APEN holds this vision of environmental justice for all people, APEN's primary focus is on Asian immigrant and refugee communities.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_254233306eb096d18f31d9112c92f8ea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include videos of vigils held in Atlanta, Georgia in the wake of the 2021 spa shootings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eefe35333a685b9e2e68fdf4f3032e13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Attia, Mohamed</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_8</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020807</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Attia, Mohamed" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Attia, Mohamed</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cae52689a7bff2df770d160f97fc56e4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Loubna Qutami on September 16, 2020. The interview details Mohamed Attia's experience as an immigrant street vendor and the myriad of systemic injustices the community has experienced even prior to the COVID-19 pandemic. Attia explains how those challenges were exacerbated following the outbreak of the pandemic and speaks to the different types of services and programs his organization has been offering the Street Vendor Community.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c4c7c1b94674fa2f601c7dca6c31924e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_9e56482e316700201fc87d928fe46259"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Mohamed Attia is an organizer with the Street Vendors Project in New York City. Attia came to the U.S. from Egypt in 2009, began working in local bodegas, and then as a street vendor. Through firsthand experience, Attia witnessed the hardships he and other street vendors from diverse immigrant backgrounds experienced including the difficulty in accessing food vendor permits as a result of discriminatory policies at federal, state, and local levels. Frustrated with the exclusions and oppressions the street vendor community experienced, Attia was eager to contribute to change and joined the Street Vendors Project as a general member in order to advocate for street vendors rights. After several years as a general member, Attia joined the Street Vendors Project as a staff member. Since then, he has been a part of a number of campaigns that seek to secure the rights of street vendors as an important economic, social, and cultural sector of New York City.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_3d773ba52b7daad1edd8a804fcc90e74" level="file"><did><unittitle>Begum, Zenat</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_9</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020809</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Begum, Zenat" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Begum, Zenat</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fe9bebcaaf0b9d99246637cc882c63e1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Zaim Alam on January 22, 2021. During the interview, Zenat Begum spoke extensively about how since the beginning of the pandemic, rather than shelter in place doing nothing, she instead pivoted to the question what Playground Coffee Shop could do to help the community. Distributing personal protective equipment (PPE) became a significant part of Playground's mutual aid efforts, particularly during the protests of summer 2020. Begum was also involved with establishing a community fridge, which was setup in spring 2020, and has since been replicated across the borough.</p><p>Zenat also discusses moments of exhaustion and sheer misfortune she's experienced during the pandemic, and her ability to remain positive. She expresses her belief that while it will be impossible for things to go back to normal post-pandemic, and as long as we sustainably put into action all we have been angered by and fought for, there is light at the end of the tunnel.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ef8f9b0ad0465f1038a56c58767dc590"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_f0abeb30be0ce3ed33ed7703989e3862"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Zenat Begum is an entrepreneur, activist, and native New Yorker of Bangladeshi origin. In 2016, she opened Playground Coffee Shop in Brooklyn's Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood. Begum and her team have further leaned in to serve the community by hosting chess classes, financial literacy workshops, community dinners, and more. During the COVID-19 pandemic, Begum and her peers established an initiative to set up refrigerators with free produce throughout Brooklyn, further demonstrating her mission to serve her community.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_68b12f61061819143b314baafd6d4c89" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bernabe, Thria</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_10</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020811</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Bernabe, Thria" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Bernabe, Thria</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_acff093294bc03fa6ca3241d82bf01f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Rosario Joaquin on July 6, 2020. During the interview, Thria Bernabe describes the impact the pandemic had on her as an individual and the impact it had on her community in Queens. She describes a few of her mutual aid projects, including providing childcare for her emergency room colleagues; and donating profits from her art sales to a rotating list of COVID-19 relief funds and Black-led organizations, such as the Loveland Foundation Therapy Fund. She explains the challenges of living with an immunodeficiency during a pandemic, including facing medication shortages as various drugs were rumored to cure or prevent COVID-19; and making the ultimate decision to leave Queens and return to her family's home in New Jersey, where she could better protect herself from the virus. Bernabe ends her interview describing how art, her friends, family, and community brought her hope; and how she leads with the following guiding principle: we all deserve love, care, and happiness.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_99a908fa1e921205df4d1be4c0dfb6d6"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_b08935cddf39a07f84e75866afac8fb0"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Thria Bernabe is an artist and organizer from New Jersey. She is a graduate of New York University's Rory Meyers School of Nursing and works as a medical scribe for NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital. When the COVID-19 outbreak began in the United States, Bernabe was living in Queens and working in an emergency room.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_07d224a468f51e72fb601a8be8b0a88b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cabiles, Moana</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_11</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020813</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Cabiles, Moana" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Cabiles, Moana</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_25591e9a67b770aac3689bf72a9f2739"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk on December 2, 2020. In her interview, Moana Cabiles shares her experiences as a Native Hawaiian community leader in La Mesa in San Diego, CA. When shelter-in-place was announced in California, Moana and her extended family were preparing for a carefully-planned family vacation in Europe, but due to COVID-19, the family had to cancel these plans and this overlapped with the beginning of other significant shifts that emerged due to the pandemic. </p><p>Cabiles discusses changes in her work due to COVID-19 and the shelter-in-place order; and how the virtual shift to online communication, i.e. using Zoom, changed the social dynamic and relationship-building components of her work. In particular, she emphasizes the difficulty of contacting elected officials. She also discusses challenges faced by her children as they navigated online learning and school; and the challenges faced by Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander (NHPI) elders who do not use the Internet, email, or phones to remain in contact with others. Cabiles also discusses challenges related to Black Lives Matter (BLM) and the particular ways her community was impacted by protests. Though she supported BLM, she shares her anxieties and concerns regarding the violence incited by protests. Cabiles closes the interview by emphasizing the necessity of mental health support and social support resources. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_07f05f9a943e15b27873680a2aed8015"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_210503ab82de376a4ce0b4368211bd73"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Moana Cabiles is a Native Hawaiian community leader in La Mesa in San Diego, CA. Cabiles is a public health advocate and a member of the Community Services Commission in La Mesa. She specifically works with households impacted by smoking.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_bbe04a689d01419ac4c67df6c03ba90d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chang, Han-hua</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_12</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020815</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Chang, Han-hua" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Chang, Han-hua</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d1fc19a303ecd0e50a376f86695b17b7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Sarah Nguyen on March 24, 2021. Two poems titled "Walking Home" and "Photographic Justice" are also included. During his interview, Han-hua Chang discusses the initial onset of COVID-19 during the school year and how he took the pandemic seriously from very early on. Chang talks at length about his school's lackluster response to the pandemic, insensitivity of trauma training in relation to Asian students, dismissals of his own concerns, and lack of discussion around the political turmoil the country had been experiencing. Chang expresses how he misses in-person teaching, and complains his school provided few resources for faculty and students to better facilitate online learning. </p><p>Chang frames many of his experiences during the pandemic through those of his parents. His father died five years ago after experiencing hospice and hospital care; and his mother was in and out of hospitals during the pandemic. Chang's mother contracted COVID-19 in a nursing home and was mistreated by health care professionals throughout her time in various care facilities. Impacted by her past experience as a nurse for the Allies in China during World War II, Chang's mother was very cautious during the pandemic before her health declined. </p><p>Chang discusses his challenging experience getting the vaccine and different parts of his daily routine during the pandemic. Chang, who lives in Columbia University's Law School Dorms, was disturbed by the lack of safety and sensitivity displayed by the college students, who continued to throw parties and not wear masks in the hallways, despite the presence of vulnerable individuals. Chang concludes the interview talking about his experiences in organizing and how he believes the current state of politics has radicalized and united the left. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_0038482ba5bdb413504495f03b409153"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_d96868f676051f1dbf129c71548fa888"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Han-hua Chang is a math teacher at John J. Pershing IS 220 in Sunset Park, NY and lives in the Upper West Side of Manhattan, on the Columbia University campus. He used to be a vice president and organizer for the 1199 SEIU union.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_9aa1eb5dd14c28a3c26dfd7011f76fdd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chang, Kyle</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_13</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1020817</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Chang, Kyle" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Chang, Kyle</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c7eb30de4bfb0205295010d8db4f7559"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Mi Hyun Yoon on March 26, 2021. In his interview, Kyle Chang discusses growing up in Southeast Michigan in Macomb Township. Chang contrasts the hostility of his conservative hometown with how open minded his parents were, and recounts how he came to be adopted by his working-class midwestern Catholic parents. Chang recounts how the pandemic affected his family as he has had to navigate caring for his mother after his father's death in 2006 – something that was complicated by the pandemic due to the distance of Texas and Michigan.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fcb92e78d4729fdd7eeb264a1e84670a"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_417444e4c1269964d5c7f11a0612f3e6"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kyle Chang is a Korean American adoptee who lives in Frisco, TX and works as a user experience designer.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_bd40f8d806db72f9049d0fd7ca081f4e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chau, Monyee</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_14</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021127</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Chau, Monyee" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Chau, Monyee</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_86ff5c9d36f371f050fc20990080f7f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on August 21, 2020. Examples of Monyee Chau's artwork is also included. </p><p>In this interview, Chau explains how COVID-19 impacted Chinatown residents, how her personal response to anti-Asian racism raised her political consciousness, and became the reason for her current cultural activism.  Chau talks at length about her work against gentrification and the ways in which crime, violence, and gentrification are critical issues that were brought into clear focus during COVID-19. Chau also discusses her artwork including a poster she donated to the A/P/A Voices Project that displays the message 'We're all built on resilience. We will Survive this too," which has been shared and posted in Chinatowns internationally. Chau also talks about her influences as an artist and describes the process behind a zine they created for the Wing Luke Museum about COVID-19. The zine features portraits of Chau's father and asks the question: "Will we be able to bounce back from this?" The zine was been used as a fundraiser for Wing Luke and has raised several thousand dollars for the Museum.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_159f935e05d45924680f7202e9084d74"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_87bb6a24a513bf4cc311357875bea1e0"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Monyee Chau is a Seattle-based contemporary Taiwanese and Chinese American artist. Chau is a resident of Seattle's International District and grew up in Seattle's Chinatown. Chau explores the journey of healing through decolonization and reconnecting with her roots and ancestors through a variety of mediums. She has shown and curated multiple shows at Cornish College of the Arts, Pilchuck Glass School, Wing Luke Museum, Bellevue Arts Museum, and various exhibitions throughout Seattle. Chau has been the recipient of multiple Pilchuck scholarships, Cornish's Art Merit scholarship, nominations to the Outstanding Student Achievement in Contemporary Sculpture, and the Corning award. </p><p>As of 2020, Chau was a member of several organizations calling for community policing and volunteers with a Community Night Watch to patrol the streets. These patrols were founded in honor on Don Chin, a community hero who lost his life protecting Chinatown.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_0cfbb2647e073f0ec9cc97523b4c1a55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chau, Sabrina Mon-Yee </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_15</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019530</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Chau, Sabrina Mon-Yee " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Chau, Sabrina Mon-Yee</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d3677f2392e9f694245e0c54e8ba58f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a poster titled "Resilience," which was a response to white nationalists stickers that had been appearing in Seattle's Chinatown International District as a fear tactic designed to intimidate the community; a comic titled "A Comic on Resiliency," which was made as part of a fundraiser for the Wing Luke Museum; a takeout  menu style zine on the history
of Chinese immigrants in America creating Chinatowns across the nation titled "Chinatowns In America - And The Racism That Built Them;" and a PowerPoint with other art made by Chau.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9141589a50368d6ca6d1fbebc6fd5c03" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chiu, Yucan</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_16</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021129</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Chiu, Yucan" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Chiu, Yucan</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_208d1cd67c59096d3a06ac5782959609"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Sarah Lin on July 22, 2020. In his interview, Yucan Chiu discusses grief, numbness, and disorientation at the start of the pandemic – especially as someone whose work relies on face-to-face interaction. Chiu also discusses the disproportionate impact of COVID-19 on the Black and Brown communities within the community he serves; how the pandemic and its impact raised theological questions and reflections; and the need for local human touch in the midst of COVID-19 and the disconnection it brought. Chiu talks about how he helped put together COVID-19 relief efforts with other leaders in New Brunswick, NJ and the need for caring leadership in times of crisis. Chiu also discusses the importance of faith partnerships; multifaith work and coordination in a pandemic setting; the resilience of the human spirit in the face of crisis; and the need for systemic transformation in the seasons ahead.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ffaef734fe52a014eed32b0adf72dcee"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_d5472b7c7ecf716ef7b649f7b442795c"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Reverend Dr. Yucan Chiu, D.Min. was born in Chicago to parents of Chinese descent. Chiu came to understand and experience Jesus in his teenage years while in California, and began to help create and lead faith communities in his early 20s. He holds bachelor degrees in Sociology and Biology from the University of California, San Diego; and graduate degrees in Theology, Urban Studies, and Missiology (M.Div, Talbot School of Theology, D.Min. Bakke Graduate University). Chiu has been married for 20 years to Dr. Yen-Yen Chiu, Ed.D. (an educator in the public schools) and has two teenage daughters. Chiu serves as a chaplain at Rutgers University, a trainer for City to City, and the Director of the Ethnos Network.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_98ede20538a8c9121eb6d378fb1c45ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chow, Yvonne</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_17</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021131</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Chow, Yvonne" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Chow, Yvonne</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4ad41a90815c68277dd949b20701dd3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Linda Kuo on August 30, 2021. In her interview, Yvonne Chow discusses how COVID-19 has impacted her ability to create choreography; the virtual shift for her dance company; and the challenge to stay connected with and be of service for the community when in-person events were limited. Chow also talks about Dance Mart, the free grocery, health services, and resources program offered by H+; and setting up a grocery delivery program for dancers during the pandemic.</p><p>Chow addresses racial tensions and reckonings with the racial divide and disconnection in the Hip Hop community during attacks against Asian Americans. She shares opportunities for connecting more deeply with Asian American women, selfcare, building solidarity, and her upcoming projects -- all as responses to anti-Asian racism during the pandemic. Chow further talks about her work with H+ and House of Chow; building communities; and forging relationships toward racial solidarity and dancer economic sustainability. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_1589b668e0587cc9ef9d46fd8302e833"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_efa961af9f8a14d95a110da0397a7ac2"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Yvonne Chow is a first-generation Chinese American woman from the Bay Area in California. As of 2021, she has been living in New York City for over a decade and is the Education Director for H+/ Hip Hop Dance Conservatory. She's also the founder of House of Chow, the Asian (American) division of H+.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_7234f490e8efe1d6c73775dfde7b06a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Choy, Catherine Ceniza</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_18</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021133</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Choy, Catherine Ceniza" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Choy, Catherine Ceniza</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3094d5b2c7757c7474d7fc6d7cabc11a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Rosario Joaquin on December 7, 2020. During the interview, Catherine Ceniza Choy begins by sharing a personal story about traveling in Europe during the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic and how she began to witness anti-Asian sentiment stem from fear of the virus. Upon returning to her home in California, Choy talks about the emotional toll of her trip to Europe; making the decision to lend her voice to the media as a historian and scholar in order to counter misinformation; and attempts to portray Asian-Americans in a more human light. She highlights many projects from the Filipino American community and examples of community care, including the Philippine Nurses Association of America's (PNAA) Heal Our Nurses campaign; Kanlungan; the Philippine Health Initiative for Research, Service, and Training (PHIRST); and This Filipino American Life.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_a6c09f918487fd332f796514d03873d1"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_e577d15cde9fb0ee211e20a4ee4bb792"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Catherine Ceniza Choy is the Professor of Ethnic Studies and an Associate Dean of the College of Letters &amp; Science's Division of Undergraduate Studies at the University of California, Berkeley. She is the author of several books on Asian American history, Filipino American studies, race, gender, and migration, including <emph render = "italic">Empire of Care: Nursing and Migration in Filipino American History</emph> (2003). At the time of this interview, Choy had completed 30 interviews since February 2020 and continued to bring light to the critical role Filipino American nurses play in the U.S. healthcare system.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_f12e7f3a10553c91c86b0e36b2e385a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dancers Unlimited </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_19</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019534</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2021" type="inclusive">2019, 2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Dancers Unlimited " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dancers Unlimited</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_cce432a6bdf4f1aacf498a32fe92e502"><head>Historical Note</head><p>Dancers Unlimited (DU) is a bi-coastal 501(c)3 nonprofit company based in New York City and Hawai'i. DU creates authentic MoveMeant narratives for community advancement through creative collaboration, community engagement, and social justice work. Established in 2009, the company has presented work in festivals and showings in Hawai'i, New York City, and Asia.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_fdd3469945ccc7ec0cc4894e340dfce5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This material includes two videos: "I'mMigration / Ku Kia'i Mauna" and "AAPI Community Discussion." </p><p>I'mMigration/Ku Kia'i Mauna was performed on September 10, 2019. The work explores the kuleana, or responsibility, of members of the Hawaiian community to decolonize by connecting with their heritage and building allyship to support Indigenous rights. This relates to the proposed controversial development of the Thirty Meter Telescope at Mauna Kea, which continued during the pandemic. This dance was performed by Dancers Unlimited NYC and Hawai'i dancers; was performed at the Arts at Mark's Garage in Honolulu, HI; and was part of the Small Plates Dance Festival. The videographer was Mark Feijão Millian.</p><p>The AAPI Community Discussion was recorded on May 30, 2021. It was hosted by Dancers Unlimited, Peridance, and the Mark Morris Dance Center for an Asian American Pacific Islander (AAPI) Solidarity fundraiser and community discussion. The discussion portion was moderated by Jessica Chen, the Director of JChen Project, and Yaya Yuan, the Director of Education and Mentoring Programs at APEX For Youth.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f50b99cfc3babbaa3d6edde6b30ea880" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dang, Cathy</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_20</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021135</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Dang, Cathy" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Dang, Cathy</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2407f544aa3a07ff7da5c20d60dc4e53"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Vivian Truong on July 14, 2020. In the interview, Cathy Dang discusses her personal experiences with pregnancy during the first several months of the pandemic. She also discusses how the government response to COVID-19 in Vietnam, where her parents live, was different from the response in the U.S.; her sister's experience losing their job in Hawai'i and sewing masks for healthcare workers; and the potential connections between unemployed people and essential workers.</p><p>Dang also discusses her participation in the Black Lives Matter (BLM) protests after the police killing of George Floyd in Minneapolis. She reflects on how the pandemic and uprisings have affected Crown Heights, NY, where she was living at the time of this interview. As the daughter of a small business owner, she offers her analysis on Asian immigrant responses to the uprisings and the movement to defund the police in New York City. Finally, Dang shares her hopes and concerns for the movement and her own family; and what she wants her future child to understand about the moment that they are being born into.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_81b134eb35d613150f6be08acee2b455"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_15919b149525d741eb6a7aa07cb21eb6"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Cathy Dang grew up in New York City and Los Angeles, CA. She has been a community and labor organizer for over fifteen years. She was the former director of CAAAV: Organizing Asian Communities. She is a Soros Equality Fellow and an advisor with the Center for Empowered Politics.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_4ce60f0bb892c215b2ed4815ecca8e9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Desis Rising Up &amp; Moving (DRUM) </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_21</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019536</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Desis Rising Up &amp; Moving (DRUM) " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Desis Rising Up &amp; Moving (DRUM)</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3fd01657d430ad49ece0b87dfd09f3e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a "Building Power &amp; Safety Through Solidarity" flyer.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_498ba5ae783fb654d5afd4e552a0c3ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diente, Xenia </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019537</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_ea2412449f90ba819fb0e702346788f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_22</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021137</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d44a845341eae670a975c833d1ea6ce9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on January 18, 2021. A flyer titled "Bayanihan Response to COVID-19 in the Northeast" is also included. In this interview, Xenia Diente shares her personal experience traveling in the Philippines when COVID-19 first started in March and her family's immigration history from the Philippines. Diente provides historical background around the labor exportation policies that resulted in large numbers of Filipino nurses immigrating to the U.S. -- her mother is a retired nurse and her entire family are health care workers impacted by the pandemic. </p><p>Diente talks about her new interest in Philippine history as a result of her community-based art practice. As a 2020 fellow with the Laundromat Project, Diente and her partner, Jaclyn, initially proposed a series of public art activations celebrating the Filipino diaspora in Queens, but quickly pivoted to a mutual aid project during the pandemic that sought to support the brick and mortar businesses of Little Manila. Diente discusses the geography of Queens; and talks in depth about the different languages and social make up of the Filipino community in Queens. The last half of the interview is spent talking about the Meal to Heal project, her participation in a mural created for frontline workers around the concept of 'Mabuhay' (a Filipino expression that means 'may you live'), and community efforts to rename a stretch of Roosevelt Avenue, 'Little Manila Street'.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_4cba7887e0fa2254537d96ba4f998322"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_11219c52c8de9b924b2c7c79ecf86b4c"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Xenia Diente is a Filipina and a Queens-based public art professional who works for the New York City Department of Design and Construction (DDC). Diente sits on the board of the Filipino American National History Society-Metro NY Chapter. She was a Laundromat Project Create Change Fellow when she and her partner Jaclyn Reyes developed "The Meal to Heal Initiative" in April 2020, in response to the COVID-19 crisis in New York City. Meal to Heal was a mutual aid project that paired Filipino restaurants in Queens with local hospitals and nursing homes, providing free meals to frontline health care workers. This initiative was created for the Laundromat Project, by Little Manila Queens Bayanihan Arts, in partnership with the National Alliance for Filipino Concerns USA North East Chapter and the Filipino American National Historical Society Metro NY Chapter.</p></bioghist></c></c><c id="aspace_72881b5efef875b870f2015afb250acc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eda, Haruki</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_23</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021140</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Eda, Haruki" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Eda, Haruki</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c0d313772739c5c1525ecc728800a348"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and audio files from an oral history interview conducted by Mi Hyun Yoon on March 15, 2021. In his interview, Haruki Eda speaks about his engagement with Nodutdol and Eclipse Rising; and how his experiences as an organizer have changed due to the pandemic. In particular, Eda took the pandemic as an opportunity to shift his thinking and refocus on what he actually wants to do with his life – he shifted his career aspirations from academia to urban forestry. Eda also talks about his family in Japan and teaching an Asian American studies class at a time when anti-Asian hatred and racism have increased.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_797762e8887b1f8ff6f4c590a852e59b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and audio files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_cf14d3e8c67a217b5fb8ad2d79a4ea5c"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Haruki Eda is a community organizer involved with NoDutDol for Korean Community Development and Eclipse Rising, both of which are  organizations for Zainichi Koreans, or postcolonial exiles of Korean descent in Japan. Eda identifies as Zainichi Korean and as of 2021, he was a PhD candidate in sociology at Rutgers University.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_dce31e964fb1520eaf6f7364b643e118" level="file"><did><unittitle>Emma</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_24</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021144</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Emma" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Emma</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b7472445a3ae691f9d2ee6e81b0fbbd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and audio files from an oral history interview conducted by Emma Callahan on September 13, 2021. In her interview, Emma talks about her experiences protesting during the Black Lives Matter (BLM) movement throughout the summer of 2020. She mentions the importance of getting involved and why she felt her participation was necessary. Emma also discusses a collective change in attitudes towards the protests by the end of the summer, specifically how as people's lives changed, in person protests were deprioritized. Emma reflects and questions the ways in which the George Floyd protests could have lasting impact on people's lives. </p><p>Emma addresses her own complicated feelings during the Stop Asian Hate movement in early 2021 and discusses finding community in a group of neighborhood and childhood friends who were primarily Asian women. At the same time, Emma expresses feeling a strange need to make a resounding statement, especially on social media, about the Stop Asian Hate movement. She was unsure of how to take ownership of Stop Asian American and Pacific Island (AAPI) Hate when an increase in anti-Asian violence was not something she had personally experienced. Emma discusses how her own identity as an Asian-American has evolved and changed over the past year, especially with the realization that she is seen as an Asian woman by her white peers. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c14d35229fee2ace66ba73d34e5fb1bd"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and audio files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_b8ec3ff195904985612e0e2b9356d87d"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Emma is a mixed-race Korean-American musician and artist from the Lower East Side of New York City.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_f7ad70506070f401a4281a6fe1e70b97" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fincher, Beverly Hong</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_25</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021150</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Fincher, Beverly Hong" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Fincher, Beverly Hong</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c85d6e11f728d3d7f3cd7f037bc505f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Diane Wong on December 11, 2020. A photograph of Beverly Hong Fincher is also included. The interview starts with Fincher discussing her career as a linguist and her first academic position; and her research, teaching, and lecturing on Chinese language and discourse analysis. Fincher goes on to discuss the intellectual life and community she was a part of in Washington D.C., where she lived before the pandemic, and feeling lonely and disconnected since moving back to New York City over the summer.</p><p>Throughout the interview, Fincher shares fond memories of visiting different places to give lectures. She recalls visiting Meridian House to give a talk and was gifted a silk jacket covered with a famous Chinese poetry, which she recited aloud. She also recalls a chance encounter with an ambassador on her way back from China, choosing to sit next to him on the shuttle bus to the airport, while advocating for anti-smoking laws to be passed in China. To her surprise, a few weeks later, she saw there was a nationwide law passed on smoking. She claims this moment to be one of her proudest accomplishments because it saved lives. Towards the end of the interview, Fincher discusses how difficult life has been for her in quarantine and how her mental health has suffered. Although she has found joy from visiting Manhattan Chinatown, her visits are infrequent. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_c4cb9b7f0167707dc2d379a75a8ac064"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_d8c87011bb80d001f60b756546654138"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Beverly Hong Fincher is a linguist and academic.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_e73cdd410e4fbcda707bfc27f28fc234" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fu, Lisa</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_26</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021159</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Fu, Lisa" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Fu, Lisa</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1df546f4e2c9eef0fa95d9e32fcd249b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Preeti Sharma on July 29, 2020. The bulk of the interview focuses on the pandemic's impact on the predominantly Vietnamese staffed and owned nail salon sector in California, especially in terms of statewide closing and reopening policies. The interview opens with Lisa Fu's initial experiences in the pandemic, detailing her personal schedule and quarantine routine as a mother of two children with immunosuppressed family members at home. Fu also discusses details about how the first shut down impacted workers and independent contractors, including access barriers to unemployment insurance and loans for business owners. </p><p>Fu shares the Healthy Nail Salon Collaborative's decision to raise emergency aid and create a Nail Salon Community Care Fund. She also highlights the Collaborative's response to the Governor's false claim that the first wave of COVID-19 in California originated from nail salons. Fu considers the challenges of what reopening nail salons in California could look like, particularly given the different speeds of reopening across the country, across the state, and the damage of the Governor's false claim; and the types of  guidelines and advocacy the Collaborative could offer these businesses. Fu discusses how the Collaborative acted in solidarity with the Black Lives Matter (BLM) protests. She closes the interview considering aspects of anti-Asian racism in salons and the ongoing toxic chemicals and respiratory issues in salons that have been exacerbated by COVID-19.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_131f88db77d195b1c2055718916a79f3"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_93ee625ba66620c7c6636dac5b24f214"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Lisa Fu was born and raised in Los Angeles, CA. She received her Master of Public Health in 2003 and was previously the National Organizing Director for the National Asian Pacific American Women's Forum. As of 2020, she lives in Los Angeles and is the Executive Director of the California Healthy Nail Salon Collaborative.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_80a68e45f59802e83709dc3f8bf8045f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gao, Cynthia "Cindy"</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_27</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021163</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Gao, Cynthia &quot;Cindy&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Gao, Cynthia "Cindy"</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f04f7a1fe278555b3a77767af6f6de78"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on September 15, 2020. In her interview, Cynthia Gao talks extensively about the neighborhood of Flatbush in Brooklyn, which is a largely Caribbean community with a sizable population of healthcare workers. She describes her experiences providing mutual aid through Equality for Flatbush and delivering food during the pandemic. Gao reflects on the ways the lock-down impacted her and covers a number of topics from policing and community safety; her role in the Black Lives Matter (BLM) protests; anti-Asian racism; and the challenges of organizing radical mutual aid efforts, which she envisions can be a way to build consciousness and community power.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_099485286dcdeb1c7a5fd2186e27bb54"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_65c3aa419820ab82b11d17da0b62b275"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Cynthia Gao is Chinese American and as of 2020, a PhD student in the Department of Social and Cultural Analysis at New York University. She is researching the influence of Revolutionary Asia on Communist and radical movements in the United States. Cynthia was a volunteer with A/P/A Voices: A COVID 19 Public Memory Project during the summer of 2020, as part of her work with the Center for Global Asia. Until recently, Cindy was a member of Equality for Flatbush, a Black/person of color led grassroots organization in Brooklyn that fights for affordable housing and mobilizes against gentrification
and displacement in Flatbush, East Flatbush, and Brooklyn-wide.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_597fb0a5ab4179ad5871698443013e3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Garcia-Dia, Mary Joy</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_28</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021165</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Garcia-Dia, Mary Joy" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Garcia-Dia, Mary Joy</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9aa6bbf3ab05eb92ad22bca587042171"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Rosario Joaquin on December 4, 2020. During the interview, Mary Joy Garcia-Dia discusses the successes and challenges she encountered in organizing the Philippine Nurses Association of America's (PNAA) response to COVID-19, including her promotion to President in June 2020 as the virus quickly showed a disproportionate impact on her local, national, and international community of Filipino nurses. Garcia-Dia emphasizes the value of resilience, the topic of her doctoral research, and the theme of her PNAA presidency. She discusses various PNAA initiatives, including the organization's COVID-19 Task Force, the Heal Our Nurses campaign, and their resilience training program. Garcia-Dia also shares personal reflections of how the COVID-19 pandemic compares to her experiences working as a bedside nurse during the 1990s HIV crisis. Finally, Garcia-Dia discusses the importance of cross-cultural solidarity and disaggregated health data as we imagine a post-COVID-19 world and seek to not repeat the tragedies of this virus.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_4251eba1fe31d8f94e35b6430c67dd25"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_53f9fbf04d062fa387ba867d5cc50b34"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Mary Joy Garcia-Dia is the Program Director of Nursing Informatics at NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital. She is the former President-Elect and President of the Philippine Nurses Association of America, Inc. (PNAA), one of the oldest and largest non-profit professional nursing organizations in the country.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_ed365db8efbd3a83d0f547945c545354" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gina </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019544</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_95efc7a8838190d09ef484ac881eea58" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_29</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021169</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e960baacc1926a19eb4aa450dfcfc8d2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include video files from an oral history interview conducted by Mi Hyun Yoon on March 12, 2021. Photographs of Gina and her family are also included. The interview begins with Gina discussing the rise of Asian hate crimes. She mentions that even before the pandemic, in January and February of 2020, people in her hometown area of Dallas Fort Worth, TX would avoid her or give her strange looks as an Asian-presenting woman. </p><p>On a personal level, the pandemic has changed many aspects of Gina's personal life. She realized many of her friends were harboring their own prejudices and would not take radical action to combat racism in their everyday lives. Gina became more involved in radical social justice organizing and discourse online through Twitter and Reddit. She explains that online platforms have helped her connect with communities across the world and stay informed about breaking news. In addition to social media, Gina has participated in various radical-left podcasts over the pandemic including Mango Press or Escape from Plan A.</p><p>Gina explains how the racially charged violence of the pandemic angered and radicalized her. It also revealed her complicated feelings about the narrative of Asian-Americans in anti-Black racism. As the daughter of a Korean store owner, Gina expresses discomfort about how Asians are often excluded or othered in communities of color or constantly othered as non-American. Gina feels incidents like the L.A. Riots often flatten and simplify narratives that place blame on Asian communities. Gina also expresses frustration that small businesses of working-class store owners, like her mother, were targeted during the Black Lives Matter protests in 2020. Gina questions a desire to go back to a "normal" post-pandemic world and questions what normal means in a post-pandemic world. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_791996327bdd58bb001db4bd145382ca"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_992079ce3319dd222a1f04c41ae9ba90"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Gina is a multi-racial Asian-American woman living and working in the southern United States. Born in South Korea on a military base, she grew up in Southern Texas and is of a Tejana and Korean descent. As of 2020, Gina works for a health insurance company.</p></bioghist></c></c><c id="aspace_95da8e93f2dc5b2421a92d297e54b1f0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hoa, Vincent</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_30</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021173</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Hoa, Vincent" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Hoa, Vincent</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_005d9b6b400321a52cf9ac1fac986f07"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Cynthia Gao on June 18, 2020. The first part of the interview concerns Vincent Hoa's experience as a city gardener whose position was declared "essential" during the first lockdown of the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020. He describes the confusion and lack of consistent direction given by his immediate supervisors, union representatives, and the city before and after the lockdown. According to Hoa, safety precautions varied and were inconsistent and there was a lack of personal protective equipment (PPE) available for workers. </p><p>Hoa discusses contracting COVID-19, his belief he contracted the virus through working, and the process of accessing a test in the early months of the pandemic. Attitudes towards COVID-19 among parks workers is discussed, as are conspiracy theories, beliefs about its origins in China, and questions about why parks workers were considered essential. Hoa describes some of the
emotional and psychological impacts of working through the pandemic and getting sick; the kinds of work he performed; and the kinds of safety precautions he took.</p><p>In the second part of the interview Hoa discusses the Black Lives Matter (BLM) protests in New York City and nationally. He describes feeling moved by the protests, as a person of color, and applauded the protests for both having widespread support and remaining centered around the particular experiences of Black people. Hoa talks about how the protests opened up conversations in his personal life and among coworkers; and how he connects the protests with the backdrop of inequalities produced by the pandemic lockdown. Hoa talks about the feeling of seeing Confederate statues torn down in his hometown of Richmond, Virginia and connects local police abolitionist movements with an international analysis of imperialism. Hoa also discusses paying rent during the pandemic and rent strikes in New York City. The interview concludes with Hoa discussing changes in their emotional experiences of the pandemic, from early despair to renewed hope because of the protests.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_8640dd6f0c0d588adba3180a87f6f20d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_a4c51034dc22c9cfc811d33863ea7d98"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>"Vincent Hoa" (pseudonym) was born and raised in Richmond, VA and has lived in New York City since 2015. His parents are refugees from Vietnam. Hoa is a gardener with the New York City Parks Department and works in the borough of Brooklyn. Hoa was asked to participate in the A/P/A Voices project because of his experience as an essential worker and city employee during the COVID-19 lockdown in New York City.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_96484951c3ac1ae473766ebcf5662979" level="file"><did><unittitle>Huynh, Hoai-An Melody </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_31</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019546</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Huynh, Hoai-An Melody " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Huynh, Hoai-An Melody</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a18152b94a81a9cb07d7388c33397e25"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include Huynh's drawing, "Mani-curing the Hate," and an explanation of the piece.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7458a0f946b4515c7b90678bdbd81072" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jason</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019548</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_e8efe48675760620838053f12959e736" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_33</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021185</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fec05eebc340a71aae62e4be4f31a1d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include video files from an oral history interview conducted by Vivian Truong on August 11, 2020. In his interview, Jason discusses working in the Emergency Department at a hospital in Houston, TX in March 2020 when COVID-19 cases began to rise in the United States; and the lack of proper precautions and personal protective equipment (PPE) for healthcare workers, especially in the early months of the pandemic. Jason reflects on the confusion between varying COVID-19 protocols in the different hospitals where he worked and the need for nurses to advocate for their own health as well as their patients'.</p><p>Jason traveled to work in New York City  for twelve weeks from April to July 2020, as cases began to plateau following the height of the first wave. He lived in Chinatown while working in New York City and describes how the neighborhood had come to a standstill before slowly reopening during the summer. After New York City, Jason traveled to another assignment in Albuquerque, NM. He describes his experience traveling during the pandemic and encountering people who did not believe in the severity of the pandemic. The interview ends with Jason's concerns that the full effects of the pandemic have not yet been realized and his hopes for lessons learned for the future.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_673959696a4a8bd9149ccaa1cc8e3ffc"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_ce3e45dcef743a660a54d230076998dd"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Jason is a traveling nurse and a former community organizer. He was born in New York and raised in South Florida. Jason was working in the Emergency Department at a hospital in Houston, TX in March 2020 when COVID-19 cases began to rise in the United States.</p></bioghist></c></c><c id="aspace_978af41a3d6e41fe5c5751e35eda2b0e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jennifer</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_34</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021189</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Jennifer" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jennifer</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a00471a3be3a8b1b4f39453a74ceeaf8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Ronak Gandhi on February 25, 2021. During the interview, Jennifer talks about her experience during the pandemic, her family background, and her parents' undocumented status. Jennifer expresses a great sense of urgency and suppresses anger about the treatment her parents face; and the "invisibility" of undocumented workers, their workplace oppression, and their troubled relationship with the government. Jennifer describes how completing unemployment paperwork for her family occupied a large space in her mind, particularly since her parents could not fill it out themselves as they do not speak English. The interview also discusses Jennifer's life as a student during three distinct phases: the spring semester post-COVID-19, the summer, and the fall return to campus.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_602585e14156a7bd24fe8f58fd5039bc"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_5a537866a94bf894644226829d7b22ec"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Jennifer is from Queens, NY and grew up in a predominantly Black, Indigenous, and People of Color (BIPOC) working class neighborhood. She studied sociology at Yale University with a focus on ethnicity, race, and migration.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_1938d927d2cb7575ab10ca9a5f4ee8c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jeung, Russell</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_35</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021191</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Jeung, Russell" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Jeung, Russell</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_344a515222d7dbd927a3216d7ac0abf4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Diane Wong on December 18, 2020. The interview began with Russell Jeung talking about being in the Bay Area and contextualizing the present moment within longer Asian American histories. Jeung talks about his involvement as one of the founders of Stop Asian American Pacific Islander (AAPI) Hate, a web-based project that logs occurrences of hate crimes against Asian Americans. Jeung talks about both new and old resistance tactics including the use of social media to combat misinformation and bullying in schools. Over the summer, he worked with a group of over a hundred youths from across the country on an anti-bullying school campaign that involved the leveraging of social media and outreach to well-known YouTubers and international celebrities like Jeremy Lin.</p><p>Jeung also discusses the involvement of South Asian youths and organizers in combating anti-Asian hate in the wake of COVID-19. The group applied strategies and knowledge gained post-9/11, in an attempt to support documenting anti-Asian hate in the present moment. Jeung also discusses how disproportionately Asian Americans have been impacted by the pandemic in other ways from access to health care, language assistance, and small business closures. The interview ends with Jeung sharing his vision for a justice-oriented vision for the future where Asian Americans are working closely with other communities of color specifically around issues of restorative justice and transformation.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_98cd2bc53f6f6cd331e0528f3a2f9513"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_6fb823df1e91cb4e6dea51750bcf5d4a"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Russell Jeung is a co-founder of Stop Asian American Pacific Islander (AAPI) Hate, a web-based project that logs occurrences of hate crimes against Asian Americans. The project was born out of a need to document hate-crimes directed towards Asian Americans and to challenge the false narrative President Trump had been advocating that Chinese Americans are the reason for the pandemic. As of December 2020, the project has since documented over 3,000 incidents of anti-Asian hate with Asian American women being disproportionately impacted. The project made national and local policy impacts by pushing for accountability through legislation, but also structural changes that address the roots of racism.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_19ec936c686ca72b2b04d98810ef64d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Keo, Mike</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_36</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021195</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Keo, Mike" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Keo, Mike</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f0b061aac7c983c9ec29699f21727c2e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on October 20, 2020. In his interview, Mike Keo talks extensively about the rise of anti-Asian racism during the COVID-19 lockdown; references the historical roots of discrimination against Asians; shares his personal experiences with discrimination; and the impact of the virus on his career and family. Keo discusses the online platform he has created, along with his team of volunteers and educators, to address the problems of anti-Asian racism through a media campaign; films and posters; a free downloadable Wellness Toolkit; educational materials for students that include a coloring book honoring Asian American community leaders; and a curriculum about Asian American history. Keo explains how by working on a local level, he has worked to 'stop hate' by partnering with schools and local leaders to develop projects that foster understanding and community building. The interview concludes with Keo discussing his #IAmNotAVirus online campaign, which was fueled by photographs he shot in his studio.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5e9031d663f77a203eae6aa39f261517"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_3471f95ac684dc9100b380794ada21c3"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Mike Keo is a Cambodian American wedding photographer and founder of the #IAmNotAVirus campaign, which was launched in response to the surge of Anti-Asian racism during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_80d637a2d0d8c400092f498a5f251d72" level="file"><did><unittitle>Khmer Girls in Action (KGA) </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019552</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2022" type="inclusive">2020-2022</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_0196f169baf2250d681024d18f08e2af"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Khmer Girls in Action is a Long Beach, CA-based youth organization acting in collaboration with the #WeCanDoThis campaign, a federal Department of Health and Human Services COVID-19 public education campaign.</p></bioghist><c id="aspace_6b7d915d1829e99d2f7d4f048b0664c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paper Files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019780</unitid><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_668001ba4353f4bd422018f1569792d6" label="Mixed Materials [31142067162605]" type="Box">Shared Tamiment 189</container><container id="aspace_01f62fdbb651d1f4d6137fa05be0c6e1" parent="aspace_668001ba4353f4bd422018f1569792d6" type="Folder">4-5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_54bb117b0161aa00d9cce7c15f0578ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a set of original postcards, some of which include updated information on COVID-19 vaccines; a brochure about the organization; information about the #WeCanDoThis initiative as it relates to outreaching to Asian American, Pacific Islander, and Native Hawaiian (AAPINH) communities; and a few branded stickers.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_eefd54845dddca530d12ed150d20ee4e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files
</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_37</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019781</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files&#10;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f0ca7c46d4b60a2c1e944c77978bfc1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include digital copies of the paper materials. There are also two videos produced to promote the #WeCanDoThis initiative, while also amplifying the perspectives of community members Keomoney Norn and Jocelyn Ly.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_82f248115315bf0650d1022b0a5a7c7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Khurana, Sarita </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_38</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019553</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Khurana, Sarita " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Khurana, Sarita</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_4058cd814b84039ef8c5fbd223a350a6"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Sarita Khurana is a Brooklyn-based director, producer, and writer whose work focuses on South Asian stories and female subjectivities.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_958e515271703b7e1594bbdd62478b19"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include Khurana's short film, <emph render = "italic">Home, Delivered</emph>, which was commissioned by the Asian American Documentary Network as part of their COVID-19 storytelling series.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_64bc8632b8b231e5b01e994d810c26a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kim, Ha Kyung</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_39</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021200</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Kim, Ha Kyung" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Kim, Ha Kyung</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_91b032831bfc49101a88f96977227959"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Mi Hyun Yoon on May 23, 2021. In her interview, Ha Kyung Kim talks about the lack of diversity where she lives, which has a 70 percent white population, and mentions that most of the Asian population in her community come from scientists and engineers who work for the military. Kim discusses her job, which she started in January 2020, and the impact the pandemic has had on it. Kim also mentions how her home gym has helped her through the pandemic and how, as a federal employee, she has not been able to actively participate in protests. For Asian American Pacific Islander Heritage month in 2021, Kim was recruited to be involved with program planning and she recounts how it was both a positive and negative experience.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6d4872a953b008240caf3ffa700e947f"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room only once permission has been obtained from Ha Kyung Kim.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_5e64e23ff195bca3de2260a0a58acb5e"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Ha Kyung Kim is a Korean American woman who lives in Bel Air, MD and works as a HR specialist for the U.S. Army.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_bc57ff43fbfea2a640727bcec4aae2a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kim, Patricia</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_40</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019555</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Kim, Patricia" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Kim, Patricia</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a0aec987650b781bcc6b737b2e22ce1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include the video "How to Start Talking to Your Korean Family about Black Lives Matter," which is in English with Korean subtitles.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_a890a8c54f863708afed21b7bdababbe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kochiyama, Eddie </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_41</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019556</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Kochiyama, Eddie " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Kochiyama, Eddie</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_df96d4e076590aebf4f442356fd10cba"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include Eddie Kochiyama's photographs of murals and graffiti in Oakland, CA; and Kochiyama's reflections on George Floyd's death.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_66fd5146c2c6d7a8b1ccfac36c2b8eae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kuo, Linda</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_42</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021206</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Kuo, Linda" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Kuo, Linda</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a74895179afd9aaad8114752710567c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on April 29, 2021. In this interview Linda Kuo talks about the impact of the pandemic on her family and her dance company, Dancers Unlimited. As a Taiwanese born resident of Brooklyn, NY, she shares her thoughts about cultural appropriation and the role of traditional dance in Pacific Islander communities; her observations of anti-Asian racism in Hawai'i; and the ways she has coped with the isolation and mental health issues she experienced during this past year under lock-down. In the interview, Kuo shares an open rehearsal of her new project, <emph render = "italic">Edible Tales</emph>, a dance about Taro, a food staple in the Pacific Islands. Taro is presented as symbol of the resilience of Indigenous people. At the end of the interview, Linda speaks about shifting towards healing.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_dada9128919b02a7671ef3ab9d5ef273"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_a62752f287b233ff383319a90b2da894"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Linda Kuo is a co-founder, director, and choreographer of Dancers Unlimited (DU), a bicoastal dance company based in New York City and Hawai'i. Born in Taiwan and raised in Hawai'i, Kuo is shaped by cultural diversity and performing arts including dancing the Hula. As a choreographer, Kuo's work has been presented on stages in New York City, Hawai'i, and abroad. Kuo's Hawaiian upbringing is influential in her artistry and creative approach. Dancing the Hula helped cement her belief in dance as the backbone of cultural identity and resilience. Her choreography addresses social and cultural issues, while fusing contemporary, street, and cultural dances with a strong emphasis on authentic and diverse storytelling; and her creative vision emphasizes community engagement as part of her mission. Kuo has trained in the BOLD (Builders, Organizer, and Leaders through Dance) program by the Urban Bush Women and studied at its Summer Leadership Institute at New York University. She also volunteered to conduct interviews for the A/P/A Voices project.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_526ca6876c70501c1ac0eb55c3dc706f" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render = "italic">Labor Notes</emph></unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_43</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019558</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2021" type="inclusive">2020-2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Labor Notes " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Labor Notes</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3ff8eac84aabcd28ef2e1fc44f3af7d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include an interview with Annie Tan about growing anti-Asian racism with the emergence of the COVID-19 pandemic and an article by Saurav Sarkar about the same topic.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f9a381b2193d32ba80aacfda6d47b738" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lam, Kevin</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_44</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021212</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2021" type="inclusive">2020-2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Lam, Kevin" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Lam, Kevin</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ff1f58aa1d1f0d1c5cdd8ada184945f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include transcript, audio files, and video files from two oral history interviews conducted by Vivian Truong on July 24, 2020 and March 1, 2021. In the July 24, 2020 interview, Kevin Lam discusses his personal experience of the pandemic, the Asian American Resource Workshop's (AARW) responses to the multiple crises facing its membership base, and the organization's shift to remote work during the early days of the pandemic. Whereas AARW primarily focused on community organizing in the years leading up to the outbreak of COVID-19, responding to the pandemic meant an increased focus on direct service, including raising funds for impacted community members and coordinating grocery deliveries. The organization also had to shift its ongoing campaigns on gentrification, deportation, and policing to address the domino-like effects of the pandemic on each of these issue areas.</p><p>Lam expresses his concern for his parents, who are essential workers in the manufacturing industry, and among the few Asian families in their area during a time of rising anti-Asian sentiment. As refugees of the Vietnam War, Lam's parents approached both the public health threat of the pandemic and the potential for anti-Asian violence as yet another period of crisis through which to survive. As a form of personally coping with the isolation of stay-at-home directives, Lam nourished his connection to his Vietnamese and Laotian identity through cooking. Lam discusses how Black Lives Matter (BLM) reinforced the necessity of intergenerationally engaging Asian immigrant members in solidarity work with Black communities, particularly in relation to defunding the police and decarceration. The interview ends with Kevin's reflection on the sustainability of movement-building through and beyond the era of COVID-19.</p><p>In the March 1, 2021 interview, Lam discusses a deportation case AARW worked on prior to the pandemic involving a Cambodian American. Lam shares how anti-deportation organizers are approaching the immigration policies of the new presidential administration and explains how AARW continues to coordinate mutual aid efforts, including culturally relevant grocery deliveries to Asian immigrant communities in Boston. While the organization did not consider direct service provision to be a main part of their work prior to COVID-19, the pandemic helped change AARW's understanding of the relationship between direct service and community organizing. The interview also includes reflections after a year of the pandemic where Lam shares the need for healing and mental health care to address the traumatic effects of the pandemic that would persist after its "end."</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_1bf1974314c711e6c6cc7d7bc3e942df"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_3ef1f069bbd5a6ff583a794e792197d7"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kevin Lam grew up in Poughkeepsie, NY and his parents are Laotian and Vietnamese refugees. As of 2020, he was the Organizing Director of the Asian American Resource Workshop (AARW), founded in 1979. AARW works with Asian and Asian American communities in the greater Boston area, including Vietnamese residents of the neighborhood of Dorchester. The organization focuses their community organizing on issues including gentrification, deportation, and policing.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_035e0d5647f6eb785a06f45c79c1ba2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Latif, Khalid</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_45</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021214</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Latif, Khalid" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Latif, Khalid</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e83f289ba42b9297451302122f74a0c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Zaim Alam on April 13, 2021. In this interview, Khalid Latif talks about his efforts early in the pandemic to immediately fundraise and guide resources to students, first responders, and community members -- often in multi-family households in the outskirts of the boroughs -- who were unable to leave the city or shelter-in-place. He spoke in great detail about his experience living in Lower Manhattan, on New York University's campus, and feeling empowered by how much his local community in New York and in the Muslim community at large stepped up to serve, however they could, during this crisis.</p><p>Towards the end of the interview, Latif recounts a moving story about his children, who he says in many ways taught him more than he taught them. In Muslim tradition, children are often taught how to make "dua," or supplications to God at the end of their prayers, often asking God for health, guidance, protection. As ambulances became the soundtrack of New York City in the worst days of the pandemic, Latif's son would lead his younger sibling in prayer oriented toward the ambulances, asking God to protect and have mercy on everyone inside. When the George Floyd protests erupted, Latif's son did the same, praying for the protestors and everyone else involved in the streets below.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_220a227c24efccc5cd4b87c8a7496c89"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_71eaba33517e2679951bc26dec365afe"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Khalid Latif is the Executive Director and Imam for the Islamic Center at New York University. In 2005, Latif was appointed the first Muslim chaplain at NYU and in 2007, his position was fully institutionalized. While at NYU, Latif has initiated his vision for a pluralistic American Muslim community rooted on campus and reaching out to the city.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_18cf86f513250f03512e8ea914df339e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lee, Patrick </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019561</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_1560ab47c01865009c715153ae7f85c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_46</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021220</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f4f6564f91be275c728b2f5899a414ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include audio files and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Minju Bae on July 24, 2020. In this interview, Patrick Lee talks about the COVID-19 pandemic, how it affected his filmmaking, what the pandemic's impacts were at queer clubs in Seoul, and how he understood what was unraveling in the U.S. from abroad.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_90362b80939cb216148b3cd5eba29c6a"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The audio files and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections or remotely. For remote access, a time sensitive online web link will be provided.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_1e322b484617a41c861d5eed7499513e"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Patrick Lee is a queer Korean American documentary filmmaker, writer, and organizer living in New York. At the beginning of the pandemic, he had been living in Seoul, Korea, working on a documentary film.</p></bioghist></c></c><c id="aspace_b339e4633fc5040944b5ee26dc2003b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Leong, Russell C. </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_47</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021222</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Leong, Russell C. " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Leong, Russell C.</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_461fdf8762a0365db578c39ef10cbcb1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on August 5, 2020. Artwork, poetry, and photographs are also included that illustrate the emotional impact of sheltering in place during COVID-19.</p><p>In his interview, Russell Leong connects his experiences with the SARS virus, for which he was quarantined while in Hong Kong in March 2003, to the COVID-19 pandemic. As a gay Asian man, he also reflects on the AIDS virus and his work volunteering for the A/P/A Intervention Team, working with Chinese immigrants who had AIDS. Leong talks about the ways class and race have contributed to the impact of the virus. He makes connections between the Black Lives Matter slogan of "I Can't Breathe" with the devastating and life-ending symptoms of COVID-19. He also speaks at length about racial justice movements and his Buddhist practice. Later in the interview, Leong shares a PowerPoint containing drawings he has donated to the A/P/A Voices Project and talks about the creative process behind this work. The interview concludes with Leong reading a poem he wrote about COVID-19.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_860ce2d9dff2c95c9d3e819f89c63271"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_95fb9f4e5ed2262d542997f2c8fdf4b1"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Russell Charles Leong is an academic editor, professor, writer, poet, practicing Buddhist, Asian American activist, and an artist. He was an editor of  <emph render="italic">Amerasia Journal </emph> from 1977–2010; and an adjunct professor of English and Asian-American studies at University of California, Los Angeles. Leong serves as senior editor for international projects including the <emph render="italic">CUNY Forum</emph>, a quarterly journal published by the Asian American and Asian Research Institute (AARI) at the City University of New York.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_31f86a83bbe5098df61e1ec5f349b5a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Liang, Kathy </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_48</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019563</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Liang, Kathy " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Liang, Kathy</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca360c7b249b94eab6f843f1d2c85e70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include two drawings titled "You're not like FROM China" and "Community Work;" and explanations of these drawings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_c40b970852a54c33a38babb795feb4af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Liu, Chelsea and Dominique Xi</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_49</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019564</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2022">2022</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Liu, Chelsea and Dominique Xi" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Liu, Chelsea and Dominique Xi</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed939dd6c3b2825d5a9c781631ce941e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, classroom presentation, and videos from an oral history interview conducted by Chelsea Liu on March 29, 2022 and April 23, 2022 with Dominque Xi on the subject of Asian American theatre arts activism during the COVID-19 pandemic. This oral history interview was not recorded as part of the A/P/A Voices: A COVID-19 Public Memory Project, but rather, was filmed as part of Liu's academic coursework.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_7946edd8baffe3106edefeefd71eebf5"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Chelsea Shi-Chao Liu is a graduate of Sarah Lawrence College and Claremont University's MA program in History &amp; Archival Studies. She is an archivist and researcher with interests in Asian American studies; gender and sexuality; and visual culture.</p></bioghist><bioghist id="aspace_85238ccfa042711c7b6a18533e3f491f"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Dominique Xi is a graduate of Sarah Lawrence College and a multi-hyphenate filmmaker based in New York. Xi wrote and directed the short film, <emph render="italic">A Hero's Journey</emph>; executive produced the web series, <emph render="italic">STUCK</emph>; and acted in the Crossway's Theatre production of "COVID Crime."</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_d34cf5408ed183a71936255e2acf8e9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ma, Jerry </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_50</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019565</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Ma, Jerry " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Ma, Jerry</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_1289c88b410da30b1c0606ea9da892ea"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Jerry Ma is a graphic artist and founder of the indie comics studio Epic Proportions. With Keith Chow, Parry Shen, and Jeff Yang, he is a co-author of <emph render = "italic">Shattered: The Asian American Comics Anthology </emph> and a co-editor of <emph render = "italic">Secret Identities: The Asian American Superhero Anthology</emph>, both published by The New Press.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_28ba2b03233e3392a215292d2b89425e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include Jerry Ma's painting "I Am Asian American," which was a response to anti-Asian sentiments that had been growing during the pandemic. The painting highlights a variety of everyday people that were donating face shields, masks, food, time, and energy to the Asian American community. Those who work in the medical field are colored in blue, those who work in the food industry are colored red, and those who just wanted to help in their own unique way are colored in purple.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b2d8e6a0c1bdded9cc3d117ee215eded" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mauna Kea Protectors at the University of Hawai'i </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_51</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019566</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Mauna Kea Protectors at the University of Hawai’i " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Mauna Kea Protectors at the University of Hawai'i</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ac5a51ed61953d41839fb5ef2aedfb17"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a letter dated June 14, 2020 from the Mauna Kea Protectors at the University of Hawai'i to the university administration, renewing its support for the Kia'i who are defending Mauna Kea from Thirty-Meter Telescope development -- just one month short of the one-year anniversary of sustained community resistance to the ongoing desecration on Mauna Kea. This support continued amidst the COVID-19 shelter in place orders and the demonstrations for the Black, Indigenous, and People of Color (BIPOC) community.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_749e279adee81d9df55e2b63e173005e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mock, Emily</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_52</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021226</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Mock, Emily" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Mock, Emily</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a97cc2151c415793f1134f7ff14f5c3a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on August 28, 2020. Photographs of Emily Mock and her work with CAAAV: Organizing Asian Communities are also included. </p><p>In this interview, Mock discusses her work as the Chinatown Tenant Union (CTU) Membership Organizer for CAAAV: Organizing Asian Communities. She shares images of tenants organizing before and after the COVID-19 lock-down; and the challenges they met mobilizing around Cancel Rent campaigns and Rent Strikes during the pandemic. Mock talks about the impact of COVID-19 on residents of Chinatown; language justice issues; the use of graphic aids and art in the form of banner drops; and social messaging during social distancing protocols. Prior to the lock down, Mock explains how CTU organizing committee members met every Sunday and held office hours where residents could bring in their leases or get legal assistance; and members also engaged in door knocking twice a week to check on residents. After the lock down, these systems disappeared and the tenants began using WeChat to communicate with each other. Mock discusses the ways tenants have adapted to social distancing and shares the difficulty, and necessity, of talking to Chinese tenants about anti-black racism and Black Lives Matter (BLM). The interview concludes with Mock reflecting on ways small businesses and restaurants in Chinatown have been heavily impacted and forced to close during the pandemic.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_34facf5ccbacb846dbce664742971d01"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_54f823a8ab82467e061c3e392d8b0564"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Emily Mock is an artist, educator, and community organizer. Mock is originally from San Francisco, CA and as of 2020, lives in New York City. As of 2020, she is the Chinatown Tenants Union (CTU) Membership Organizer at CAAAV: Organizing Asian Communities; and has created community arts education and public programming as the Center for Neighborhood Leadership Community Organizing Apprentice at The Laundromat Project. She has facilitated in English and Mandarin with all ages in schools, parks, museums, and organizing spaces. Emily is also a member of the Chinatown Art Brigade.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_8d57e8d14a9d575333c5c5524587ec2a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Morimoto, Risa</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_53</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019568</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Morimoto, Risa" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Morimoto, Risa</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_03fd41b9a6e85b0d3bd700eda9130e54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a video of Risa Morimoto discussing her father, Hisanori Morimoto, and his death from COVID-19 on April 23, 2020 while living in a nursing home. This was a YouTube video on Morimoto's website, www.ThisIsModernAging.com, which was published on May 7, 2020.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_70d0d330f0c48611326aac964c8f4cf8"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Risa Morimoto is the founder and CEO of www.ThisIsModernAging.com.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_c00ed29a3194a285d8bf8cdfb4a4789f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Morrar, Maisa</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_54</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021230</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Morrar, Maisa" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Morrar, Maisa</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_200d8b952ab9b304e071c66830a6c014"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Loubna Qutami on January 14, 2021. In this interview, Maisa Morrar addresses the pandemic from the perspective of a first responder and discusses the challenges first responders have been experiencing since the beginning of the pandemic. Next, Morrar discusses the historical, racial, and economic inequities that have made certain communities -- particularly Black communities -- more vulnerable and disenfranchised during the pandemic. Morrar illustrates that though the pandemic has resulted in crises of paramount proportions, it also posits new opportunities to envision alternative visions and strategies for health, wellness, and medicine. Morrar examines the work she has done as part of the Oakland Power Project, which works to create and offer resources to the community on alternatives to having to call the police; and mechanisms to develop community-based emergency response that do not further criminalize mental health and disability. Morrar also discusses the struggle Arab-American communities have faced in acquiring relevant data and resources as a result of their census-less status both prior and during the pandemic. Finally, Morrar discusses how the pandemic has posed serious struggles in places like Palestine where people continue to live under a military occupation.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_966fbc9e2f318d448c2edde8efe90cfd"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_85d551ada390a89be74d58d4a24c90fb"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Maisa Morrar is a physician assistant in Urgent Care and Family Medicine in Oakland, CA. Morrar is also active with the Palestinian Youth Movement, the Palestinian Feminist Collective, and Critical Resistance's Oakland Power Project.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_a0be00ad3dd9f7650527a9598e253635" level="file"><did><unittitle>Na, Taiyo</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_55</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019570</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2021" type="inclusive">2020-2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Na, Taiyo" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Na, Taiyo</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7eec57737dc3b687f9e5d841b5cfe72b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include Taiyo Na's poem "Weeks in the Womb" and an audio recording of the poem; an essay "Outlive Us All" by Na; and song lyrics, production information, and a video for the song "We Belong," which was written by Na and Magnetic North in 2010.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2a2ed9e8b1157fe517edbf3967d20d63" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nabulsi, Mohammed</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_56</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021234</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Nabulsi, Mohammed" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Nabulsi, Mohammed</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_68b8c6af703fb0b62e509c6c3013e002"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Loubna Qutami on August 25, 2020. In his interview, Mohammed Nabulsi details the impact of the pandemic on the Arab-American community in Houston, TX; the response of state and non-state actors; and the lessons learned and challenges experienced in developing modules for grassroots mutual aid efforts. Nabulsi speaks to the political activism his community has undertaken against anti-Black state violence following the murder of George Floyd; the community's response to the Trump Administration's declaration of the "Deal of the Century"; and the impending Israeli annexation of large portions of the West Bank. Nabulsi details how and why the community is responding to mounting crises; and the challenges they are enduring while also shedding light on the way compassion, care, love and wellness characterize the volunteer lead efforts.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b049c40f32dc381c825cae505ec7df18"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_44d236f6dc2cd636b2ce78ecbf715954"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Mohammed Nabulsi is an attorney and Palestinian community organizer based in Houston, TX. Nabulsi is the national U.S. Vice General Coordinator for the Palestinian Youth Movement (PYM), a member of the board of directors of the Houston-based Palestinian American Cultural Center (PACC), and the General Coordinator for the Houston Arab Community Mutual Aid Coalition (HACMAC). During the COVID-19 global pandemic, Nablusi was a central anchor in a variety of Houston based mutual aid services, political mobilizations, and actions.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_e7ece9332ebdada3fe5a254e143e0d43" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nguyen, Jessie</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_57</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021236</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Nguyen, Jessie" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Nguyen, Jessie</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e1080d3494d377717defebb70f4a52ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Sarah Nguyen on June 23, 2021. In the interview, Jessie Nguyen discusses how they wanted to keep their cafe open through the pandemic, but ultimately closed on March 20, 2020, and have remained closed since. Initially, the cafe was able to get funds through small business loans like the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) and grants provided by the state of California, but Nguyen remembers this process as confusing, involved, and inaccessible to someone who did not have computer literacy or extensive business records. </p><p>As their employees found work elsewhere, the cafe became involved in several community food programs around the city, like SF New Deal, a company made in response to COVID-19 that commissioned small businesses for community meals for COVID-19 shelters. Additionally, utilizing extra equipment no longer used after the cafe shut down, Nguyen started two community fridges and modeled these community fridges off of the Playground Coffee fridge system in Brooklyn, NY. Nguyen felt that in San Francisco and Oakland, many realized that community needs were not being met and had felt a call to action.</p><p>Nguyen also discusses changes to their personal life; and being able to find community outside of their restaurant work, having joined a queer trans Viet healing circle through the QTViet Cafe, a queer trans Viet gathering space in San Francisco. Through this healing circle, Nguyen also developed a three-look collection of clothing called Áo Dài for the Modern Prince. When looking forward, Nguyen states they want to approach any kind of return to restaurant work slowly and in fact, they are unsure if their relationship to food will return as a business since the old cafe structure was, in retrospect, tiring and unsustainable for their mother and themselves.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5d723e673a09e4d848efe793f045c58d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_4d215f8c3c4078f8727b82976fb1f69c"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Jessie Nguyen is a queer Vietnamese small business owner based in San Francisco, CA. They owned a small cafe in Telegraph Hill with their mother. During the pandemic, after the closure of their cafe, Nguyen developed a three-look collection of clothing called Áo Dài for the Modern Prince that reimagined the traditional Vietnamese áo dài through a diasporic, futuristic, and queer lens.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_787a921ffd0d535d443dfbff96af693b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nguyễn, Nguyên Khôi </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019573</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate></did><bioghist id="aspace_386948b28980254cfcbc06667862b08a"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Nguyên Khôi Nguyễn is a multi-disciplinary artist and educator. He is the author of the multimedia graphic novel, <emph render = "italic">The Gulf</emph>. He is the vocalist, pianist, composer, and bandleader of the jazz trio, Superior Cling. As of 2020, Nguyên was a digital media lecturer at Loyola University Maryland.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_e755243c53935ba2223c811e4a7f6a39"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a physical and digital copy of <emph render = "italic">Bittersweet: A Pandemic Sketchbook</emph>, which recounts the pandemic experience of Nguyên Khôi Nguyễn as he drove from his home in Maryland to reunite with his mother living in Florida, and their journey back to Maryland together.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ee7d1c248e47f7e33dc6164fa388416e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paper Files</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019836</unitid><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_32b9e2a2c68de7d33caf31713ac1861c" label="Mixed Materials [31142067162605]" type="Box">Shared Tamiment 189</container><container id="aspace_73bc1b8f2857b6fdeb7200c7aa2277be" parent="aspace_32b9e2a2c68de7d33caf31713ac1861c" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_3ceaaf4d303311f6f17ef0953739bc45" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_58</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019837</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did></c></c><c id="aspace_0ac55a79f12613777deee9cf57e6c1bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>NoDutDol</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_59</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019574</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="NoDutDol" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>NoDutDol</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_781007e105790c5e3208b4a3a1aab58f"><head>Historical Note</head><p>Based in New York City, NoDutDol is a community of North and South Koreans living in the United States. NoDutDol represents the Korean diaspora spread throughout the globe and is made up of artists, filmmakers, teachers, students, workers, professionals, and young families who believe in social justice.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_ab939930b7fb57c1f19f6d9246f07552"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include two zines: "From Quarantine, With Love: A NDD Zine on Hope in Uncertain Times" and "제국의 제재, Sanctions of Empire." </p><p>"From Quarantine, With Love" is a zine that Jeong Eun Annabel We directed and created. It is a documentation of NoDutDol
members' experiences during the COVID-19 Pandemic from late April to early May 2020, and proposes the grassroots organization's collective vision of reunification and demilitarization shaped by the members' reflections on the pandemic.</p><p>"제국의 제재, Sanctions of Empire" is a zine that explores the human impacts of sanctions, particularly as it relates to North Korea. With the pandemic, sanctions on North Korea deepened scarcity, highlighting the imperial motivations of international restrictions when people needed equipment, personal protective equipment, and supplies the most. This zine provides this context.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ac88d8726b6e03fad747d6ac99a369a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oye, Derek Isawo</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_60</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021243</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Oye, Derek Isawo" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Oye, Derek Isawo</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d3f121e74e3c47b210fc922849c54114"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on July 18, 2020. In this interview, Derek Isawo Oye explains the significance of taiko to the Asian American community and how it has fostered community building. He shares his personal experiences with different Taiko groups; how COVID-19 has impacted the taiko community both financially and as a communal practice; and how remote learning has changed the way the art form is being taught and performed now, and possibly into the future. Oye talks about his concerns for the future of Taiko, an art form that needs to be practiced "in community." The interview concludes with Oye addressing the ways in which the Taiko Community Alliance is addressing Black Lives Matter and issues of equity and diversity across the organization.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_98e6ffce932745efd2a32128491100f8"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_a54cbc949114cc4ce7412a4e584c59c4"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Derek Isawo Oye is a fourth generation Japanese American born and raised in Torrance, CA. He is, as of 2020, the Chair to the Board of Directors of the Taiko Community Alliance, a cultural arts service organization that empowers the people and supports the art of taiko, or Japanese drumming. He is also a member of the seminal North American taiko ensemble, Kinnara Taiko, and an active volunteer at the Gardena Valley Japanese Cultural Institute.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_7241cb24c70cc162e2f2c06e9cc382a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Park, Danny</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_61</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021250</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Park, Danny" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Park, Danny</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3743ac1233811fa7acd1d9a23e8b06f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk on July 14, 2020. In his interview, Danny Park shares his experiences living and working in Los Angeles' Skid Row district -- a space in Los Angeles just adjacent to and overlapping with downtown Los Angeles, Little Tokyo, and the Arts District. Skid Row has the heaviest concentration of homeless people in the United States, and when asked to describe what it has been like working in Skid Row since the pandemic, Park describes the isolation, anxieties, and stresses associated with witnessing the heightened precarity of communities, which are overwhelmingly Black and Brown. Park explains how this community is also already vulnerable with regards to food, healthcare, and shelter access. Park describes the pandemic as a time of deep reflection as he engages his own diasporic family histories and relationships. Park shares what has provided joy and sustenance during this tumultuous moment and the supportive mentorship he has received primarily from Black movement leaders and mentors.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_eefa007bddd0c1e9b7233b79ac1de967"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_181e923be8536bc46a9b5afaf29fbd13"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Danny Park is a social justice-minded small family business owner and community organizer from Los Angeles, CA. As of 2020, he was the owner of Skid Row People's Market and the co-founder of Skid Row Coffee in Los Angeles. Park, who co-manages the market with his mother, May Park, partnered with the Los Angeles Food Policy Council through the Healthy Neighborhood Market Network (HNMN) program with the goal of transitioning the business to focus on healthy food. As a small business owner, Park is deeply involved in the life of the Skid Row neighborhood, advocating for rights to housing, food, and work opportunities. His activism inspired his desire to use his family's market for an even greater purpose.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_b9cf9bf44be7a17792eaec2b799c0563" level="file"><did><unittitle>Park, Kyoung H. </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_62</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021253</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Park, Kyoung H." xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Park, Kyoung H.</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5f1f32afa04f3c72571ccdeac3918c50"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Minju Bae on May 12, 2021. As an artist born in Chile, rooted in Korean diasporas, and living in New York,  Kyoung Park highlights the importance of war, militarism, and traumas in his art practice; and discusses his experience as a playwright during the COVID-19 pandemic. Although categorized as "non-essential," culture workers, performers, and artists were left with inadequate relief, pay, or support, but Park worked to raise and distribute mutual aid. He also engaged in healing practices and developed programming around dismantling white supremacy. Park also described how his ensemble worked in virtual platforms, hoping to redefine and decenter theater audiences, and play productions. As a playwright committed to transformative change and abolitionist politics, Park questioned the efficacy of the traditional theater as a means to reach broad audiences, and communicate theses around peace and liberation.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_a1da223b229959fc4c43c25138c69e57"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_44462ee2036df0add7e16ae098702658"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kyoung Park is a playwright, performance artist, and theater performer. Park was born in Santiago, Chile and is the first Korean playwright from Latin America to be produced and published in the United States. As of 2021, he is the Artistic Director of Kyoung's Pacific Beat, a peacemaking theater collective that works against oppressions and seeks to heal, uplift, build, and transform the world anew. As Artistic Director, Park writes and directs devised theater by collaborating with artists, non-artists, and local communities to rigorously explore sources of violence, transforming personal and communal experiences of oppression into peace messages made public through performance. Some of Park's works include <emph render = "italic">DISORIENTED</emph>, <emph render = "italic">TALA</emph>, and <emph render = "italic">PILLOWTALK</emph>.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_3a3dbcf07e6b90bb4dcd3482851ca8b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ports, Suki Terada</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_63</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021256</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Ports, Suki Terada" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Ports, Suki Terada</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b95b7fff481e30b173d8cde72d8cafe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include transcript and audio files from oral history interviews conducted by Tomie Arai on June 26, 2020 and June 29, 2020. In her June 26, 2020 interview, Suki Terada Ports shares her family history and talks about how she became an activist; her work in the public school her children attended; and her involvement in community empowerment issues to ensure housing and park land were protected from institutional expansion. She also describes her efforts to provide care for Black, Indigenous, and people of color (BIPOC) communities with HIV/AIDS through the formation of organizations like Asian Pacific Islander Coalition on HIV/AIDS (APICHA).</p><p>In her June 29, 2020 interview, Ports speaks more directly about the personal impact of COVID-19 and sheltering-in-place during the pandemic. She describes mutual aid efforts provided to Japanese American seniors through the Japanese American Association (JAA), where she serves on the Board of Directors.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_55f64d143a8280f9c3308173c964c236"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and audio files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_fbd11aa89dfb54f108d79b8719c18271"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Suki Terada Ports has held leadership positions in the Japanese American Citizens League and the Japanese American Association in New York. Ports co-founded the Asian Pacific Islander Coalition on HIV/AIDS (APICHA) and through this organization has been able to assist members of the Asian American community with HIV/AIDS. As the child of parents directly affected by U.S. policies against Japanese Americans during World War II, Ports has devoted herself to improving the quality of life of Japanese Americans. As of 2020, Ports is retired and lives in Manhattan.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_f2f53ef0050a69a07f6431ada0504ae2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Queens Mutual Aid Network: Rima Begum &amp; Moumita Ahmed</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_64</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021259</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Queens Mutual Aid Network: Rima Begum &amp; Moumita Ahmed" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Queens Mutual Aid Network: Rima Begum &amp; Moumita Ahmed</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a30313d81001eb3ae55ae6d69b78f64e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Cynthia Gao on July 16, 2020. In the interview, Rima Begum and Moumita Ahmed explain how Queens Mutual Aid (QMA) was founded, how it was run, and what kinds of community assistance was provided. QMA's central work was food distribution; and the logistical processes of intake, fulfillment, and delivery are described. The importance of cultural sensitivity and its relationship to mutual aid principles; questions of morality and ethics amidst overwhelming need; and spiking COVID-19 deaths are also discussed.</p><p>Ahmed discusses her understanding of mutual aid; the importance of accessibility through language and computer literacy; and her political inspirations. Ahmed describes working and collaborating with other mutual aid projects in the city such as Astoria Mutual Aid, Sunnyside Mutual Aid, and the Ridgewood Tenants Union. She discusses her belief that many COVID-19 related deaths in the Bangladeshi community were under-reported or unrecorded by the city as a consequence of racial misclassification and language barriers. Although many Bangladeshis are also essential workers, despite their growing population, Bangladeshis do not have meaningful representation in local politics and are often lumped in with other "model minority" Asian American groups.</p><p>Begum discusses her day job with Chhaya Community Development Corporation and her experiences working with tenants trying to navigate rent relief programs, rent strikes, and difficult landlords. Ahmed discusses the challenges of mounting a political campaign for district leader, which she lost by sixty votes, in the middle of a pandemic. These challenges included contracting a mild case of COVID-19 and being a candidate of color operating outside the local party machine.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_5fe77b0f40b5bc7e2eac21b545a9aec4"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_25c8faee7e0c23b1d82babcf4ebd1187"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Rima Begum and Moumita Ahmed were lead organizers of Queens Mutual Aid (QMA), an ad hoc mutual aid project that ran from March 2020 to June 2020. They are both Bangladeshi-American and work with Bangladeshi Americans for Progress. Begum is also a tenant organizer with Chhaya Community Development Corporation, a Queens non-profit, which works on behalf of South Asian and Indo-Caribbean communities. Ahmed was a candidate for female district leader for Assembly 24 in 2020 and ran for City Council in District 24 in 2021.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_380f01f89ec57237a0a51a26aba5b960" level="file"><did><unittitle>Quenga, Kaina </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019580</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_23757710577110cbb2a403733b100dfe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_65</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021263</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a6c6f168ff8d73ce21d3502271cd2e18"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript from an oral history interview conducted by Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk on February 28, 2021. In this interview, Kaina Quenga talks at length about the different ways the pandemic has impacted the Hawaiian economy and community. Quenga explains that despite the economic challenges performing artists faced during lockdown, she managed to continue teaching remotely throughout the pandemic and took a traditional chanting class. Quenga recalls both the refreshing experience of being in Hawai'i without tourists at the beginning of lockdown and the frustrating experience of tourists returning, some with ideas of relocating permanently or even buying property to develop in Hawai'i. She recalls the fear Native Hawaiians faced during the pandemic due to the Indigenous population's history with invasive and deadly disease.</p><p>Quenga describes how the Indigenous communities, in and outside of Hawai'i, have organized throughout the pandemic with solidarity and support. She talks about Protect Mauna Kea and her work with Nā ʻOiwi NYC, a group that educates about Indigenous Hawaiian culture. She also discusses working with groups like the Indigenous Peoples Day Coalition and the A/P/A Institute to continue her mission to educate about the struggles and culture of Indigenous Hawai'i; and support Indigenous peoples across the United States.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_d60620aedaea0235333d475361067359"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_93543053d7cb1b1b17ca2caab47d8007"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kaina Quenga is an Indigenous and Native Hawaiian, as well as professional hula dancer and instructor. She was based in Hilo, Hawai'i at the time of the interview. The narrator had spent the last 20 years living in New York, but moved back to Hawai'i in January of 2020.</p></bioghist></c></c><c id="aspace_25573f893ea5763074e1d7d2effe7a28" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richards, Zabrina</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_66</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021266</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Richards, Zabrina" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Richards, Zabrina</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5c609302b22420d417a5f85b901edc0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Rochelle Kwan on September 6, 2020. A drawing titled "Go Back to China" and poems by Zabrina Richards are also included. </p><p>In this interview, Richards talks about her experience as an Asian American adoptee living in the predominantly white town of Arundel, Maine, where she lacks an Asian American community. Since the start of the pandemic, Richards has been particularly focused on the news of xenophobia and hate crimes against Asians and Asian Americans. She recalls her mother's decision to not allow her to go grocery shopping because she did not want Richards to be the next potential target of a hate crime. For Richards, the pandemic has revealed the detrimental impacts of the model minority myth, the discrimination Asian Americans continue to face in the U.S. today, and the fear of violence for being Asian American. To cope with these fears and frustrations, Richards has been spending her time reading, writing poetry, and learning about Asian American history. In the future, she hopes to connect with other Asian American youth through her poetry, organizing, and celebrating of their Asian American identity and culture.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9967ae40e77a898fa89563c5eed795c1"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_67bf57bef3c61d8055e9d455c4071b40"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Zabrina Richards is a Chinese American, first generation, transracially adopted high school student from Arundel, Maine.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_8f15eac6cdd78e4644397737bc1f1530" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rongkilyo, Set Hernandez</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_67</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021269</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Rongkilyo, Set Hernandez" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Rongkilyo, Set Hernandez</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_825830180577b66caeb96c23b2f224af"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript from an oral history interview conducted by Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk on August 24, 2020. In the interview, Set Hernandez Rongkilyo shares their thoughts about what it means to navigate COVID-19 in Los Angeles, CA as a Black, Indigenous, and Person of Color (BIPOC); queer; and undocumented person. They mention that COVID-19 is not the worst thing they've experienced because shelter-in-place conditions are something they and other undocumented peoples experience on a daily basis beyond the pandemic. Rongkilyo discusses their cultural work and labor as a filmmaker; and how important and grounding their work has been, especially during difficult or sad moments. </p><p>Rongkilyo reflects on the importance of supporting the Black Lives Matter (BLM) uprisings and the Black community. Rongkilyo shares how they came out to their mother during the pandemic; their methods of communication with their father, who lives in the Philippines; being reunited with someone who took care of them and their siblings in the Philippines when their parents were migrant workers in Japan; and the passing of a migrant worker and fellow community organizer from COVID-19 in June 2020. Rongkilyo reflects on the complex meaning of "value" when it comes to the lives of migrant workers, undocumented peoples, and others who inhabit precarious social positions; and how certain people might come to believe that their lives are less "significant" than others.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_6474587fdcf42c3fe823696dcb2bcfa6"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_59c0fa183fd24e70515b7c3259d92571"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Set Hernandez Rongkilyo is a filmmaker, cultural worker, and community organizer. Rongkilyo is an undocumented immigrant who originates from Bicol, Philippines. Rongkilyo produces videos and short documentaries that advance grassroots messaging for migrant justice campaigns. Their work is rooted in the belief that cultural strategies can propel political transformation, and to do this, directly-impacted people must embrace the empowerment to tell their own stories authentically. Since 2010, Rongkilyo has been involved in organizing efforts around migrant justice issues such as education equity for undocumented students, deportation defense, driver's licenses, and healthcare access for undocumented Californians. Rongkilyo's short films have been televised, featured, and awarded in film festivals across the U.S. Their current film projects explore the intersectional issues impacting undocumented immigrants, including the connection between immigrant rights and disability rights.</p><p>Rongkilyo was also the Assistant Editor and Impact Producer for PJ Raval's award-winning documentary, <emph render = "italic">Call Her Ganda</emph>, which premiered at the 2018 Tribeca Film Festival. Rongkilyo's 2019 short documentary, <emph render = "italic">COVER/AGE</emph>, follows the campaign to expand healthcare access for undocumented elderly immigrants in California by centering the voices of immigrant health justice leaders. In addition to the 2018 Firelight Media Impact Producer Fellowship, Rongkilyo is the recipient of the 2019 Working Docs in Action Film Fund, 2019 Annenberg Civic Media Fellowship, 2017 Soros Justice Fellowship, among others. Rongkilyo co-founded the UndocuFilmmakers Collective, a space for undocumented filmmakers situated across the United States.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_f141c62a4379f1fd76b68b881f1a26b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Samuelu, Tavae </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019584</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_77dacabea7c0cbebc3c1ea5d6ea96579" level="file"><did><unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_68</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021272</unitid><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Digital Files" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Digital Files</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f9340355e05a4168db47eb98d8146563"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript from an oral history interview conducted by Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk on November 22, 2020. In her interview, Tavae Samuelu discusses the impact of COVID-19 on her national organizing work with EPIC (Empowering Pacific Islander Communities), as well as on her multigenerational family in Long Beach, CA. Samuelu discusses the specific impact COVID-19 has had on Native Hawaiian Pacific Islander (NHPI) communities and how these communities have been disproportionately impacted by COVID-19. She emphasizes that everyone across NHPI communities are only a degree removed from knowing someone who has passed away from the virus. In her interview, Samuelu discusses the entrenched politics of disposability and dispossession that shape NHPI communities' experiences, in regards to their limited access to resources and the lack of ethical response from political leaders in the United States. </p><p>Throughout the interview, Samuelu makes clear that COVID-19 has only made hyper-visible the fracture points and existing inequities that already exist in U.S. settler society; and the ways that Indigenous peoples, including Samoan and other Pacific Islander communities, have for centuries survived multiple catastrophes. Samuelu shares how she and her household contracted COVID-19 over the summer of 2020 and the anxieties, fears, and concerns related to becoming sick again and impacting others. Samuelu mentions the struggles she and other NHPI leaders and organizations face as their communities have collapsed with Asian Americans and the tokenization that often happens with her leadership in Asian American institutional spaces. She ends the interview by discussing how COVID-19 has impacted her own perspectives regarding her own body, health, and the comfort provided by rest and naps.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9ae7c96ba95a7a4e0cba531b358c04dc"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_bc489fd668d59f266ebe06cfb316c01e"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Tavae Samuelu is the daughter of a pastor from Leulumoega and a nurse from Saleimoa in Sāmoa. Tavae was born in Compton, CA; raised in Long Beach, CA; and credits the Bay Area for her political identity and consciousness. Of the many titles she has, the most important one is Aunty Vae.</p></bioghist></c></c><c id="aspace_5dff5a1ee6b9615bbe38337e889f5e55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sridaran, Lakshmi </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_69</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021274</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Sridaran, Lakshmi " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Sridaran, Lakshmi</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_82272e24ef757ccac6ef97a4f43d8d0e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Amita Manghnani on August 24, 2021. During her interview, Lakshmi Sridaran talks about her work as Executive Director of South Asian Americans Leading Together (SAALT) and describes some of the specific ways South Asian communities in the U.S. have been impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic. Sridaran draws attention to the disparities and inequities within these communities, pointing out that working class and minority South Asians, including Muslims and Sikhs, have been more impacted by the failure of the state and social injustice of the last 16+ months. She also discusses SAALT's responses to its constituents and member organizations, which comprise the National Coalition of South Asian Organization, many of whom were reporting issues accessing health care, hospital beds, food, domestic violence resources, legal services, employment, benefits, assistance, and information about COVID-19 in South Asian languages. </p><p>Sridaran points out that as the federal government failed to adequately respond and nonprofits were stretched so thin, SAALT shifted its focus from policy advocacy to on-the-ground response. She also shares her personal experience of being pregnant and becoming a parent during the pandemic; coping with her father being sick and in the hospital; and her visions for a "post-pandemic" world. Sridaran reflects on the impact the Black Lives Matter (BLM) movement has had on her development as an organizer; the evolving public discourse on the occupation of Palestine; the very recent events surrounding American withdrawal from Afghanistan; and the approaching twentieth anniversary of September 11 and its significance in today's discourse on anti-Asian racism.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_37f628be30897a44b1be3c348cf142ac"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_c197959f93eaf60fd2e89462d8ad1bf1"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Lakshmi Sridaran is the Executive Director of South Asian Americans Leading Together (SAALT). Since 2014, she was SAALT's Director of National Policy and Advocacy, where she led the organization's external engagement and developed SAALT's policy and legislative agenda, which primarily focuses on immigration, racial profiling, and combating hate violence. Prior to that, she served as the Policy Director for The Praxis Project, a Washington D.C. based national movement support organization focused on health justice in communities of color. Before moving to D.C., Sridaran completed six years of work in New Orleans, LA after Hurricane Katrina, helping improve federal contracting opportunities for Disadvantaged Business Enterprises; instituting participatory budgeting; and preserving public schools and infrastructure. Sridaran holds a M.A. in City Planning from Massachusetts Institute of Technology and a B.A. in Ethnic Studies from The University of California, Berkeley.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_6198d88c9fd27c6c7ec0fa2c6472ac26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Su, Celina</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_70</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021276</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2021" type="inclusive">2020-2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Su, Celina" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Su, Celina</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2b60aafb022b1ad6476ed825a7a1082a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Diane Wong on September 3, 2021. A flyer for Celina Su's playground reading event and two articles written by Su are also included. </p><p>The interview starts with Su sharing her experiences of the COVID-19 lockdown, the rush of emotions when her partner was sick, and the logistics of trying to care for her father in Queens. Su also talks about the various hardships of new motherhood, especially the lack of support from the state during the pandemic; and the community of support she found elsewhere through mutual aid and other localized networks. Su talks about an outdoor playground reading she organized in a park that brought together mothers and children in the neighborhood. In the second half of the interview, Su shares an excerpt from correspondence she wrote with her friend Wah-Ming that was published in the Brooklyn Rail about experiences of sheltering in place during the pandemic. The conversation ends with Su talking about her fears for the current state of the world and hopes for an abundant future.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e9a49564a0bf95c81a610385f6f547cc"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_975532907f6c5b8e4f3334a84692cdcb"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Celina Su was born in São Paulo, Brazil and as of 2020, lives in Brooklyn, NY. She is a poet and writer; and the Marilyn J. Gittel Chair in Urban Studies and professor of Political Science at the City University of New York. She has written several books including <emph render="italic">Landia</emph> and <emph render="italic">Streetwise for Booksmarts: Grassroots Organizing and Education Reform in the Bronx</emph>; and has had pieces featured in the <emph render="italic">New York Times Magazine</emph>, <emph render="italic">Harper's</emph>, and <emph render="italic">n+1</emph>. Su's work focuses on everyday struggles for collective governance, centered economic justice, and racial justice. She is also the co-founder of Kwah Dao, the Burmese Refugee Project, which was founded in 2000. Su served as the Executive Director and then a board member until 2016.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_7658dceb34d250af3ca71f81b4ef2996" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sunwoo, Elizbeth "Liz"</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_71</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021278</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Sunwoo, Elizbeth &quot;Liz&quot;" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Sunwoo, Elizbeth "Liz"</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f115b4ebad7fab27b20250c4b5814ac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk on August 13, 2020. In her interview, Elizabeth "Liz" Sunwoo discusses what it has been like to live in a COVID-19 epicenter, Los Angeles, CA; and the challenges COVID-19 has created for her family and the organizations she works with as a social justice consultant. She discusses the intersection of COVID-19 and racial justice; shares what it has been like to raise two young daughters in Koreatown; and recognizes the ways in which racial, class, and gender privilege impact the everyday decisions she makes personally and professionally. Sunwoo discusses the formation of Kids for Justice and Freedom, an experimental network modeled on the Radical Monarchs that provides a critical experiential learning space where young children aged 8-12 learn about and tackle racial, gender, sexual, and class asymmetries, while also providing children the opportunity to inhabit decision-making positions. Finally, Sunwoo discusses the impact COVID-19 and racial violence has had on the organizations she works with, including youth-based organizations that focus on
homeless populations in Los Angeles County.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_a89f9c02c0a1c6226ac0ce2189e7d918"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_4b1e72726bd8ab3ebcf7f15378921fcd"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Elizabeth "Liz" Sunwoo is a social justice movement and organizing consultant based in Los Angeles, CA. She has a long history of working with immigrant justice, labor rights, and multiracial solidarity organizations; and collaboratives, including what was then called the Korean Immigrant Workers Alliance (KIWA) and the Multi-ethnic Immigrant Worker Organizing Network (MIWON). She also worked as the Southern California Organizing Director for Change to Win Labor Federation; and the Director of Leadership Development and Civic Engagement at CDTech in South Los Angeles. </p><p>For the last several years, Sunwoo has been working as a social justice consultant working on initiatives with the Department of Child and Family Services in Los Angeles County; the California Endowment's Building Healthy Communities South Los Angeles site; the CA Labor Commissioner's Office; the James Irvine Foundation's Worker Influence Initiative and Dignity in Schools California that aims to use research and organizing to end the School to Prison pipeline; and most recently, the UCLA Asian American Labor Studies Center.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_73bbc94b3bb4516e4c44e4dd3721468e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Svetvilas, Chanika </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_72</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021280</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2021" type="inclusive">2020-2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Svetvilas, Chanika" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Svetvilas, Chanika</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_84ff26248d2629398a952536ec1fe1a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from two oral history interviews conducted by Tomie Arai on July 7, 2020 and January 26, 2021. The film <emph render = "italic">COVID-19 Chapters 1 &amp; 2</emph>, which is also included, was filmed and edited by Svetvilas and documents her experience during COVID-19. </p><p>In her July 7, 2020 interview, Chanika Svetvilas discusses the impact the pandemic had on her family – both her sisters are nurses. Svetvilas talk about producing and sewing protective gowns and PPE for essential workers during the early stages of the pandemic and her work as an advocate for disability justice. In her work in disability justice, Svetvilas comments on how moving online has made many events more accessible. She emphasizes that accessibility and inclusion like this should not be afterthoughts or products of necessity, but instead part of everyday life. Svetvilas also talks about disability as a spectrum and oftentimes being invisible, like in the case of her bipolar disorder. Svetvilas reflects on the possibility of returning to "normal," but reaffirms that normal is a standard that is problematic and does not really exist. Svetvilas contextualizes this in how a return to normal would negatively impact the disability community.</p><p>In her January 26, 2021 interview, Svetvilas discloses she has received a rent grant lottery from New Jersey and has had two-thirds of her rent covered for six months. She goes on to discuss the ways her family continues to be affected by the pandemic, especially due to the fact that most of them are essential workers. Svetvilas touches on how she has kept in remote contact with her father in Thailand and siblings throughout the U.S. via online chatting and family video calls.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_b77835cdf13df1c4e917ff58d68a2f0b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_f90cb513f815b7c6fdd12d39e5b05b18"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Chanika Svetvilas is a Thai-American interdisciplinary artist and disability rights activist. She has presented her work at Stony Brook University, the Queens Museum, ABC No Rio, the Brooklyn Public Library, and other spaces. In 2020, she curated Unique Minds: Creative Voices, an exhibition of art and creative writing for Princeton University's Mental Health Awareness Month. She is the co-founder of ThaiLinks, a collective that was based in New York City dedicated to increasing awareness about Thai issues and the Thai American community; and Thai Takes, a biennial Thai film festival presented in New York City. </p><p>After experiencing a bipolar manic episode and hospitalization in 2010, Svetvilas was motivated to explore her experience and to break the stigma connected to invisible disabilities. She decided to use her art practice to create safe spaces that build community through public interactions. As a mental health advocate, Svetvilas has presented at national mental health conferences on arts and disability and addresses her personal experiences with discrimination and stigma. </p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_317c7421c467ce1c9206363b9b6cc3f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Taiko Community Alliance</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_73</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019590</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Taiko Community Alliance" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Taiko Community Alliance</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_114d43c77cee9143f3a51fe9691c62f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a video of "Taiko and COVID-19: Sharing Experiences," which captures commentary from leaders within the taiko community, sharing how COVID-19 has impacted them and their taiko.</p></scopecontent><bioghist id="aspace_46c65a0c0277dda1f84dd00108261082"><head>Historical Note</head><p>The Taiko Community Alliance (TCA) is a 501(c)3 nonprofit organization with a mission to empower the people and advance the art of taiko, or Japanese drumming. TCA was the first nonprofit outside of Japan to provide art services and resources to taiko practitioners.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_05e05dc35cdad4e73795092646bb996e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tirona, Marissa</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_74</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021282</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Tirona, Marissa" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Tirona, Marissa</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_40b51dc886f22bd8101bb0e734191d6a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript from an oral history interview conducted by Lena Sze on March 7, 2021. In her interview, Marissa Tirona recounts her experiences during the early days of New York City's location as a global epicenter in March 2020; her hospitalization as a result of COVID-19 that included a 28-day induced coma during which she was on life support; the remainder of her stay at the hospital and a rehabilitation center into May 2020; and her recovering and healing process since her hospitalization. Tirona discusses her frightening ordeal, and the intensity and trauma of her family's experience, particularly her teenage daughter, Bebe, and her husband, Ephraim. She reflects on the connections with her community; and how she understands care and caregiving, especially on the part of her husband. As a social justice advocate active in philanthropy, Tirona spends time reflecting on the meaning and experience of the Black Lives Matter (BLM) protests of 2020; and the intertwined and complicated politics around anti-Asian violence during the pandemic. She speaks of these larger political movements in terms of her own experience, especially as she watches her child develop her own analysis and consciousness as a mixed-race person, Filipina/Black/White, growing up during this pandemic.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_7156afce9bea44d659576c73bfa1b50b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_07fdd65c80eeadb7f4e5a43ef79206c0"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Marissa Tirona is a Filipino American woman who lives and works in New York City.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_5eb169c15e178fd72e6aba67d6dce3a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vaj, Kabzuag </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_75</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021287</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Vaj, Kabzuag " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Vaj, Kabzuag</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fadf3a671eee6509dd9f9f864a6a3764"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Crystal (Mun-Hye) Balk on July, 10, 2020. In her interview, Kabzuag Vaj describes how Freedom Inc.'s work in Madison, WI centers on the critical health, wellbeing, and power of Black, Southeast Asian, and refugee communities. She describes the pre-pandemic structural violence experienced by Black and Southeast Asian peoples; and how these precarities have only been amplified by COVID-19. Vaj also describes the origins of Freedom Inc. prior to 2003 and how influential her experiences abroad helped conceptualize the organization, especially in regards to her experiences in Thai refugee camps. Through these experiences, Vaj questioned why and how certain peoples and communities experienced uneven levels of state violence, socioeconomic precarity, and loss -- a line of questioning that brought her to a more developed critique of racial capitalism. </p><p>At the beginning of the pandemic, Vaj describes the fear and anxieties experienced by Southeast Asian and Black communities, particularly among elders. She describes the difficulties experienced by youths who could not access the Internet for school and the domestic violence others were experiencing in their homes. As a consequence of the pandemic, Freedom Inc. had to shift its work foci by supporting mutual aid, housing access, food access, direct service, and support; while also supporting Black Lives Matter organizing, racial justice, and liberation. Vaj mentions the anti-Asian sentiments and anti-Blackness she's experienced within her own community, and how supporting Black Lives Matter is crucial given that Black liberation lifts and supports our entire society and social ecosystem. In the context of George Floyd's murder in May 2020 in Minneapolis, Vaj emphasizes the urgent necessity of framing the protests as an uprising for justice within the Southeast Asian community, rather than describing it as "looting" or "property damage." Lastly, Vaj emphasizes that because of the violence and urgency of the current moment, there has been no moment to rest for community organizers such as herself, who are also essential workers.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fd97c35d6bd574b8b1c3e5c775e10b10"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_5da48a122c6c7474d8e2b8b7ca942e01"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kabzuag Vaj was born in Laos and came to the United States as a refugee with her mother and siblings. She is the founder and co-executive director of Freedom Inc., a Black and Southeast Asian nonprofit organization that works with low to no-income communities of color. Vaj has dedicated the majority of her life to ending gender-based violence. Her advocacy started when she was 16 years old, assisting and housing at-risk teens; and challenging abusive gender norms within her community. She is a strong believer that those who are most deeply impacted must be at the forefront of the movement and have opportunities and resources to advocate for themselves and tell their own stories.</p><p>Vaj has spent her life working to build collective power and social change within Southeast Asian and Black communities. She was recognized as a Champion of Change at the White House during Domestic Violence Awareness month in 2011 and was named one of "20 Women of Color in Politics to Watch in 2020" by She the People. Vaj is a co-founder of Building Our Future, a global  community campaign that works to change traditional practices, behaviors, and beliefs that contribute to gender-based violence within Hmong Families while building the leadership of women and girls. Vaj is also a co-owner and founder of Red Green Rivers, a social enterprise that works with artisan makers, most of whom are women and girls, from the Mekong Region in Southeast Asia. Vaj is a daughter, mother, artist, and organizer. </p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_0866e3a99a14023a09b4475b227a50f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vani</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_76</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021289</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Vani" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Vani</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ffb01b1767b45c09185d4e031a0b121a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Lena Sze on August 7, 2020. In this interview, Vani discusses aspects of this pandemic ranging from workplace policies and their partial furlough; the profit-driven model of higher education as evidenced through this pandemic; forms of community built geographically through a mutual aid group in a very gentrified Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood they were involved in; and socializing virtually through a book club that was important to them during the pandemic. Vani discusses the grief of losing people to COVID-19; and discusses the protests and politics following the murder of George Floyd, racial justice, trans rights, abolitionism, anti-Islamophobia, and Hindu nationalism.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_d3c2f5470de68edd8d4fa58ede9f7a5e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_72fe020201db4fe495008287a9696157"><head>Biographical / Historical</head><p>Vani is an Indian American writer and librarian living in New York City.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_7e4653057cc591d0f5eb5de9b3b6fee5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wang, Claire </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_78</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021293</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Wang, Claire " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Wang, Claire</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b958426b46cf32b0365cf5d7746d3a22"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Sarah Lin on July 30, 2020. In the interview, Claire Wang discusses her journalistic work and reflects on how topics she focused on changed over the course of the pandemic. Some COVID-19 related topics Wang covered include a story about Korean BBQ restaurants affected by COVID-19; and attempting to locate the intersection between the anti-Asian xenophobia, the economic downturn, and racial justice protests. During the course of her reporting, Wang realized an under coverage of Asian American stories in media and journalism. As the pandemic continued, Wang's stories evolved to include stories about Asian American restaurants and seniors; and as summer 2020 continued, she began to cover Asian Americans and the Black Lives Matter movement. Wang's work during the pandemic made her realize the challenges of being a journalist in an online/remote environment and the need for self-care. She also learned some systemic challenges moving forward and the importance of creating a public memory.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_83ffb2efdfe391643c2ce96b45ed0446"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_f552ed0ec3a5b9d69c9c6da1327c2cd0"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Claire Wang is a California-based freelance reporter who writes about politics, culture, and Asian-American issues. Her byline has appeared in <emph render="italic">NBC News</emph>, <emph render="italic">Atlas Obscura</emph>, <emph render="italic">Mic</emph>, <emph render="italic">Vice</emph>, the <emph render="italic">South China Morning Post</emph>, the <emph render="italic"> American Prospect</emph>, and several other publications.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_50637ebb7ffdb3d4227e66758f0d2da7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Williams, Kai Naima</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_79</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021296</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Williams, Kai Naima" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Williams, Kai Naima</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_928d2b35b02e0ec7b4ded8a8e2d1cd82"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on December 1, 2021. In the interview Kai Naima Williams recounts being a senior at Wesleyan University and being on Spring Break with her friends in California when the COVID-19 lockdowns began. She remembers finishing her last semester virtually and thinking she and her friends would return to campus to graduate together, but was disappointed when they did not return and she was unable to experience a traditional graduation ceremony.</p><p>Williams recounts attending Black Lives Matter (BLM) protests in high school and compares how different it was during the pandemic. In 2020, she wanted to attend as many BLM protests as possible, but was afraid of contracting COVID-19 at the marches and then potentially spreading it to her family. As a Black multiracial woman with Black family members, Williams describes how painful it is to see Black people continuously murdered in this country and how difficult it was to not have the same in-person support structures in place because of the pandemic.</p><p>Williams talks about her paternal great-grandmother, Yuri Kochiyama, a radical activist and freedom fighter who fought for all oppressed people in this country. For Williams, Kochiyama has become a symbol of solidarity, particularly for her work in combating anti-Black racism. Being both Black and Asian, Williams was troubled by the tensions between the Black and Asian communities, especially during a time of increased violence against both communities. When the Atlanta spa shootings happened and six Asian women were murdered, Williams experienced a similar depression to when George Floyd was killed, however, this time she felt more isolated in her grief due to her lack of Asian friends. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_ed94c4a962280f633ee4d95100a4cc8f"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_65ea9fbd546450a92b8360f4c7c52dd4"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kai Naima Williams was born and raised in New York City and identifies as multi-racial -- Japanese, Black American, and Jewish. Williams is a storyteller, published author, poet, and performer. She is the granddaughter of interviewer Tomie Arai and the great-granddaughter of activist Yuri Kochiyama.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_5f14444980e13f4157ec3e24df075292" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wong, Alice</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_80</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021299</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Wong, Alice" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Wong, Alice</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_28aceada89161ab9c7a42bcb77437034"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Rochelle Kwan on January 14, 2021. In this interview, Alice Wong talks about her experience as an Asian American woman with disabilities during the COVID-19 pandemic. During a time when people with disabilities were continued to be seen as disposable and Asian Americans were experiencing high rates of racist violence, her identity as an Asian American woman with disabilities placed her at the intersection of ableism, racism, and xenophobia. She reflects on the bittersweet transition to virtual gatherings from home, which forced many people to think about accessibility and workplace flexibility for the first time, despite longtime efforts to advocate for these things from the disability community. Wong discusses her and her community's history of online socializing and activism pre-pandemic; the erasure of these longtime efforts; and her hopes for the rest of the world to carry and adapt these lessons beyond the pandemic to ensure greater accessibility for all.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_e3d27125ec3b1800c777e2c7ee72a21f"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_088674bdb5867f19c15b04f4885fcd34"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Alice Wong is a disability activist, media maker, and consultant. For Wong, accessibility promotes connection and community, thereby fostering safety and care. She is the Founder and Director of the Disability Visibility Project, created in 2014, which is an online community dedicated to creating, sharing, and amplifying disability media and culture. Wong is the editor of <emph render = "italic">Disability Visibility: First-Person Stories from the Twenty-First Century</emph> (Vintage Books, 2020), an anthology of essays by people with disabilities, and hosts the Disability Visibility Project podcast.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_7d354e789ec12c2f18611c31cb3c7197" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wong, Cheryl Wing-Zi </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_81</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019598</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Wong, Cheryl Wing-Zi " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Wong, Cheryl Wing-Zi</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9341d92c2b2f8dd15ef87c838f90d135"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include "Musings from Chinatown: Peri-Pandemic Notes on Resilience," a bilingual English and Chinese digital publication featuring contributions from Chinatown community members on how to stay resilient and how to remember the stories of Chinatowns. This publication was produced by Cheryl Wing-Zi Wong as part of the Calgary Chinatown artist residency commissioned by The City of Calgary's public art program in partnership with The New Gallery. This project is also supported by The Laundromat Project through the Creative Action Fund.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_3d7ded2c3238f3a15d21429e2b0252f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wong, Kristina</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_82</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021304</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Wong, Kristina" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Wong, Kristina</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4bae4df6bdf9ab6f3f7bc24bda1aa7bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Preeti Sharma on July 7, 2021. A large majority of the interview focuses on Kristina Wong's experience as the founder of Auntie Sewing Squad, a group she says formed only because the government failed to properly provide masks for its people. Wong goes over some of the difficulties the group faced early on to produce masks when the demand for face coverings was overwhelming and sourcing materials was a struggle. Later in the conversation, Wong explains a shift in the Squad's priorities from hospitals to communities of color that did not have the same access to masks. While there were many other mask making groups who wanted to avoid politics, the Auntie Sewing Squad did not shy away. To them, mask making was inherently a political act. While Wong warmly shares her feelings of genuine love and community that developed out of the Squad, she does state she does not want the group to last forever and explains her reasons for not wanting to turn Auntie Sewing Squad into a non-profit.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_2d55603dc7b3e1fca1d5193b7cd44366"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_aad790e6b8e42f33961d2ad5f6600ebc"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kristina Wong is a third-generation Chinese American performance artist and Los Angeles, CA council member. Wong was raised in San Francisco, CA and as of 2020, she resides in Los Angeles' Koreatown. Wong had just started performing <emph render = "italic">Kristina Wong for Public Office</emph> when the lockdowns started in California, but no longer able to perform, she decided to start Auntie Sewing Squad, a national group of volunteers who have been making masks for those in need during the COVID-19 pandemic. Inspired by her experience, Wong created a new performance called <emph render = "italic">Kristina Wong Sweatshop Overlord</emph>. The New York Theater Workshop was streaming the performance from October 25, 2021 to December 14, 2021.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_ff1a8808b8a71e4487425ff59ca8820b" level="file"><did><unittitle>W.O.W. Project</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_77</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019594</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="W.O.W. Project" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>W.O.W. Project</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_9137e2e338598b85f8a2d842768835ef"><head>Historical Note</head><p>The W.O.W. Project is a female, queer, and trans-led community initiative using art and activism to grow and protect New York City Chinatown's creative culture.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_bbe8aa72c14bb3396a31e207f8b0b508"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a copy of "Love Letters to Chinatown," which is a collection of love letters, poems, paintings, and essays dedicated to Chinatown.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_91360c0e5a3df1d5859e40841ebf016f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Xiong, Khaty </unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_83</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021306</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2022">2022</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Xiong, Khaty " xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Xiong, Khaty</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e4c26b66332bafaa9fe6bbee6a090512"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on March 30, 2022. A photograph of Khaty Xiong's mother is also included. </p><p>Xiong begins the interview talking about her work as a poet writing primarily about her experience dealing with deep loss. She describes herself as a "poet living in Ohio trying to make sense of the pandemic, writing a book about grief" and trying to build a space about grieving publicly, as New York University's Spring 2022 Artist in Residence. Setting up the installation in New York City was her first time traveling since the lockdown. Xiong talks in detail about the isolation and loneliness she felt while sheltering in place for two years; and how the quarantine and her loss of connection with community and family has impacted her life deeply. Xiong reflects on the reasons she became a poet and why she writes about grief, which is tied directly to her family's history and wartime experiences in Laos. As a way to deal with the anxiety she struggles with about her Hmong identity, she believes writing about hard things and writing poetry, while naming the process of grieving, is what empowers her.</p><p>In the second part of the interview, Xiong shares a family photograph of her mother who is dressed in traditional Hmong clothing. She talks candidly about her mother's death, which was the impetus for the installation, "The Grief Garden," at NYU. Xiong describes the installation as a space for visitors to mourn privately as well as publicly, through the act of sharing handwritten
stories about people they have lost on templates provided in the installation and adding them to the garden. She talks about her writing practice and the challenges she has faced as a Hmong poet. The interview ends with a discussion about memorials, memorialized spaces, and the mural "In the Future, Our Asian Community is Safe" by Jess X Snow, which touched Xiong and has given her hope.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_3deef441cddb346a1fffe41ad19eaf57"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_1e3dd36088883ce6ed0fe3ec7b9809ff"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Khaty Xiong was born to Hmong refugees from Laos. She is the author of <emph render = "italic">Poor Anima</emph> (Apogee Press, 2015), which is the first full-length collection of poetry published by a Hmong American woman in the United States. Xiong's work has been featured in <emph render="italic">The New York Times</emph> and <emph render = "italic">How Do I Begin?: A Hmong American Literary Anthology</emph> (Heyday, 2011), as well as on the Poetry Society of America's website. Xiong was the Spring 2022 Artist-in-Residence at the A/P/A Institute at New York University.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_da48aaaa5062b3927855c16bc7ac86e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yakupitiyage, Thanushka</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_84</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021309</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Yakupitiyage, Thanushka" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Yakupitiyage, Thanushka</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2f21c3451862cf09bd2ff459a16590f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Amita Manghnani on July 23, 2021. In this conversation Thanushka Yakupitiyage reflects on the events of March 2020 and the first weeks of the pandemic; the changes she witnessed in her Brooklyn neighborhood; and connects it to the news she was hearing from Southeast Asia, where her parents live and where she grew up. As a DJ, climate activist, and migrant rights organizer, Yakupitiyage talks about the challenges this time posed to her political and artistic work -- when people were prohibited from gathering together in physical spaces. She explores the questions: how do political organizers and cultural workers fulfill their goals? How does one organize and mobilize communities locally and globally? How can a DJ continue to create spaces of joy and connection?</p><p>Yakupitiyage also analyzes the intersection between climate justice work, the existing inequities exposed by the COVID-19 pandemic, and forced migrations around the world. She speaks about her own experience as an immigrant to the U.S., the challenges in being so far away from her elderly parents who live in Asia, and vaccine inequity. Since Yakupitiyage is immunocompromised and has been a caretaker for an infant during this time, she has had a heightened sense of wanting to be careful during the pandemic. She speaks about the ways shifting gatherings to an online space has affected her, her sense of community, and the ways in which she responds emotionally to isolation during this time.</p><p>Yakupitiyage comments on the rise of anti-Asian violence and highlights the ways South Asians have been left out of the conversation. She also addresses white performativity during the Black Lives Matter protests during the summer of 2020. She ends the interview speaking about her hopes for a different kind of future, and the ways in which community and relationships might form more intentionally. </p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_0e1ea32d1ac6918c105c925bc0ddc1a3"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_7691c7148e048d87e850ff9fb4ce05e4"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Thanushka Yakupitiyage is a Sri Lankan-born and Thailand raised activist; a cultural organizer; and DJ under the artist moniker "Ushka." She deejays from the perspective of a dancer, blending a wide range of club music from soca to dancehall, hip hop to South Asian rhythms, Baltimore/Jersey club to baile funk, vogue cuts to kuduro, azonto to Afrobeats and more. When she is not crafting dancefloor spaces, she's a political and cultural organizer.</p><p>Yakupitiyage has performed across the United States, Mexico, and Canada—including at institutions such as the Brooklyn Museum, MoMA PS1, the American Museum of Natural History, and the Rubin Museum. She released mixtapes on Discwoman and The Fader; produced a sound piece for artist Mel Chin's installation at the Queens Museum; and played on the online music platform Boiler Room. She was NYU's Asian/Pacific/American Institute's 2018-2019 Artist-in-Residence and was selected to be one of fifty-two artists to produce new work for The Shed Open Call in 2019.</p><p>Ushka collaborates with a wide range of DJs and producers including DJ Rupture, Tygapaw, Papi Juice, Uproot Andy, Riobamba, and Juliana Huxtable. For several years, Ushka has thrown a Queer and Trans People of Color (QTPOC) and immigrant-centered global club party with DJ Beto called iBomba.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_a821ad3f191b172b0b098c5312611298" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yu, Betty</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_85</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021314</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Yu, Betty" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Yu, Betty</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5cbac0170532a9df679e3fc7c90479c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Tomie Arai on October 22, 2020. Photographs, artwork, and videos related to Betty Yu's  interactive project "Intimate/Distant: Family Roots + the Pandemic" are also included. </p><p>In this interview, Yu talks extensively about her project, "Intimate/Distant," an interactive web-based documentary project that tells her family's immigrant stories through video, photographs, mixed media collages, and archival materials. The COVID-19 lockdown and the ways it has impacted her parent's relationship is at the center of these stories. The short video vignettes provide a portal into her family's journey, beginning with the COVID-19 global pandemic and going back to the early days of Chinese exclusion in 1882.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_fbd3508f53a55783c05cc265aadae62e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_b5434606cfb4f18add3ff83c49efd95c"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Betty Yu is a multimedia artist, photographer, filmmaker, educator, and activist. She was born and raised in New York City to Chinese immigrant parents. Yu integrates documentary film, new media platforms, and community-infused approaches into her artistic practice; and has close to 20 years of community, media justice, and labor organizing experience. In 2015, along with ManSee Kong and Tomie Arai, Yu co-founded the Chinatown Art Brigade, a cultural collective using art to advance anti-gentrification organizing. As of 2020, she works as an adjunct assistant professor teaching new media, film theory, art and video production at various colleges in New York City, including The New School, John Jay College, Pratt Institute, Marymount Manhattan College, and Hunter College.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_f28f0354181f620e482a65caab9a5562" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zaatari, Zeina</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_86</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021317</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Zaatari, Zeina" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Zaatari, Zeina</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96e5c38c24bd3def47a1946536cd15d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Loubna Qutami on October 19, 2020. In the interview, Zeina Zaatari begins by speaking about her personal experience as both the director of the Arab-American Cultural Center and as a mother since the beginning of the pandemic; and the challenges of homeschooling and working from home. She then speaks about the Center, which is the only one of its kind nationwide, and the ways the pandemic has affected its programs. Zaatari also posits important opportunities for reflection and creative ways to continue student and community engagement despite new challenges. Zaatari speaks to the methodological process by which the center assesses the needs and interests of the students; and how it develops programs and initiatives that collectively engage and respond to pressing needs. Zaatari also speaks about how the pandemic has been felt in University life, how it poses potential permanent change to higher-education, and how it has affected the everyday lives of students at all levels. Placing these reflections into the broader political, racial, and economic context of the U.S. right now, Zaatari explores how the center has and continues to create values and practices that meaningfully reflect student/community understandings of justice and wellness.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_61b8cddd75e75230029c9c976f4a9d37"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_e8870039b0f29f800435c9f40ef27898"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Dr. Zeina Zaatari is an Arab feminist scholar, organizer, and Director of the Arab-American Cultural Center at the University of Illinois, Chicago. Zaatari's organizing and research has largely focused on international feminist movements; and on women's rights and issues in the Middle East and North Africa, particularly Lebanon.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_6868ba71a07d25ccfd2ae9e904954815" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zen, Kate</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_87</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021320</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Zen, Kate" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Zen, Kate</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_314047e4d49dd74117732f18b38231b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript, audio files, and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Minju Bae on September 29, 2020. In her interview, Kate Zen discusses the beginning of the pandemic; and how it affected her work and members of Red Canary Song. Speaking to uneven structural conditions for workers and tenants in Queens, Zen discusses the nature and impact of anti-Asian violence. She shares the story of Red Canary Song's founding and the collective's mutual aid work at the beginning of the pandemic. She also reflects on her concerns about migrant laborers; the U.S. and China trade war; and policing and urban development in New York City.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9881d5713e18f9c9abc4bd876f6dbab2"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript, audio files, and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room or remotely.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_1a41ffb814e8e3772197afdf9af86079"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Kate Zen is a sex worker rights activist; co-founder of Red Canary Song, a grassroots organization composed of Asian and migrant sex workers, as well as massage workers, who organize transnationally; and the Executive Director of the New York State Assembly Asian Pacific American Task Force.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_4e2d5338c4bc999738330b4b222e9cfa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zhang, Alex</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_88</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1021322</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2021/2021">2021</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Zhang, Alex" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Zhang, Alex</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1aadf10945ee0695a6346d0cab90fc24"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include a transcript and video files from an oral history interview conducted by Mi Hyun Yoon on March 16, 2021. In his interview, Alex Zhang speaks about his transition to a new job in the midst of the pandemic; his continuing to work remotely and having never met his coworkers in person; and what his job as a software engineer for an insurance company entails. Zhang also discusses being asked by his company to speak on a panel about anti-Asian racism and how his neighborhood in Hell's Kitchen has changed since the pandemic.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_9bb0c1990f9bc5394ba054b8e6385fa4"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>The transcript and video files of this oral history interview can be accessed in the NYU Special Collections reading room only once permission has been obtained from Alex Zhang.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist id="aspace_4a917acb4daaa3d5450c669a56daf040"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Alex Zhang is a software engineer for the insurance company Haven Life. He identifies as Chinese American and lives and works in New York City.</p></bioghist></c><c id="aspace_a575806ae421247a905da84a76c8abae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zhou, XY</unittitle><unitid>TW_TAM_837_ER_89</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/1019607</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">circa 2020</unitdate><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://hdl.handle.net/2333.1/material-request-placeholder" xlink:role="electronic-records-reading-room" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Zhou, XY" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Zhou, XY</p></daodesc></dao></did><bioghist id="aspace_c19a537b45c85cb05b7fcb1d587516fa"><head>Biographical Note</head><p>XY Zhou studied at New York University Gallatin School of Individualized Study and concentrated in art and culture, with a strong interest in writing. Zhou was raised in California's Bay Area and as the daughter of immigrant parents, she has always retained a strong tie to her cultural heritage. As a first-year student during the pandemic, she used art and writing to cope with the state of the world.</p></bioghist><scopecontent id="aspace_d1a4463a9563f70e128827767ca29b32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Materials include two zines, "A Comparative Study of Two Chinese American Women" and "The Mystery of 7th Street"; artwork; and an essay titled "What the Pandemic Reveals About America's Cult of Productivity."</p></scopecontent></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
