<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="multilevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="https://findingaids.library.nyu.edu/tamwag/wag_324/">wag_324</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records <num>WAG.324</num></titleproper><author>Rachel Schimke, 2012. Edited by Rachel Schimke for compliance with DACS and Tamiment Required Elements for Archival Description, 2013.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><p><date>May 2012</date></p><address><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>Business Number: (212) 998-2596</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-08-28 14:51:01 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>August 2019</date><item>Updated by Megan O'Shea to incorporate unprocessed photographs, archived websites, and prepare material to be sent to offsite storage</item></change><change><date>October 2023</date><item>Edited by Nicole Greenhouse for additional administration information and the incorporation of archived websites</item></change><change><date>December 2024</date><item>Edited by Weatherly Stephan to reflect deaccessioning of duplicate buttons</item></change><change><date>August 2025</date><item>Updated by Weatherly Stephan to close unprocessed boxes.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Caoile, Gloria T.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Lee, Jin Sook</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95035215" source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95035215" role="dnr" source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>WAG.324</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/1569</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">60 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 53 record cartons, 3 flat boxes, and 3 card boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">41 Digital_Betacam</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">91 VHS</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 U-matic</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 DVDs</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 audiocassettes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 CDs</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 websites</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 7 archived websites.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/2023" type="inclusive">1970s-ongoing</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1990/2010" type="bulk">1990-2010</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8781d25d51c214ff8656d00f43ea4fe9">Founded in 1992, the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) was created to address the continued underrepresentation of Asian Pacific American (APA) workers in the labor movement and the specific challenges APA workers face. The collection documents many of the activities of the national office and some of the local chapters of the APALA from its early years through 2009, as well as some of the activities of other APA organizations.  Materials date from the 1970s through 2019, with the bulk of the material dating from 1992 to 2009.  The collection includes paper and audiovisual materials regarding APALA annual conventions and events; meeting minutes; photographs of events; reports and audiovisual materials created by other APA groups; and archived versions of the APALA's websites and the Washington, DC chapter's website.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_aa78fc080a7007d574beb1236b7bae40">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_34c8fc3ad8f36325434938ea4b098dfc">Materials are primarily in English, with some materials in Chinese, Thai, Khmer, Korean, Japanese, and other Asian languages. The website is predominately in English, with some Chinese, Vietnamese, and Tagalog.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_938ec03dbcc7e61bd8eef5a19c3b529a">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>The foundations for the creation of the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) were laid in 1990 when a number of Asian Pacific American (APA) labor activists presented the AFL-CIO with a proposal to better address the continued underrepresentation of APA workers in the labor movement by forming a national APA labor organization. These activists sought to get more APA workers into unions, especially those working in historically important industries such as garment factories and restaurants. The APALA founders also recognized that, in addition to traditional workers' rights issues like fair wages and health care, APA workers face workplace discrimination and challenges related to immigration status, language ability, and education which force many Asian and Pacific Islander Americans into low-paying and insecure jobs.</p><p>In 1991, the Executive Council of the AFL-CIO formed a steering committee consisting of representatives from the three regional APA labor groups, representatives from Hawaii's AFL-CIO, and the seven founding unions to explore the rationales and practicalities of forming a national APA labor organization.</p><p>APALA became a formal entity at the National Founding Convention in 1992. Over 500 APA labor activists, representing major cities across the United States, gathered in Washington, D.C. APALA was envisioned as an organization that would address a number of pressing needs within the APA community by educating laborers, promoting political education and voter registration, and training and mentoring APA leaders within the labor movement and the greater community. In addition, it was decided that APALA would be committed to the defense and advocacy of civil and human rights of APA laborers, immigrants, and people of color, while developing ties to international labor organizations, especially those within the Asia-Pacific Rim.</p><p>With approximately 660,000 members, a national office in Washington, D.C., and 13 chapters and pre-chapters across the country, APALA remains the first and only national organization of APA union members.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_aaa9a3791d08d96ee75ceb0401fc9d27">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records document many of the activities of the national APALA office and some of its local chapters (especially the New York, San Francisco, Seattle, and Los Angeles chapters) from the organization's early years through 2009. The collection consists mostly of research and organizing materials related to APALA's various advocacy efforts in the areas of minority, immigrant, and/or workers' rights. Additionally, the APALA Records contain the activities of the executive board, convention materials, e-mail correspondence (especially correspondence written by or to Jin Sook Lee and Gloria T. Caoile, former Executive Directors of APALA) and materials related to various political and voter mobilization campaigns. The collection also includes photographic and audiovisual materials from APALA events and archived versions of the APALA's websites and the Washington, DC chapter's website.  The websites include information about national and Washington chapter APALA events, programs, and political activities.</p><p>Parts of the collection also include materials generated by the Public Services Labor Independent Confederation (PSLINK), the union for government workers in the Philippines, and the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), especially during Gloria Caoile's term as assistant to the AFSCME president. The collection also includes materials created by other APA organizations, particularly the National Council of Asian Pacific Americans (NCAPA), of which APALA is a member, and other labor groups, such as the Labor Coalition for Community Action. To a lesser extent, there are materials generated by other minority activist groups, such as the Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (CBTU).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1a93d566a380531c7ef41d5f4e889e46">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>The majority of the collection is closed pending processing due to preservation concerns. The archived websites in the collection are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c5cecb4fef172aba37d93509bdc36899">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>This collection is protected by copyright and/or related rights. You are free to use materials in the collection in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use. For other uses you need to obtain permission from the rights-holder(s).</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5d154499a750f138bce9534c96ca80ed">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>In 2012, photographs, negatives, slides, and contact sheets were removed from their original housing and placed into archival quality containers or folders. In all such cases, the original order of the materials was maintained, and any labels were copied onto the new containers or folders. Unlabeled photographs and negatives were kept in their original groupings. Folder titles added by the archivist are indicated with square brackets. In 2014, materials found in the repository were added to Box 5 of the collection.</p><p>In 2014, the archived website was added to the collection. Additional websites were added to the finding aid in 2019-2023.</p><p>In December 2024, duplicate buttons were removed from box 57. The remaining buttons were placed on foam board upright in a manuscript box.</p><p>In August 2025, the unprocessed portion of the collection was closed due to preservation concerns.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_aad0d73013b1a83e80e712f86af534d2">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Papers related to the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance can be found in the Rocky Chin Papers (WAG 325).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <prefercite id="aspace_5352488c68c87a0ad4145de4cf8ccc36">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records; WAG 324; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p><p>To cite the archived website in this collection:
Identification of item, date; sian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Records; WAG 324; Wayback URL; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="aspace_e111c4b23c9cf8890605914ce8d2ea80">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.  Materials are described at the box level.</p>  </arrangement>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_26c2be21f749544e4377bcc16722e1f2">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Approximately twenty-five issues of the <emph render="italic">APALA News</emph>, three books, and some issues of <emph render="italic">Filipinas</emph> magazine were separated for library cataloging. Some personnel documents pertaining to employee finances and health insurance and/or containing sensitive information like Social Security numbers were removed. Personal materials were returned to the donors.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ef0323d5a0729d71d26e445e6ddf464c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) in March 2012. The accession number associated with this gift is 2012.020.</p><p>A small number of publications produced by the APALA were discovered in the repository and added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.034.</p><p>Websites were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2007 as part of the Tamiment-Wagner: Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2017, crawling of two of the websites,  https://apalanet.wordpress.com/ and https://apaladc.wordpress.com/, was discontinued.  In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2019, https://www.apalaconvention.org/ was added to the web archives. The accession number associated with this website 2019.131. In 2021, https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvoun8paqpAJiP30ECBZ3sQ/videos/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.027. In March 2022, https://docs.google.com/document/d/1hFIcb_pJhJDjjK5q-9lQgu3LHGBo65kPWyfn_LM2t5Y/edit was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.049. In September 2023, https://www.youtube.com/@apalanational989/videos/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.083.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <phystech id="aspace_1ef11c47e6ff9ebd1e5c60eaf862a045">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and  Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <phystech id="aspace_20d5e7e4699c58d8682727470825cd83">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may
not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text  
searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p>  </phystech>
  <appraisal id="aspace_78c88644fc828edf38fe7879db69ef1c">
    <head>Take Down Policy</head>
<p>Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.</p><p>If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.</p><p>If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.</p><p>Please include the following in your notice:  Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature.  Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.</p>  </appraisal>
  <appraisal id="aspace_e4957bbc58bac99dcee97839318cf0b5">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Duplicate buttons in box 57 were deaccessioned in December 2024.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Minorities -- Civil rights -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Politics and government.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Minorities -- Employment -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Social conditions.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Minorities -- Education.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Race discrimination -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Employment.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Civil rights.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Asian Americans -- Economic conditions.</subject>
    <subject source="local">Asian American labor union members.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Discrimination in employment -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants -- United States -- Civil rights.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)no2002017440" source="naf">United States. President's Advisory Commission on Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95035215" source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Labor Coalition for Community Action</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">National Council of Asian Pacific Americans</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n79086831" source="naf">AFL-CIO</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)n81056646" rules="dacs" source="naf">AFSCME</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="(lccn)nr95035215" role="dnr" source="naf">Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref132" level="file"><did><unittitle>Archived Websites</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/379528</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 websites</extent><extent altrender="carrier">in 7 archived websites.</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="Captured" normal="2007-09-24/2007-09-24">September 2007-ongoing</unitdate><container id="aspace_c83ce328e19bc7d9a9697b152a7b2050" label="electronic records" type="Box">Electronic Records</container><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/http://apalanet.org/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) Archived Website: September 2007-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://apaladc.wordpress.com/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="APALA Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, AFL-CIO, Washington DC Chapter Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>APALA Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, AFL-CIO, Washington DC Chapter Archived Website: March 2014-October 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://apalanet.wordpress.com/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="APALA Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, AFL-CIO Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>APALA Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, AFL-CIO Archived Website: March 2014-September 2017</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.apalaconvention.org/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="APALA Convention Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>APALA Convention Archived Website: April 2019-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvoun8paqpAJiP30ECBZ3sQ/videos/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance YouTube Channel Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance YouTube Channel Archived Website: November 2021-March 2023</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://docs.google.com/document/d/1hFIcb_pJhJDjjK5q-9lQgu3LHGBo65kPWyfn_LM2t5Y/edit" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance COVID-19 Resources Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance COVID-19 Resources Archived Website: March 2022</p></daodesc></dao><dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6349/*/https://www.youtube.com/@apalanational989/videos/" xlink:role="external-link" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance YouTube Channel Archived Website" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance YouTube Channel Archived Website: October 2023-ongoing</p></daodesc></dao></did><scopecontent id="aspace_daf334ff5ffd903454bc32b191e53db5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Founded in 1992, the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA) was created to address the continued under-representation of Asian Pacific American (APA) workers in the labor movement and the specific challenges APA workers face. APALA works on projects related to voter registration, the DREAM Act, and workplace organizing. Incomplete captures of the website began in 2007 with information on the Employee Free Choice Act, the DREAM Act, voter mobilization efforts, biannual conventions, the Asian Pacific American Workers' Rights Hearing, and the Organizing Institute. The first complete capture of the website occurred in 2014. Then, the website focused on fundraising for victims of Typhoon Yolanda (Haiyan); Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA); citizenship rally; mentorship programs; spokesperson training; summits for young leaders and seniors and retirees; congressional voter guides; end of year reports; and other organizing and leadership trainings. In 2015, the website redesigned. The website contained information on stopping the Trans-Pacific Partnership; the All Students Count Act; educational material on immigration, worker rights, and civil rights issues that impact Asian Pacific Americans; labor and community partnerships; and chapter news pages. In 2017, the website redesigned again, with sections on civil and political engagement; organizing and leadership development; racial justice and ending mass criminalization; solidarity with global Asian and Pacific Islander communities; and corporate accountability. Other issues the organization focused on immigration and refugee policies, family immigration, undocumented workers, the census and civic engagement, Black Lives Matter protest and anti-racism resources, anti-asian violence resoueces, and their COVID-19 response and fund for Asian American and Pacific Islanders workers in healthcare, transportation and service industries.</p><p>The websites also contain information on activities and policies at the organization's national level as well as for their Washington, DC chapter.  The websites contain infomation on their executive board, youth leadership and organizing committees, press releases, news listings, convention highlights, and a blog.</p><p>The YouTube Channel for the Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance contains videos of convention panels, awards, speeches, principles for liberation, COVID-19 stories, and APALA's 25th anniversary.</p></scopecontent><phystech id="aspace_94baaab933a353f123e7c41e0ee956a4"><head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head><p>Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of  the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.</p></phystech><accruals id="aspace_4f4a257f8b8998704aa4bb9a6d3aa537"><head>Accruals</head><p>http://apalanet.org/ and https://www.apalaconvention.org/ are crawled semiannually.</p></accruals><appraisal id="aspace_56b0b598d8d95041499454eff8cd7da8"><head>Appraisal</head><p>https://www.apalanet.org/ and https://www.apalaconvention.org/ were rescoped to include the domains drive.google.com, docs.google.com, apalanet.z2systems.com, and d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net to capture the contents of the website.</p><p>In 2023, YouTube URLs were changed to better capture the videos on the channel.</p></appraisal></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
