<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">ms346_keppler_family</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Keppler Family Papers<lb/><date> 1840 - 1957 </date><lb/><num></num> <num>MS 346</num></titleproper><author>Processed by Kit Messick</author></titlestmt><editionstmt><p>This version was derived from keppler.xml</p></editionstmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><address><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>Telephone: (212) 873-3400</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.nyhistory.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.nyhistory.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-05-25 10:01:01 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in <language>English</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Keppler Family Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>MS 346</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.3 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(3 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1840-1957</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_386b0bd0e7be97a0235e8ea7757a11dd" label="Abstract">The Keppler Family Papers, 1840-1956, contain the miscellaneous personal papers of Joseph Keppler, cartoonist and founder of Puck Magazine and of his son, Udo J. Keppler, later known as Joseph Keppler, Jr. They consist of correspondence in English and German, dealing with Puck, cartoons, personal and family matters, and a wide range of other papers and printed ephemera.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <custodhist id="aspace_c218529e4a3a317a5479c266d858658d">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Donation.</p>  </custodhist>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1dabb2781797a0905d57d87a31555e7f">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Open to qualified researchers.</p><p>Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.) See guidelines in Reading room for details.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_33a01054e6a015981c996883a5f4638c">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Permission to quote from this collection in a publication must be requested and granted in writing. Send permission requests, citing the name of the collection from which you wish to quote, to <lb/><lb/>Library Director <lb/><address><addressline>The New-York Historical Society<lb/></addressline><addressline>170 Central Park West<lb/></addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024<lb/><lb/></addressline></address></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f72bd57ab736054331202f234e15bcfb">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as The Keppler Family Papers, The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="aspace_33cf8b7bd127dd1a2aec9274f2b578c2">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
    <chronlist>
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1838</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Joseph Keppler born in Vienna, Austria.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1867</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Joseph Keppler emigrates to United States.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1871</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Joseph Keppler and Adolph Schwarzmann create <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title> in St. Louis; it fails.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1872</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Udo J. Keppler born.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1876</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Joseph Keppler and Adolph Schwarzmann resurrect <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title> in New York.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1877</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>English version of <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title> begins publication.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1891</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Udo Keppler joins the staff of <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1894</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Joseph Keppler dies; Udo Keppler changes his name to Joseph Keppler, Jr. in honor of his father.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1899</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Udo Keppler elected honorary chief of Seneca Indians.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1917</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event><title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title> sold to William Randolph Hearst.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1918</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event><title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title> closes.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
      <chronitem>
        <date>1956</date>
        <eventgrp>
          <event>Udo Keppler dies in La Jolla, California.</event>
        </eventgrp>
      </chronitem>
    </chronlist>


  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_911d0ebb82a7bd87f7b9f80bb9c0c820">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection documents the personal and professional lives of Joseph F. Keppler and his son, Udo J. Keppler. The papers give insight into life in New York City in the late nineteenth to twentieth centuries, as well as describing the creation, management and eventual sale and demise of <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>.</p><p>Joseph Keppler was born in Vienna in 1838. Although he studied art, publishing his earliest political cartoons in the Austrian magazine <title render="italic">Kikeriki</title>, his initial goal was to become an actor. He performed in various plays in Austria, but his acting career was never particularly successful. He emigrated to St. Louis, Missouri, in 1867, where he became active in the German-American community, and fell in with a group of journalists, writers, and artists. With fellow émigré Adolph Schwarzmann, he tried his hand at publishing satirical magazines, an enterprise which culminated with the creation of <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>.</p><p>Joseph Keppler's papers include both his personal and legal papers, from a smallpox vaccination certificate dated from his infancy, to his fiscal records of his work at <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>. School papers, correspondence, theatrical contracts, passports and naturalization certificate are included, as are books and plays in German. Letters to his wife Pauline, from various correspondents, are also contained in the collection.</p><p>The collection also contains many materials dealing with the history and operation of <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>, one of America's first political satire and humor magazines. Initially published with Adolph Schwarzmann as a German-language weekly in St. Louis in 1871, <title render="italic">Puck</title> faired badly and quickly folded. The duo successfully reprised the magazine in New York City in 1876, with an English-language version first appearing in 1877. At first, the English-language version fared poorly and its publication was supported almost entirely by the German-language version, but later years saw the subscription rate of the English version soar as the magazine took on such controversial local topics as Tammany Hall corruption, and national issues like Ulysses S. Grant's attempt to win a third term as President. Joseph Keppler served as co-publisher and chief cartoonist for the magazine until his death from heart disease in 1894. His political cartoons were notoriously biting, garnering much attention for <title  render="italic">Puck</title>, and he was one of the first artists to use color lithography for caricature. Son Udo, born in 1872, joined the staff of Puck in 1891 as a political cartoonist, and assumed control of the magazine after his father's death. <title render="italic">Puck</title> was ultimately sold to William Randolph Hearst in 1917, who ceased publication of the magazine in 1918. Materials in the collection relating to <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title> consist of business, legal, and financial papers. Included are accounts, cancelled checks, legal contracts, and correspondence. Ephemera relating to <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>, such as broadsheets, advertisements, original magazine issues and <title render="italic">Puck</title> stationery is also included.</p><p>Joseph Keppler's son Udo is more thoroughly represented in this collection, and the bulk of the materials contained in the collection deal with his personal and professional life. Materials relating to Udo Keppler's involvement with <title render="italic">Puck</title> include correspondence, memos, accounts, land assessments and a closing statement for the sale of the Puck Building, all of which can be found in Box 1, folder 5.</p><p>Udo became active in Indian affairs around the turn of the century, and remained an activist for Native Americans until his death. In 1899, he was made an honorary Chief of the Seneca tribe and given the name Gy-ant-wa-ka. The collection contains material dealing with his Indian activism, including news clippings, personal correspondence, and letters acknowledging bequests of Indian artifacts from Udo Keppler to various museums. </p><p>The bulk of the material relating to Udo Keppler in this collection takes the form of personal correspondence. Letters from other artists and cartoonists like Joe Scheuerle and Art Young are included, many containing original drawings, as well as a number of letters from miscellaneous authors. The correspondence spans the late 19th century through Udo's death in 1956, and contains an extensive collection of sympathy letters written to Keppler's wife Vera upon his death, as well as other memorial materials and obituaries. A group of letters to Vera Keppler from Draper Hill describes the development and writing process of his dissertation on the life and career of Udo Keppler in 1957.</p><p>After his father's death, Udo legally changed his name to Joseph Keppler, Jr. and many of the items in the collection are addressed in this fashion. In personal correspondence, he is often referred to by a variety of nicknames, including "Kep" and "Chief." There are also items addressed to his Indian name, Gy-ant-wa-ka.</p><p>Miscellaneous materials belonging to Udo Keppler filed at the end of the collection include a commonplace book and a large quantity of newspaper clippings relating to <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>, obituaries of family members and fellow cartoonists, and an assortment of prose and poetry. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b6b98d3ce978d19e283869bdb55d0142">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized into the following seven series:</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <head>Missing Title</head>
      <item>I. Joseph Keppler: Business and Legal Papers</item>
      <item>II. <title render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>: Business and Legal Papers</item>
      <item>III. Joseph Keppler: Miscellaneous Materials</item>
      <item>IV. Udo J. Keppler: Papers</item>
      <item>V. Udo J. Keppler: Correspondence</item>
      <item>VI. Udo J. Keppler: Memorial Materials</item>
      <item>VII. Udo J. Keppler: Miscellaneous Materials</item>
    </list>
<p>Material is arranged by family member and type of material. Items within the folders are chronological, with undated material at the end.</p>  </arrangement>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f9b4f0703e0316b72f5e495098fbda5d">
    <head>Related Material at The New-York Historical Society</head>
<p>The Department of Paintings, Sculpture, and Decorative Arts of the New-York Historical Society has non-cartoon drawings and paintings by both men, the elder Keppler's death mask, and other material. Secondary sources on the works of Joseph and Udo Keppler are held in the collections of the New-York Historical Society Library.</p><p> Keppler, Joseph. [ca. 1860]-1950. Joseph Keppler cartoon collection. Dept. of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections, The New-York Historical Society. </p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Stock certificates.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Prompt cooks</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Certificates.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Sympathy cards</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Christmas cards.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Autograph albums</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">German American periodicals.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Seneca Nation.</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Legal documents.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Ephemera.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Tintypes (prints)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Accounts.</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Broadsides (notices)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Playbills</genreform>
    <persname source="naf">Keppler, Udo J., 1872-1956</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Lambert, Samuel W. (Samuel Waldron), 1859-1942</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Miller, E. Jennie</persname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">Puck (Magazine)</corpname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Pulitzer, Joseph, 1847-1911</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Scheuerle, Joe, 1873-1948</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Urban, Hermann, 1866-</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Young, Art, 1866-1943</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Dana, Charles A. (Charles Anderson), 1819-1897</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Hamilton, Grant E.</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Hill, Draper</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Keppler, Joseph Ferdinand, 1838-1894</persname>
    <persname rules="rda" source="local">Keppler, Joseph, Mrs., Jr.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref16_beq" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Joseph Keppler: Business and Legal Papers</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c05b0be41b36e9096db0013421a3a18f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Series 1 consists of the personal, business, and legal papers of Joseph Keppler, 1840-1894. Includes school papers, correspondence, legal documents and contracts, passports, naturalization certificate, books and ephemera.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref17_6qs" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Joseph Keppler: Miscellaneous Papers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1838 - 1894</unitdate><container id="aspace_f21f6fc6caae49b9d1bc01cb139b0f67" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_a1c45b29aa5d62b1dbf98105be4b0a29" parent="aspace_f21f6fc6caae49b9d1bc01cb139b0f67" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref18_tk1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Joseph Keppler: Letters received</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1856 - 1894</unitdate><container id="aspace_36aa07c2a3ecd1937485b3d0d79cba83" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_01c766ff1930cf73914c26a0b415c763" parent="aspace_36aa07c2a3ecd1937485b3d0d79cba83" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref19_04a" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Mrs. Joseph Keppler: Letters received</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1894</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea17d8656926b605c72ebf3ddab59843" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_16b66c7a9b70605c91e63fc565d6161e" parent="aspace_ea17d8656926b605c72ebf3ddab59843" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref20_18q" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Joseph Keppler: Obituaries</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1894</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ff6f7157073a2c77fe58078f9925f6e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_09779fa43b7b898c079a966ddfb9ab10" parent="aspace_3ff6f7157073a2c77fe58078f9925f6e" type="Folder">4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref22_rlf" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Puck Magazine</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ee468f739f544bf424ab7693032558f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Consists of business, legal, and financial recordss related to Puck Magazine and its operations. Includes accounts, cancelled checks, legal contracts, and correspondence. Ephemera relating to <title type="simple" render="italic">Puck Magazine</title>, such as broadsheets, advertisements, magazine issues and Puck stationery is also included.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref23_5nz" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Puck Magazine: Business records</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1876 - 1847</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab2f234f5752398e96d3e28b60022178" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_ba795f9e6fcca64c09605f82b3398004" parent="aspace_ab2f234f5752398e96d3e28b60022178" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref24_fv7" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Puck Magazine: Ephemera</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1877 - 1910, ND.</unitdate><container id="aspace_846cd8d6123bb51d4ba18d721de12027" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_5f3641c3d14bc92fb499f8ddfc7512ba" parent="aspace_846cd8d6123bb51d4ba18d721de12027" type="Folder">6</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref26_sp9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Keppler Family Miscellaneous Materials</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ebe8a87a3c26a8b7f51fd107abf3d719"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Miscellaneous materials belonging to members of the Keppler family, particularly Joseph Keppler. Includes books, plays, artifacts, a commonplace book, and the first dollar earned by Joseph Keppler in the United States, framed. Some materials are in German. Note: miscellaneous materials relating to Udo Keppler are listed separately, under series seven.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref27_k33" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Keppler Family: Miscellaneous Materials</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1851 - 1886, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_972e494e0f377fb5d042e9d8be9640a5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_01037f2ebbbe1e6f287e58c403686590" parent="aspace_972e494e0f377fb5d042e9d8be9640a5" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref28_3t6" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Keppler Family: Books and Ephemera</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">ca. 1867 - ca. 1881, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_d19d95571712f4f975a779aedc71eb7d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_6e0fe370b84b3df62d34a75f8431f473" parent="aspace_d19d95571712f4f975a779aedc71eb7d" type="Folder">8</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref30_e6n" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Udo J. Keppler: Papers</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c9a582c13475a568c443c2375b9323f0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>The personal papers of Udo J. Keppler, son of Joseph Keppler. Includes schoolwork, certificates, passport, Inwood Improvement Association papers, and papers relating to Keppler's participation in Indian affairs and activities with the Iroquois Nation and Seneca tribe. In chronological order</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref31_klm" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Papers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1880 - 1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_12da6a2f230f703a3f443553489cc9e8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_54ab690ae09f395e71bfcba7d8fbdff0" parent="aspace_12da6a2f230f703a3f443553489cc9e8" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref32_3ve" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Papers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1902 - 1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_1331262f2a0f3c98b6a318234276d89f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_44ee8094e65c1b91630074c8dec0e769" parent="aspace_1331262f2a0f3c98b6a318234276d89f" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref33_z3q" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Papers Relating to Indian Relations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1899 - 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6c86eca5c99e6e8847461ea95d98dc2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_14ad68e3ed98e221785b496e0d76620a" parent="aspace_a6c86eca5c99e6e8847461ea95d98dc2" type="Folder">11</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref35_ecv" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Udo J. Keppler: Correspondence</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3aeea7318399f9bb8595ef173a78b258"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondence of Udo Keppler. Correspondents with multiple letters under their name are arranged alphabetically in separate folders, followed by miscellaneous correspondence in chronological order. Note that Keppler is called variously Udo, Joseph, "Kep," "Chief," and Gy-ant-wa-ka (his Indian name after being elected Seneca Chief).</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_ref36_jsv" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 1: Puck-related Correspondence</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref37_ywj" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Puck-related correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1894 - 1954, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b9145ff3cc96a8eb41bd276c3abcf8e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_fb5c41b5326055680db00d4bc9a0d595" parent="aspace_9b9145ff3cc96a8eb41bd276c3abcf8e" type="Folder">1</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref38_gl7" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 2: Letters Received</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref39_2lb" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Reid Carr</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1894 - 1954, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5f0a1f92470f58868156498e9705e34" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_86f46c9f4d78ac42a5e3f0e930878ee9" parent="aspace_b5f0a1f92470f58868156498e9705e34" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref40_12v" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Granadiscus</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1948 - 1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_b02a6b0234633968407c5337be19b84c" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_d2e8925b4e5d08adb1e192e2ca7570bd" parent="aspace_b02a6b0234633968407c5337be19b84c" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref41_4ni" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, A.H. Folwell</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_dcc0a26a1c3b54a9c5796ff168e30678" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_d7ac21b03f5790cb03c69d51b1d9c81f" parent="aspace_dcc0a26a1c3b54a9c5796ff168e30678" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref42_7t0" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Grant E. Hamilton</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1913 - 1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc1d63d12e7cd75298295739b11ceae1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_544eccfaf44de245759544f6eb3a934b" parent="aspace_dc1d63d12e7cd75298295739b11ceae1" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref43_604" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Anna Keim</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1937 - 1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbb238fe6107e70f1aa8874e833aee78" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_46ea0406744e5abfa60d14c48940336f" parent="aspace_bbb238fe6107e70f1aa8874e833aee78" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref44_kyo" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Irma-Joe Kiene</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1947 - 1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_f470418803e4e8c482cd5c8c14200266" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_2674d926e4d555006948bef4133ec5a5" parent="aspace_f470418803e4e8c482cd5c8c14200266" type="Folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref45_m1r" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Joseph Keppler</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1890 - 1891</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac78e423e84339b1cd1476eb6e02d5be" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4103f218ccae3c86df7194dee09a770d" parent="aspace_ac78e423e84339b1cd1476eb6e02d5be" type="Folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref46_i9y" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Theodore Roosevelt</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1903 - 1908</unitdate><container id="aspace_105967317832ce7306dc45ed88cb014f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_1d0b353e64811a046b6bd99d7d519a5a" parent="aspace_105967317832ce7306dc45ed88cb014f" type="Folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref47_scl" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Joe Scheuerle</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1945 - 1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa72815ded57fde3358ec54afae880e2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_28529d6062ef9ea7e5616b9135f92552" parent="aspace_aa72815ded57fde3358ec54afae880e2" type="Folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref48_g3b" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Hermann and Frau Urban</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1929 - 1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_6be36bd209dcbff3882006d74834a21f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_1efc0797d9683238cb606bd90ba10eaa" parent="aspace_6be36bd209dcbff3882006d74834a21f" type="Folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref49_3wi" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Frank Weitzencamp</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1924 - 1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2fdc38df7f4621f08897916f1c543c0" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_ab9a842a5c4e61c3a53b7738c69e6434" parent="aspace_b2fdc38df7f4621f08897916f1c543c0" type="Folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref50_lkj" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Art Young</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1919 - 1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1efab0a6f0aa87742ddcf8749ca3ff7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_eb6732f743564bb30f4bb23635908041" parent="aspace_a1efab0a6f0aa87742ddcf8749ca3ff7" type="Folder">13</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref51_hxc" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1888 - 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_725e303b1b8c914ee63c888b009d18b1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_18c4b4f3ce9b011531bb5128df62190b" parent="aspace_725e303b1b8c914ee63c888b009d18b1" type="Folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref52_0v1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo Keppler: Letters Received, Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1841 - 1957, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d51aec57dffd0a98916b2cf0c8cc2c7" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_b7fdfb9805b3949503660743a06e8075" parent="aspace_8d51aec57dffd0a98916b2cf0c8cc2c7" type="Folder">15</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref53_eax" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 3: Letters Regarding Museum and Library Bequests</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref54_hc2" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Letters Regarding Museum and Library Bequests</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1921 - 1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3224c26724ec73fa7ad5b384da3ee45" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_dea36f243d0742733359360a54fd984e" parent="aspace_d3224c26724ec73fa7ad5b384da3ee45" type="Folder">16</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref55_cs9" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 4: Udo J. Keppler: Letters Sent</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref56_72t" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Udo J. Keppler: Letters Sent</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1943 - 1954, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_937b59a70316521d39e14dacdcf0c68e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_4a297d31ffba3001b7606da8562fd1e5" parent="aspace_937b59a70316521d39e14dacdcf0c68e" type="Folder">17</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref57_b5f" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Subseries 5: Letters to Mrs. Vera Keppler from Draper Hill</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref58_ghj" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Letters to Mrs. Vera Keppler from Draper Hill</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_22645b6a6c8553146b364cb0818fd70f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_59d036711d9bb0b25fb99c4bd786dd07" parent="aspace_22645b6a6c8553146b364cb0818fd70f" type="Folder">18</container></did></c></c></c><c id="aspace_ref60_ez2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Udo J. Keppler Memorial Materials</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref61_7z5" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Vera Keppler</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1956 - 1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_483302a05d31c83201201457a1f67d12" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_fc38d0fac4c7d634cf458a0ce1e06321" parent="aspace_483302a05d31c83201201457a1f67d12" type="Folder">19</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref62_il9" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Sympathy cards</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_47e379695dd6390f044818fedf0ca4ca" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_7828e1f30d08325ed31f1d4af5a61232" parent="aspace_47e379695dd6390f044818fedf0ca4ca" type="Folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref63_utv" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Cards from funeral flowers, wreath banners</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_8705eb0b257b46adde720ec0ebda3e1d" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_85c06bed5c4ea199d12110d204fe1df7" parent="aspace_8705eb0b257b46adde720ec0ebda3e1d" type="Folder">21</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref64_w19" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Memorial records</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3be87361de31dd609faf35be5661368" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container id="aspace_20184f4ddd17ad3ebaf655a5fde274ef" parent="aspace_b3be87361de31dd609faf35be5661368" type="Folder">22</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ref65_kph" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII: Udo J. Keppler Miscellaneous Materials</unittitle></did><c id="aspace_ref66_rfr" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Commonplace Book</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">Ca. 1872</unitdate><container id="aspace_dbc55a9298f1e88a300a36e31cd0cecb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_50c57171e72ba0eaa8996cf546c85e8f" parent="aspace_dbc55a9298f1e88a300a36e31cd0cecb" type="Folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref67_yff" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous Ephemera</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1884 - 1959, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ea8cfd6c585eb4322216ff7e56d0b84" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_a022b04cb71b713bf1b5b71a30bdcd9d" parent="aspace_2ea8cfd6c585eb4322216ff7e56d0b84" type="Folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref68_jhx" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Museum periodicals and exhibition guides</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1938 - 1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ba8a3663d51b5858407ca1570842dbc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_150b1682a6b10beaf2fcd63b2ade2c34" parent="aspace_1ba8a3663d51b5858407ca1570842dbc" type="Folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref69_l4k" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Clippings: Puck-related</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1899 - 1957, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_ade2e06cd916c6597218981f09542500" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_e0596e6fd9bcdd1bd186c455f2e30b30" parent="aspace_ade2e06cd916c6597218981f09542500" type="Folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref70_wy4" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Clippings: Obituaries</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1927 - 1951, nd</unitdate><container id="aspace_74c5de8301e839dc0fd355cb54b2ccae" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_6994bdcab55badd57311721f954f8f9d" parent="aspace_74c5de8301e839dc0fd355cb54b2ccae" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref71_9do" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Clippings: Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_21dd1a12301c5a9497800918d803efd6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_2361837fc51bf3a8698845ae5df37089" parent="aspace_21dd1a12301c5a9497800918d803efd6" type="Folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref72_2lx" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="unspecified"><did><unittitle>Memorial Box</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_45cd4592f12eb03b5f5a0b45d5ac85d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container><container id="aspace_fca24225963c4d50f560ace2602b5a08" parent="aspace_45cd4592f12eb03b5f5a0b45d5ac85d2" type="Folder">7</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
