<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NHi">nyhs_archives_rg25</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the New-York Historical Society Development Office Records <lb/>
1956-2012 (bulk, 1982-1990s)<lb/> <num>NYHS-RG 25</num></titleproper><author>Larry Weimer</author><sponsor><emph render="bold">This record group was processed as part of the 2015-2016 N-YHS Institutional Archives project, made possible by a generous grant from the Leon Levy Foundation.</emph></sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>New-York Historical Society</publisher><p><date>December 2016; updated August 2021</date></p><address><addressline>170 Central Park West</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10024</addressline><addressline>Telephone: (212) 873-3400</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.nyhistory.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.nyhistory.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-05-25 10:05:36 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>New-York Historical Society Development Office records (RESTRICTED)</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>NYHS-RG 25</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">47.25 Linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 68 boxes of various sizes and 5 boxes of oversize computer print-outs</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1956-2012 (bulk, 1982-1990s)</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4ca46ef20fdf5170fd1b8683abcccb7c">The Development Office records include files concerning N-YHS's fundraising initiatives for exhibitions, collections conservation and preservation, cataloging, education programs, publications, physical plant improvements, general operating support, and other purposes. Sources of grants and other funds documented in the record group include government agencies, foundations, corporations, trustees, other individuals, memberships, and benefit events. The bulk of the records date from the 1980s and the early 1990s, with some files ranging back to the 1950s.The record group has not yet been vetted by the Development Office for public use and is therefore currently restricted.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_65e96bf5d425f6059670220791d3aef8">Materials are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_dcaf31127a06ee67e65bff4281ca9280">The documents in the record group are in English.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6a033511d5f8aaeebf75d8633bf7a723">
    <head>Arrangement Note</head>
<p>The Development Office records are organized in six series:</p><p>Series I. Grants, 1974-1993</p><p>Series II. Subject Files, 1982-1997</p><p>Series III. Prospect &amp; Donor Files, 1956-1996</p><p>Series IV. Contribution Records, 1983-1993</p><p>Series V. Membership Director's Records, 1983-1993</p><p>Series VI. Event Collateral Files, 1990s-2010s</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_21d66351565c87b3575a09bb400e4bc7">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>The Development Office record group remains restricted because it has not been reviewed with the Office to determine which records may be made publicly available.</p><p>Materials are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_aef8796070dd10f1f250a0a7386cd9c0">
    <head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.</p><p>Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.</p><p>Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions">https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8dd9de0759088311d7d6bab416f5a8bf">
    <head>Preferred Citation Note</head>
<p>This collection should be cited as the New-York Historical Society Development Office records (NYHS-RG 25), The New-York Historical Society.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f9d45f4b0615a7e4eb58536c7e058175">
    <head>Related Archival Materials Note</head>
<p>This finding aid relates to just one record group of the New-York Historical Society archives. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/nyhs/nyhsrgarchives/">Guide to the New-York Historical Society Archives</extref> (NYHS-RG Archives). Other record groups that are processed and available to researchers and are especially related to the New-York Historical Society Development Office records
(NYHS-RG 25) are as follows:</p><p>Both the New-York Historical Society Museum Department records (NYHS-RG 20) and the New-York Historical Society Library Department records (NYHS-RG 21) include files concerning grants and the grant-funded exhibitions, projects and other initiatives</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3f2692f0ddbf4f900bca940aeadcf888">
    <head>Scope and Contents Note</head>
<p>The Development Office records include files concerning N-YHS's fundraising initiatives for exhibitions, collections conservation and preservation, cataloging, education programs, publications (including catalogues and the <emph render="italic">Encyclopedia of New York City</emph>), physical plant improvements, general operating support, and other purposes. Sources of grants and other funds documented in the record group include government agencies, foundations, corporations, trustees, other individuals, memberships, and benefit events (including the first History Makers galas, held in 1988 and 1989). The bulk of the records date from the 1980s to the 1990s, with some files ranging back to the 1950s.</p><p>The records include files of grant applications (both approved and declined) and related correspondence and reports, subject files for specific fundraising objectives and events, corporate and foundation prospect files, donor contribution records, and membership event and benefit logistical arrangements.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accruals id="aspace_ed2dc6355beb20014ddb95ee0c53b573">
    <head>Accruals Note</head>
<p>Further accruals to the record group are expected over time.</p>  </accruals>
  <processinfo id="aspace_bc33df55fb21089f8fa0e9f0ac1a2c99">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The record group has been minimally processed. The bulk (Series I through V) were processed in 2016 by archivist Larry Weimer during the project funded by the Leon Levy Foundation. An additional accession was received from the Development Office in 2019 and this was added to the finding aid by Weimer in August 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Fund raising</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Grants-in-aid.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Learned institutions and societies -- New York (State)  -- New York. </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- History -- Societies, etc.</geogname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society -- Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society -- Benefactors.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="naf">New-York Historical Society -- Correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname rules="rda" source="local">New-York Historical Society. Development Office</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_ref1_oys" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Grants</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.25 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation">1974-1993</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6712bd491a13a49232cc7aab904229b0"><head>Scope and Contents Note</head><p>This series includes grant applications and related instructions, correspondence, drafts, working files, acknowledgements, interim and final reports, and other documents. The files include both grant requests approved and declined/rejected. The grants pertain almost entirely to government grants, with only occasional reference to foundation or other private grants. These files include grant requests for conservation and preservation, cataloging, exhibitions, educational programs, and general operating support. The container list includes more specific references as to content at the box and folder level. The bulk of the material dates from the 1980s, especially the mid to late 1980s. A few files date from the late 1970s and early 1980s, and a few date from the early 1990s. Although the bulk of the files appear to have come from the Development Department, many of the files in the final box of the series, from the early 1990s, appear to have come from the files of N-YHS President Barbara Knowles Debs, and were likely moved here by a processing archivist in the early 2000s.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_da942068b4393071cac9f790507f8ac1"><head>Arrangement Note</head><p>With minor exception, the files are in original order as found during processing in December 2016. Although the series is arranged by grant funding organization, there appear to be four rough sets of the files: first, a set of core files from the Development Office; second, a set of what appears to be mostly rejected applications; third, a set of various files likely found after the first two sets were boxed for storage; and a fourth with later (early 1990s) material. The Bond Act files, found separately by the processing archivist in 2016, were added to the end of the series.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_65c42ee464b02cf75e7d4ca7c0621cc1"><head>Processing Information Note</head><p>The bulk of the series was processed in 2016 by project archivist Larry Weimer. The series was minimally processed and so most of the files remain in their original folders.</p></processinfo><c id="aspace_ref4_4k9" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Council for the Humanities (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1983-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea4f4794f4cdcf8b9d4fcb947164cad8" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019893]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container id="aspace_b265c122e86f4c8ba0e6e86f2d7440b9" parent="aspace_ea4f4794f4cdcf8b9d4fcb947164cad8" type="Folder">1-3</container></did><odd id="aspace_4f838e1ffc5a8b312a9288d6b7249256"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes photo survey proposal (declined) and film on Theresa Bernstein.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref6_k8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York City Department of Cultural Affairs (6 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1985-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba8a5e9a50653c15043ddbca10173b92" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019893]" type="Offsite-Box">1</container><container id="aspace_cb9e556acffa084b0b992bad5b450709" parent="aspace_ba8a5e9a50653c15043ddbca10173b92" type="Folder">4-9</container></did><odd id="aspace_43b1c4e33998498bcc91afbf04c9076f"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes public services/programs and education funding.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref8_nvh" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Council on the Arts (10 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1986-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_533929a93dc10ec3c1d9c5b895936fac" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019894]" type="Offsite-Box">2</container><container id="aspace_5a8e36a05468685b89d57f0a3fa4fd28" parent="aspace_533929a93dc10ec3c1d9c5b895936fac" type="Folder">1-10</container></did><odd id="aspace_666feaa9b3632462c794144e8e1a7bdf"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes exhibition planning, collections maintenance, Calyo audience survey, Luman Reed frames, paper conservation studio.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref10_boq" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Council on the Arts (7 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1978-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_b473a31ef71590d2ecb74f667e9508e7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019895]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container id="aspace_e8ccdb3b08ee60f44a2388584e693c9a" parent="aspace_b473a31ef71590d2ecb74f667e9508e7" type="Folder">1-7</container></did><odd id="aspace_e158eb926b1787fbccfbc076a826bc5b"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes Bracklow, de Tocqueville, de Neuville, and other exhibitions, and furniture conservation.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref12_r2z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Institute of Museum Services (IMS)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f2c247cfac60aba55e838ae3c5953d6" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019895]" type="Offsite-Box">3</container><container id="aspace_7759170f64c5454758ffa2df4bdcf97b" parent="aspace_0f2c247cfac60aba55e838ae3c5953d6" type="Folder">8</container></did><odd id="aspace_c26a3422bf2fede29d1fa46e9c58ddd7"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes furniture conservation.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref14_duv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Institute of Museum Services (IMS) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1987-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_29c30f319edd5fdfcafcb9718a4f5cff" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019896]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container id="aspace_2bc5f9b14867ed97dad9158619aa19fd" parent="aspace_29c30f319edd5fdfcafcb9718a4f5cff" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><odd id="aspace_02385b75d3e8d8c5d22c1f1604d1f6fe"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes painting and paper conservation labs (includes floor plan).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref16_2y3" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) (6 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1982-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a81f876f61f1b1079fc2574ff45b7e1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019896]" type="Offsite-Box">4</container><container id="aspace_9d2e344e1ff7d3c92f360bb8f56880ef" parent="aspace_9a81f876f61f1b1079fc2574ff45b7e1" type="Folder">3-8</container></did><odd id="aspace_e64c171f7db55bcbb6880d7840849510"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes conservation (hot table), exhibitions (Niagara; Bracklow; American Landscape Painting, Genre Art &amp; Drawing (includes photographs); and Nieuw Amsterdam), and development of a narrated slide presentation as an introduction to N-YHS's collections.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref18_43k" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) (8 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1974-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad7bda03a2ab80adbd380d8abc392f64" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019897]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container id="aspace_ad07b54d962a41cf8a670ecb1fd983ec" parent="aspace_ad7bda03a2ab80adbd380d8abc392f64" type="Folder">1-8</container></did><odd id="aspace_20eb28897ee0a857304387a8382eaa13"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes storage space renovation, Audubon installation, conservation of paintings, catalogue of paintings, survey and exhibitions of furniture and other decorative arts objects, and <emph render="italic">Manhattan Now</emph> exhibition.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref20_iri" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9cd5ad158d4f3f927944ef66477de19" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019897]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container id="aspace_13b8f929e174ecce0e6609aeb0bb1888" parent="aspace_d9cd5ad158d4f3f927944ef66477de19" type="Folder">9</container></did><odd id="aspace_43d2035e793ed9e77372a76262f66d53"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes mock Constitutional Conventions for school age students, an outgrowth of the Summer Institutes.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref22_smr" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Department of Education (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1987-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1068d96b18f4631610947d1781268ef" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019897]" type="Offsite-Box">5</container><container id="aspace_719bd768d5a94f178533f7149dfd2521" parent="aspace_b1068d96b18f4631610947d1781268ef" type="Folder">10-12</container></did><odd id="aspace_124fc06ac434ba4a4f692151acc367a8"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes Henry O'Reilly collection processing, American Art Union and Daniel Ullman preservation microfilming, and conservation of McComb City Hall drawings.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref24_su1" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1986-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_16934e2988f9c56f62462a1cfeae84ee" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019898]" type="Offsite-Box">6</container><container id="aspace_8d2bab704808df34cad706f19c9e79db" parent="aspace_16934e2988f9c56f62462a1cfeae84ee" type="Folder">1-4</container></did><odd id="aspace_de89d15c0b5ab02c1fb55214d607a329"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes conservation of Nicolino Calyo paintings and funding for the exhibition <emph render="italic">Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution</emph>, including photographs of documents used in the exhibition.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref26_9pi" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_02b20f23b915f3aed517360fec8e2df0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019899]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container id="aspace_0a8154a18fa914ecc3fa8d0687479604" parent="aspace_02b20f23b915f3aed517360fec8e2df0" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><odd id="aspace_2bfb2c03242b2b9de1094fad19a0cd4f"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes newspaper cataloging and exhibition <emph render="italic">Centuries of Childhood in New York</emph>, including photographic contact sheets and negatives of the galleries.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref28_p8u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Encyclopedia of New York City</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1985-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_13ab6d9c2db7133592f8bec8953a28d3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019899]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container id="aspace_ade048ee111b624e6c97e2a16af40782" parent="aspace_13ab6d9c2db7133592f8bec8953a28d3" type="Folder">3</container></did><odd id="aspace_a6f6964c88469941b0ce7d513bf981b5"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes correspondence concerning fundraising for this project. See also the files below in Series II.B (Subject Files).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref30_vkq" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Historical Publications Records Commission (NHPRC)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b454cda9ec1f20d4a8d63966dd45c0f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019899]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container id="aspace_cc0e78a0204c4aa62b49b65bad640111" parent="aspace_8b454cda9ec1f20d4a8d63966dd45c0f" type="Folder">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_1eeb4cbbcf4b3323a97165be06b5a538"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes architectural collections.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref32_1ib" level="file"><did><unittitle>Summer History Institute</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1986-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_4aeb43cb7e0362ea47f99d22115af4cb" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019899]" type="Offsite-Box">7</container><container id="aspace_c392a7be781af53ed26b76b551e9a6b5" parent="aspace_4aeb43cb7e0362ea47f99d22115af4cb" type="Folder">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_12b3b892d421ddb5355b24dcfebed352"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes plans, proposals, correspondence, etc. related to general fundraising for the program.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref34_irs" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States Department of Justice. Sharing the Spirit (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1988-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_a707d017ab681636e4195e42c4c080be" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019900]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container id="aspace_59e3a6891b5dbe8ea374fa05373759da" parent="aspace_a707d017ab681636e4195e42c4c080be" type="Folder">1-4</container></did><odd id="aspace_c584182bdc3b58fc4c595201497a16ea"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes programs funded by DOJ's Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution, including the radio series "Constitution on the Air" and "The Bicentennial Connection."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref36_dex" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States Department of Education. Summer History Institute</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a7c280b2dab06165413a8eb077c6172" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019900]" type="Offsite-Box">8</container><container id="aspace_1a7d0a1034f00f93b7ae4b3aa87e694a" parent="aspace_8a7c280b2dab06165413a8eb077c6172" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref37_lxf" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States Department of Education. (7 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1984-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3bedadf678e2450c2cee5083cadca6e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019901]" type="Offsite-Box">9</container><container id="aspace_0b1edf010f8e8ca4319f1570d13dfff9" parent="aspace_d3bedadf678e2450c2cee5083cadca6e" type="Folder">1-7</container></did><odd id="aspace_50a694203fb48cfa3b93b4107efcc2df"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes book, manuscript and map cataloging, Rufus King Library conservation and cataloging, and Landauer Collection conservation. Funding for some of these appears to have been declined.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref39_nga" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rejected Applications (11 of 13 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1977-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_6289c6b12f5bdc13af86827240d72f19" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019902]" type="Offsite-Box">10</container><container id="aspace_10d54c046f75fc520d238dafe94d3b0c" parent="aspace_6289c6b12f5bdc13af86827240d72f19" type="Folder">1-11</container></did><odd id="aspace_74c17e2446a1a5b5398f8a37159f2b5b"><head>General Note</head><p>All the files in this box appear to be unsuccessful or general information files. Includes NEH (U.S. photograph survey, Landauer collection, conservation survey, Luman Reed planning, Rivey painting conservation) and NEA (China Trade exhibition, paintings storage).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref41_g6t" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rejected Applications (2 of 13 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_414b0a688687e3f0e80ed01eb8a55f29" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019903]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container id="aspace_1110bda143d9bd6d8b2786bd06a8948e" parent="aspace_414b0a688687e3f0e80ed01eb8a55f29" type="Folder">1-2</container></did><odd id="aspace_fac273a015bd9c92e3a4f65d0e457504"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes NEA (paper conservation studio, architectural collections).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref43_wck" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) (2 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1988-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_41f7a6926133b124cb278b369b4124b3" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019903]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container id="aspace_8a13811873597c47f832a38dd1810100" parent="aspace_41f7a6926133b124cb278b369b4124b3" type="Folder">3-4</container></did><odd id="aspace_b61018505eec39f7b8866783571f6de0"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes conservation of Catlin drawings and exhibition <emph render="italic">500 Years of American Clothing</emph>.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref45_3fw" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1bd179e341c60a39b0ab193a4449b7e" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019903]" type="Offsite-Box">11</container><container id="aspace_1da0a5d44d146acc74b281e410675af7" parent="aspace_a1bd179e341c60a39b0ab193a4449b7e" type="Folder">5</container></did><odd id="aspace_26b7e1250326f5dccd89fb45deb38bfc"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes conservation planning for Audubon drawings (declined).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref47_dny" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_a42b42b228a16c59132bd680f0aa70cc" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019904]" type="Offsite-Box">12</container><container id="aspace_095df5f2ea0ef03dd1719f9c05c6a8c6" parent="aspace_a42b42b228a16c59132bd680f0aa70cc" type="Folder">1-5</container></did><odd id="aspace_3d1438c79f3f49bc3b565432fdfc35aa"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes physical plant renovations (declined), cataloging of silver collection (declined), and cataloging and preservation of Cass Gilbert collection.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref49_lty" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Department of Education (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1986-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_1449ec75f6af4c3aaaf7bce3df60d2a1" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019905]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container id="aspace_0c89206e7440545cd253e3975f2e1313" parent="aspace_1449ec75f6af4c3aaaf7bce3df60d2a1" type="Folder">1-3</container></did><odd id="aspace_b3f68ea4942f74ea779ef428b8b8c273"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes conservation of McComb City Hall drawings and conservation of maps (declined).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref51_a35" level="file"><did><unittitle>United States Department of Education</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_dfcc3034e6868f9ff40338985d41bfc7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019905]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container id="aspace_73d5184be6503c7cf0f158c3558aa72f" parent="aspace_dfcc3034e6868f9ff40338985d41bfc7" type="Folder">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_5def592fb17b0c717b1fc5ef192dfa42"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes map cataloging.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref53_tai" level="file"><did><unittitle>Institute of Museum Services (IMS) (4 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1982-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_6224e05d0f86de6d42cdf97d4f3737c2" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019905]" type="Offsite-Box">13</container><container id="aspace_a7bf588039253aacae31fb06421bea69" parent="aspace_6224e05d0f86de6d42cdf97d4f3737c2" type="Folder">5-8</container></did><odd id="aspace_1a8cb226f3e26b16dd7fe9a6f97fd3ad"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes general operating support and paper conservation studio.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref55_s0x" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Council on the Arts (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1976-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3da2a3db077bbe4341d23785f8cb7a7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019906]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container id="aspace_723234b1884cad587316ea94dc50bb4d" parent="aspace_c3da2a3db077bbe4341d23785f8cb7a7" type="Folder">1-3</container></did><odd id="aspace_975dcf3fa0e8f2daad2ca77cf2058f31"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes arts-in-education requests and "Why History?" and other programs.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref58_yw2" level="file"><did><unittitle>New State State Library</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_900dd6a6ca08ca3c1c5daa89fa73eb46" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019906]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container id="aspace_0b481c2bd800f558dcd9b2a232bcf0bb" parent="aspace_900dd6a6ca08ca3c1c5daa89fa73eb46" type="Folder">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_48c07f642f38d2b70ea3c08314285ba7"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes acknowledgement of grant for conservation of Erskine-DeWitt maps.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref65_225" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Council for the Humanities</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_4babfa4b1f57489adcca56a3b50cee6d" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019906]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container id="aspace_d2d481120073a074e0e9f43798261957" parent="aspace_4babfa4b1f57489adcca56a3b50cee6d" type="Folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ref60_fv3" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) (5 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_8faff5f11efc83f962979ffcf4b62eea" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019906]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container id="aspace_ce5d9a6d035c447303b203274006bfc2" parent="aspace_8faff5f11efc83f962979ffcf4b62eea" type="Folder">6-10</container></did><odd id="aspace_2822e64a7faca44d390b61e38cd49684"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes Cass Gilbert, photograph database, and other proposals.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref62_u0h" level="file"><did><unittitle>Institute of Museum Services (IMS) (3 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_a85dc60a5df89ff51af18ca0821eee69" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019906]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container id="aspace_ef1c68a2e06230488ebdcb8d442652f0" parent="aspace_a85dc60a5df89ff51af18ca0821eee69" type="Folder">11-13</container></did><odd id="aspace_6b77c52911c42e78c014c03f0f0ecab1"><head>General Note</head><p>Includes conservation and general operating support.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref64_cav" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (8 folders)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ea63208a962fe8d990ab1da5a16b1e7" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019906]" type="Offsite-Box">14</container><container id="aspace_5a42698fc5699a5b895f260702c64fb3" parent="aspace_6ea63208a962fe8d990ab1da5a16b1e7" type="Folder">14-21</container></did><odd id="aspace_5cbfe405c4e3ef84ce88322a9eebd729"><head>General Note</head><p>Renovation of physical plant and collection re-housing/storage, book and pamphlet cataloging, negative preservation, Tenth Street Studio exhibition and publication, images of Indians exhibition, and establishment of endowments.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref69_0iu" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Office of Parks, Recreation and Historic Preservation (1 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_5f577a2303042b95c27e2a63aa35f89f" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019907]" type="Offsite-Box">15</container><container id="aspace_0617f1ca79c5ba606fb0304783eaac1a" parent="aspace_5f577a2303042b95c27e2a63aa35f89f" type="Folder">1-8</container></did><odd id="aspace_2de30d0ef79ed96fce08819054eddca9"><head>General Note</head><p>This box and the next concerns N-YHS's application and receipt of a grant under the Environmental Quality Bond Act of 1986 (EQBA) for preservation of its building, specifically roof restoration. The second box includes extensive photographs and slides of the roof, damage, etc.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ref71_kc0" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Office of Parks, Recreation and Historic Preservation (2 of 2 boxes)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation">1989-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c889cfe03c92e0b55e82a783721642b" label="Mixed Materials [10170000019908]" type="Offsite-Box">16</container><container id="aspace_35de5776fd844c95772e01c7c2f5181b" parent="aspace_2c889cfe03c92e0b55e82a783721642b" type="Folder">1-6</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_b52adf8e4f32e546f59e762c74e442b4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI. Event Collateral Files</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 Linear feet</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990s-2010s</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4fb16a091353c13c4bb9a402be5249f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The series includes a run of "collateral" documents related to fundraisers, History Makers Gala, invitation-only events (such as exhibition opening receptions, Strawberry Festival, etc.), and other events other than those for the general public. These materials date principally from 1998 to the 2010s. They include event programs, invitations, announcements, and the like. The series also includes assorted digital media (DVDs/CDs re: object images, programs, etc.), videocassettes, and audiocassettes.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="aspace_8caf2bddd99f642c5b1fbaf38391fbad"><head>Arrangement</head><p>The paper files of collateral material are arranged as received from the Development Office, which is by topic (general collateral, particular type of event, etc.), then chronological. The digital and audiovisual media are unsorted.</p></arrangement><processinfo id="aspace_5cd78a58847e8a35e441b6b12c46eada"><head>Processing Information</head><p>The series includes materials transferred to the archives in 2019 (NYHS.2019.009). It was added to the finding aid in August 2021 by archivist Larry Weimer, re-boxed, and moved offsite. Excess copies of the collateral material were discarded.</p></processinfo><c id="aspace_bfbd3ad13cea009f3c3ade7aebcb895e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Event invitations, etc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990s-2010</unitdate><container id="aspace_21d7855127b35d3f2091f19c64669a51" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018215]" type="Offsite-Box">70</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_90970b53c75e98c994ea600eb6d5a5cb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes a few folders of miscellaneous invitations, brochures, etc. from the 1990s and into the early 2000s. The bulk of the box includes folders of material filed by year from 1998-2010.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2b094fbdae646b21081bf5c0ee2f3c5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Event invitations, etc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">2004-2012</unitdate><container id="aspace_3186962e2b9d70eda15b878685c531a0" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018216]" type="Offsite-Box">71</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_19fb75b766e646b0dc2f9c2bfcc3b84a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes files of invitations and other collateral material for: a few exhibitions (2004-2010), opening of the Dimenna Children's Museum (2010), re-opening N-YHS post-renovation (2011), American Musicals Project (2012), Weekend with History (2006-11, with gaps), History Makers Gala (2004-2011), and Strawberry Festival (2004-2012). The box also holds packets of snapshots of events, though these are mostly unidentified.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_418a2f4c97102a76f5b76746662f36dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Videocassettes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate><container id="aspace_83a76d267282624a3801debfce1e8006" label="Moving Images [10170000018217]" type="Offsite-Box">72</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b34ee9f3cb14cb4b9f53a1d34eb9d894" level="file"><did><unittitle>Videocassettes; Audiocassettes, Digital CDs/DVDs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" type="inclusive">1990s-2010s</unitdate><container id="aspace_962ef2e1e6117a13015b7d0ec83e25cd" label="Mixed Materials [10170000018218]" type="Offsite-Box">73</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
