<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD">ad_mc_128</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Feryal Matar Collection <num>AD.MC.128</num></titleproper><author>The finding aid was prepared by Maysa Shaer, Nada Shabout, and Salwa Mikdadi for al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art at NYU Abu Dhabi 	</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>al Mawrid Arab Art Archive, NYU Abu Dhabi</publisher><p><date>May 2026</date></p><address><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>Campus Center, C2-350, 353-355  </addressline><addressline>P.O. Box 129188</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>nyuad.almawrid@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/research/faculty-labs-and-projects/al-mawrid.html" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/research/faculty-labs-and-projects/al-mawrid.html" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-06-05 11:01:05 +0400</date>.</creation><langusage>The description of the collection was created in English. An Arabic version of the finding aid will also be prepared and published. A link to the Arabic description will be added to the finding aid once the revision is complete.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>al Mawrid Arab Art Archive, NYU Abu Dhabi</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Feryal Matar Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="local">Feryal Matar (Palestinian-Emirati artist, 1944- ) - فريال مطر (فنانة فلسطينية-إماراتية، ١٩٤٤- )</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="own">Amal AbuKuwaik (1981- ) - أمل أبوكويك (١٩٨١- )</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.128</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/resources/173</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">442 Digital Objects</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/2023" type="inclusive">1960-2023</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_29ff1b3e8f4434e118ee559250925710">Feryal Matar was born in 1942 in al-Majdal, Palestine, and settled in al-Shati Refugee Camp in the Gaza Strip after being forcefully displaced from her home by Zionist militias in 1948. Matar received her secondary education certificate from the Egyptian-administered Girls Ghazzah School in 1961. She began teaching art under UNRWA in the refugee camp in 1954 and continued until her departure from the Gaza Strip to Kuwait in 1964. Matar taught and exhibited in Kuwait between 1965 and 1967, and moved to Sharjah soon after marrying her husband, Dr. Zuhair AbuKuwaik. Matar began teaching art in Sharjah in 1967 under the Kuwaiti Educational Assistance Program and taught in multiple schools before working full-time with the Sharjah Women's Union Association. Matar established the association's art branch, formulated the art curriculum, and formalized her classes into state-recognized certificate-granting courses. Matar participated in solo and group exhibitions and was widely recognized as a seminal art educator. 

The Feryal Matar Collection includes personal and professional papers, press clippings, exhibition materials, photographic materials, sketches and designs, and related material that provide a comprehensive overview of Matar's artistic practice and the development of women's art education in the United Arab Emirates (UAE). Key highlights of the collection include professional correspondence and educational material that inform on Matar's involvement in the Sharjah Women's Union Association, as well as the association's impact on women's art education. Press clippings from local publications document Matar's and the Sharjah Women's Union's events. The collection also includes an extensive series of photographic materials, comprising prints and negatives that illustrate the environments Matar nurtured and taught in, as well as her own and her students' work.</abstract>
    <physdesc id="aspace_efb7950ae7a2ccc6e09a1c871a4cdfc9" label="Condition Description">The materials were received in good condition, which enabled the digitization to take place at al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art, NYUAD. Digital surrogates were created for all collection items. Upon digitization, all materials were returned to the owner. Materials were rehoused in archival enclosures as needed.</physdesc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="ara" scriptcode="Arab">Arabic</language>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_416c0ff3c6b270455034341591384ef1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Feryal Matar collection consists of biographical documents and correspondence, press clippings, exhibition material, documents generated in the context of her work as a teacher in Kuwait and Sharjah, UAE, photographs documenting her life and works, and sketches and preparatory drawings. The collection offers detailed insight into the progression of women's art education in the UAE in the decades following the country's federation in 1971. Particularly rich are materials related to Matar's career as an educator, including her leading role in the Sharjah Women's Union Association's art department, where she developed curricula, formalized her classes into state-recognized, certificate-granting courses, and produced teaching materials on art theory and technique. Professional correspondence, certificates, and other documents provide insight into her career and involvement with the Sharjah Women's Union Association. The collection also includes press clippings related to her accomplishments as a school teacher and a member of the women's association, dating back to the beginning of her career in the UAE. Amongst Matar's personal papers are the study materials and exams related to her coursework at Bennet College in the UK. Notably, the collection holds extensive photographic material illuminating the conditions of her life and work as a student and teacher in the Gaza Strip, Kuwait, and the UAE. Represented are photos of her personal life, those of her in the classroom setting, as well as photos of her own work and the work of her students. Exhibition material related to personal and group exhibitions, as well as that of her contemporaries, is also represented in the collection. The collection contains sketches and plans for Matar's design work, including designs for the Sharjah Women's Union Association, stained-glass templates, and certificate designs, among others. </p><p>Materials in the collection are primarily in Arabic, with some in English.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_8528c32fccfebcc80906794bded2f168">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in the following series: (I) Personal Papers and Correspondence; (II) Art Education Materials; (III) Sharjah Women's Union Association; (IV) Exhibition Material; (V) Press Clippings; (VI) Design and Preparatory Materials; and (VII) Photographic Materials.
Materials are subdivided into subseries by subject or type and arranged chronologically within each subseries.</p>  </arrangement>
  <custodhist id="aspace_429b2546fccb20c3a7c10665ffd01bef">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The materials in the Feryal Matar collection were created and/or collected by the artist from the 1960s through the 2020s, and the collection is now in the custody of her daughter, Amal AbuKuwaik. In March 2024, the collection was loaned to al Mawrid at NYU Abu Dhabi for archival processing and digitization. Upon completion of the work at al Mawrid, the collection was returned to the custodian in May 2024. Some sections of the collection were initially organized by the custodian, which formed the basis for the detailed arrangement carried out by the team at al Mawrid.</p>  </custodhist>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0b647b1f72e7b930db89e6f7554b045c">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Feryal Matar was born in 1942 in the Palestinian village of al-Majdal. In 1948, Matar and her family were forcefully displaced from their home by armed Zionist militias and settled in al-Shati refugee camp in the Egyptian-administered Gaza Strip. Her father was martyred during the struggle. Matar took an interest in art from a young age and, by 15, was employed by UNRWA as an art teacher, working with children in the refugee camp. Matar graduated from the Girls' Gazzah College with a secondary education certificate issued by the Egyptian Department of Education in Cairo. Matar continued to teach art in the Gaza Strip until her move to Kuwait in 1965, where she taught, practiced, and exhibited her work. She met her husband, the family doctor and fellow Palestinian refugee Zuhair AbuKuwaik, in Kuwait, and the couple married in 1967. That same year, they moved to Sharjah in the United Arab Emirates, where Matar began teaching art at the Asmaa Girls' School as part of the Kuwaiti Educational Assistance Program, with her contract being issued by the Kuwait State Office in Dubai. Upon arriving in Sharjah, Matar and her husband bought a piece of land in an area now known as the Heart of Sharjah, where Matar planted and cultivated seeds from Palestine. The property hosted dignitaries and businessmen passing through the region, and housed Matar's art studio. The site is also where Matar's husband, a family physician, established the first medical clinic in Sharjah. Matar began engaging her students in exhibitions and public displays early on, including one in 1969. Sheikha Noura [Al-Qassimi] opened the exhibition at Asmaa Girls' School, featuring a selection of paintings and mixed-media works by Matar depicting themes of Palestinian heritage and liberation, and providing young students with an opportunity to engage with art and exhibition spaces firsthand. Matar was awarded Best Teacher in the Art Education Competition for Trucial Schools in 1972 and 1973. In the same academic year, Matar received the first Excellence Award at the Art Education Exhibition, administered by the UAE Ministry of Education. In 1974, Matar was awarded her certification in Painting and Decorating by Bennet College, based in the UK, after a year of participating in remote classes. </p><p>Matar taught art at the Sharjah Women's Union Association from its formalization under the new Federation in the mid-1970s and served as supervisor of the art committee for its annual art exhibitions. Women's Associations in the UAE, sponsored and directed by members of the Royal Family, were established across the emirates in order to encourage women to play more active roles in the young federation's social and economic development. The associations organized classes to teach a variety of skills, including literacy, and also offered women-only spaces outside the house for women to gather. The Sharjah Women's Union Association was officially registered in 1972 and joined the General Women's Union created by Sheikha Fatima Bint Mubarak in 1975. Matar's curriculum covered a variety of media, including painting, drawing, mixed-media artworks, including from found material, making flowers with media such as fabric, paper, metal, plastic, and clay; flower arrangements and painting flowers on vases and canvas; decoupage; painting on glass; metalwork; painting on textiles; painting, stencil, and wax-blocking design on silk; and interior design. In 1978, the Sharjah Women's Union Association opened its annual exhibition with 550 works in 6 sections, showcasing a variety of works from abstract paintings to traditional handicrafts, with sales totaling 30k dirhams. The exhibition also held men's-only days to encourage their engagement with women's work, signifying the role the association played in legitimizing women's social contributions. By 1981, Sheikha Noura Al-Qassimi had begun advocating to the Minister of Education for Matar to teach at the Association for more than two days a week to accommodate the high demand for her classes. Matar continued in her full-time role as an art teacher at Al-Shaima School and later at Sharjah Girls' Preparatory School, before being released from her duties as a school teacher and receiving permission to dedicate her time, as needed, to the Sharjah Women's Union Association. Matar participated yearly as a teacher in the Children's Cultural Festival as well as the Child's Art Exhibition beginning with their first annual events in 1985. By the early 90s, the Sharjah Women's Union Association had graduated women from Matar's art classes with certificates attested by the Ministry of Labor and Social Affairs, allowing them to work in business or as teachers in private schools. The art course lasted six months and enrolled women from different backgrounds, including housewives, college students, and working professionals. The women participating in the association's classes and exhibitions were able to profit from their work and expressed newfound confidence in undertaking independent endeavors, including holding exhibitions in their own homes, starting their own businesses, and permanently displaying their work for sale at the association. For those who didn't profit financially from their art, the women expressed marked improvements in their home lives through a new sense of agency gained by applying what they learned to their homes' interior decoration, and in the sense of fulfillment their children experienced from learning from their mothers. The Sharjah Women's Union Association published the monthly journal, Sawt Al-Mar'aa, which covered the association's work as well as published articles and advice columns aimed at women's issues. The association's news was often covered in the Women and Society section of Al-Ittihad Newspaper. Matar continued to exhibit her work, teach, and direct the art program at the association until her retirement.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_887509ccdb790a3c8a6aea8b8e31dea5">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The materials were borrowed from Amal AbuKuwaik for archival processing and digitization and returned upon completion.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_903e3c647984396c40673261f4766d81">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Digital surrogates only are held by the repository. Based on the agreement with the owner, digital images of selected series/subseries will be publicly available on the NYU Archival Collections Finding Aid Portal. Materials not made available online may be consulted in person at al Mawrid, NYUAD. Researchers should contact nyuad.almawrid@nyu.edu to request details or to make an appointment.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ad2fef590d1cc2ed1bc1b1553155be86">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Intellectual property rights for the Feryal Matar collection remain with the artist's family. al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art does not hold any legal rights over the content of its collections, and therefore cannot grant legal rights to anyone who wishes to publish material. Copyright status has not been determined for all collection items. It is the responsibility of the researcher to clear the rights from the respective copyright holders. All use permissions must be sought from Amal AbuKuwaik through a request submitted to al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art at nyuad.almawrid@nyu.edu.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b620d06911a1ddf78d4be2635d9123ec">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Title or identification of item, date when known, Feryal Matar Collection, ADMC128, item identifier (Ref. number). Arab Art Archive, al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art, New York University Abu Dhabi.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_63ef20a9e98912f9f098c4857c6bae09">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by the team at al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art in 2024, including Ibrahim Mohamed Ali, Maysa Shaer, Ala Younis, and Jonathan Burr for al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art at NYU Abu Dhabi.</p><p>Arab Art Archive finding aids are prepared in both English and Arabic. Researchers seeking to confirm the Arabic spelling of an artist's name are encouraged to consult the Arabic finding aid. In the English-language finding aids, transliterations of Arabic names are guided by al Mawrid policy to use the artist's preferred professional spelling whenever possible. Spellings are checked against artist websites or social media presence (when existent) as well as any available government documents, such as a passport or ID. In the case when no such primary documents may be found, spellings are checked with the Library of Congress Name Authority File (LCNAF) and Subject Headings (LCSH); academic sources such as Modern Art in the Arab World: Primary Documents; Getty Vocabularies / Union List of Artist Names; and, in some cases, Mathaf Encyclopedia of Modern Art and the Arab World. Al Mawrid Arab Center for the Study of Art maintains an internal Name Standardization Reference List with notes about authoritative sources. </p><p>Rather than transliterate Arabic-language titles of documents for the purposes of the English-language finding aid, it was decided for consistency and ease to translate Arabic titles, as well as titles in other languages, into English. Translated titles and phrases are placed inside square brackets.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United Arab Emirates -- الإمارات العربية المتحدة</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="no91003289" source="lcsh">Sharjah (United Arab Emirates) --  الشارقة (الإمارات العربية المتحدة)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n81147502" source="lcsh">Abu Dhabi (United Arab Emirates) -- أبوظبي (الإمارات العربية المتحدة)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n83167803" source="lcsh">Dubai (United Arab Emirates) -- دبي (الإمارات العربية المتحدة)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n80053139" source="lcsh">Kuwait -- دولة الكويت</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n81102869" source="lcsh">Kuwait (Kuwait) -- (مدينة الكويت (الكويت</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="sh85053589 " source="lcsh">Gaza Strip -- قطاع غزة</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n2008065059" source="lcsh">Shati (Refugee camp) -- مخيّم الشاطئ</geogname>
    <subject source="local">Art -- Arab countries -- الفن -- الدول العربية</subject>
    <subject source="local">Art, Arab -- 20th century -- الفن العربي -- القرن العشرين</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art--Arab countries--20th century--Exhibitions -- الفن--الدول العربية --القرن العشرين--المعارض</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh87003162" source="lcsh">Art, Arab -- الفن العربي</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2015000067" source="lcsh">Arts, Palestinian -- الفنون الفلسطينية</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh97006183" source="lcsh">Art archives -- أرشيفات الفن</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2014001856" source="lcsh">Art, Emirati -- الفن الإماراتي</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85007522" source="lcsh">Art, Abstract</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85007505" source="lcsh">Art -- Study and teaching -- الفن -- الدراسة والتدريس</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85096661" source="lcsh">Painting</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85036316" source="lcsh">Decorative arts</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85049294" source="lcsh">Flower arrangement</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85070246" source="lcsh">Arab-Israeli conflict -- 1948-1967 -- الصراع العربي الإسرائيلي -- ١٩٤٨-١٩٦٧</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2008124232" source="lcsh">Israel-Arab War, 1948-1949 -- الحرب العربية الإسرائيلية، ١٩٤٨-١٩٤٩</subject>
    <persname role="own">Amal AbuKuwaik (1981- ) - أمل أبوكويك (١٩٨١- )</persname>
    <corpname role="his" source="local">Women's Union Association Sharjah - جمعية الإتحاد النسائية الشارقة</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_75965273c98455ce9a674a98039e486a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Personal Papers and Correspondence</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31265</unitid></did><c id="aspace_042c5ab8b0324ea60f45f306cdaf2ff1" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>I.A. Personal Papers</unittitle><unitid>cuid283</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31266</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6e59890351bb8d213df452b7681a18db"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This sub-series includes IDs, CVs, certificates (including awards and diplomas), and administrative documents, among them contracts and applications.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b22964506eea197d41b931009be1241e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>I.B. Correspondence</unittitle><unitid>cuid284</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31267</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11601ea00b4a138d42364792907af7a8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This sub-series includes administrative correspondence concerning Matar's education at Bennet College, UK, and her professional work as an artist, teacher, and member of the Sharjah Women's Union Association.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_4629e6e09a952770a6e76bc6aac5295d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: Art Education Materials</unittitle><unitid>cuid285</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31268</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e820a3fb65716856cb0b858a7a12940c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material includes writings by Feryal Matar and others on art education in general and on art techniques specific to printing, silkscreen, metalwork, and drawing, among others.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7a3ecd20feca5ebab254249b4acf412c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III: Sharjah Women's Union Association</unittitle><unitid>cuid286</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31269</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93ce69a26a9009803b3b3176f643c98c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material includes administrative correspondence and documents, certificates, drafts of mission statements, receipts and memos, and invitations, among others, pertaining to the Sharjah Women's Union Association.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9df8537722024c1bb8addff01ba75172" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV: Exhibition Material (1981-2023)</unittitle><unitid>cuid287</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31270</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b188bd1e0b221abef7672cfb48301ac0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series comprises various exhibition materials, including catalogs, invitations, and brochures of solo and group exhibitions, including early exhibitions held in the UAE.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f9fa5f314907614997088c39f9796dd8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V: Press Clippings</unittitle><unitid>cuid288</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31271</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2a16a9a2c5e28d221c757ad1aaa3bc43"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series comprises news clippings from various newspapers and magazines, which feature articles and press coverage about Feryal Matar and art exhibitions in which she participated, as well as news pertaining to the Sharjah Women's Union Association and its activities. Clippings are mainly in Arabic with some in English, and are arranged chronologically.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6d8e8cee23d8bf0ad83853b184a35085" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI: Design and Preparatory Materials</unittitle><unitid>cuid289</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31272</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5a7ae69586a60cd83503f90e579dfc1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material includes designs related to the proposed Sharjah Women's Club, stained-glass templates, and certificate designs, among others. This series also includes a set of 10 posters by Abdulrahman al-Muzayyin.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_50dc900abdffbb8ba8c750d3db9dd7ef" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII: Photographic Materials</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31273</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9590ced83d60743020789c151417d33e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Material includes several sets of photographs and negatives featuring various subjects, including Feryal Matar and her family; colleagues and students in Gaza, Kuwait, and at the Sharjah Women's Union Association; art exhibitions and events; and photographs of Matar's artwork and those created by her students.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_6434ad8364376b0f0935f2783f809ed0" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>VII.A. Loose photographs</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31274</unitid></did><c id="aspace_908414e5684317c4101e96b7527628e2" level="subgrp"><did><unittitle>VII.A.1. Personal Photographs</unittitle><unitid>cuid290</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31275</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_acd724454152845358f73e055e61f459" level="subgrp"><did><unittitle>VII.A.2. Professional Photographs</unittitle><unitid>cuid291</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31276</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_ca5ef472a6ce2ca041aaf120d5962d14" level="subgrp"><did><unittitle>VII.A.3. Artwork</unittitle><unitid>cuid292</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31277</unitid></did></c></c><c id="aspace_21ff50957a9dbc4d4e9392e98f86e706" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>VII.B. Photo Albums</unittitle><unitid>cuid293</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31278</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_725af3890a93eee54d6190fffa598b59" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>VII.C. Negatives</unittitle><unitid>cuid294</unitid><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/4/archival_objects/31279</unitid></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
