<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/arms_1978_114_higgins/">arms_1978_114_higgins</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Charles M. Higgins papers <num>1978.114</num></titleproper><author>Sativa Peterson. Updated by Sarah Quick to include additional biographical information, 2026. </author><sponsor>This collection was processed and described as part of the project, "Uncovering the Secrets of Brooklyn's 19th Century Past: Creation to Consolidation," funded by the Council on Library and Information Resources, with additional support from The Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Center for Brooklyn History</publisher><p><date>April 2008</date></p><address><addressline>128 Pierrepont Street</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://www.bklynlibrary.org/cbh" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.bklynlibrary.org/cbh" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-05-02 17:42:30 +0000</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Center for Brooklyn History</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Charles M. Higgins papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Higgins, Chas. M. (Charles Michael)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>1978.114</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/3/resources/721</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.34 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one oversize box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854/1929" type="inclusive">1854-1929</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1886/1929" type="bulk">1886-1929</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_1f1d221331d961d886b67515620b96aa">This collection contains the personal papers of Charles M. Higgins (1854-1929).  Higgins was a prominent ink manufacturer and creator of Higgins American India Ink. He was the head of the Charles M. Higgins Company, manufacturers of the drawing ink he invented. The company's operations were located in the Brooklyn neighborhood of Park Slope.  The collection contains many papers, both pamphlets and typescripts, written by Higgins on the topics of compulsory vaccination, religious ethics, morality, and patriotism.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_1b7bd1d738faa45feac89613d29c135b" label="Text" type="Oversize">1978.114 1 of 1</container>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8cb6e8c8ede4ff34399b1c2304ae3b52">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); Charles M. Higgins papers, 1978.114, Box and Folder number; Center for Brooklyn History, Brooklyn Public Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_97fdcc2b3efcf38d83fbbcb1f3b32966">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Minimally processed to the collection level.</p>  </processinfo>
  <otherfindaid id="aspace_f1c9dca26f05f260f9188b18343ec297">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>An earlier version of this finding aid, containing a complete container list, is available in paper form at the Brooklyn Historical Society.  Please consult library staff for more information.</p>  </otherfindaid>
  <bioghist id="aspace_970d70bde46ef608f8509e61ac5ace16">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Born in County Leitrim, Ireland in 1854 to Dennis and Rachel Elizabeth Higgins, Charles Higgins arrived in America at the age of six, several months after the arrival of his parents. The family settled in an apartment at 464 Columbia Street in Brooklyn, an Irish working-class neighborhood where Higgins attended school until the age of nine. By the age of twenty-five, he was working as a patent solicitor and living at 411 Atlantic Avenue with his mother and two sisters. After working for several companies, he set out on his own as an independent patent solicitor, securing patents for clients and experimenting with inventions of his own, including, in 1880, a black ink he hoped would replace the popular Chinese stick or "India" ink.  </p><p>He worked on the ink at home with the help of his sister Marguerite and brother-in-law John Gianella, who in 1885 became his partner in the "Chas. M. Higgins &amp; Co., manufacturers of Inks and Adhesives" business. He continued to work as a patent solicitor until 1888, when he sold the business and purchased a factory at 168-170 Eighth Street to devote his time to the ink business. The factory employed up to 48 men and women, many of them Irish immigrants. Higgins secured 26 patents for processes, formulas, and devices used in the business, which gained a national reputation and quickly expanded. A second factory opened at 273-277 Ninth Street, which became the company headquarters.  </p><p>In 1899, Higgins married Alexandra Fransioli. She moved into 499 Fourth Street, which Higgens shared with his mother. Rachel Elizabeth Higgins died in 1901, but the couple remained in the house until 1903, when they moved to 101 Prospect Park West. They had three children: a son, Tracy Higgins, and two daughters, Lisbeth Higgins Hamm and Rachel Higgins Everson. </p><p>Higgins was an early opponent of compulsory vaccination, thinking it harmful.  For many years he was the treasurer of the Anti-Vaccination League of America.  He wrote many pamphlets on this subject, including <emph render="italic">Horror of Vaccination</emph> (1920).  </p><p>In 1900, Charles M. Higgins wrote an open letter to the editor of the <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Eagle</emph> on "Justice for China," at the time of the Boxer Rebellion. </p><p>In 1908, Higgins was a leader in the effort to rehabilitate the Brooklyn Borough Bank, which had been founded in 1832 and was located on Court Street.  He opposed the receivership being placed in the hands of an "up-stater" and was himself appointed as a joint-receiver.</p><p>As one of the founding members of the Kings County Historical Society, Higgins fought to have the Gowanus site of the Battle of Long Island restored, especially the old Gowanus Stone House.  Higgins's money also enabled the Kings County Historical Society to donate the Altar to Liberty statue on Battle Hill in Green-Wood Cemetery.</p><p>Higgins was a member of many clubs and served on the Boards of many public service-oriented institutions, including the Kings County Historical Society, the Brooklyn Chamber of Congress, the Brooklyn Ethical Culture Society, the Anti-Vaccination League of America, the Manufacturer's Association, the Montauk Club, the Riding &amp; Driving Club, the Crescent Athletic Club, the Brooklyn Club, the St. George's Golf Club, and the Huntington Bay Club.</p>    <list numeration="arabic" type="ordered">
      <head>Sources:</head>
      <item>"C.M. Higgins Dies; Ink Manufacturer." <emph render="italic">The New York Times</emph>, October 23, 1929.</item>
      <item>"Chas. M. Higgins, Manufacturer, Dies at Home." <emph render="italic">Brooklyn Daily Eagle</emph>, October 22, 1929.</item>
      <item>Jaffe, Steven H., and Rebecca Amato. Envisioning Brooklyn: Family, philanthropy, and the growth of an American city. Brooklyn, N.Y: Brooklyn Historical Society, 2016. </item>
    </list>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_46741e3444d317ae83c88307310115cb">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Charles M. Higgins papers consist primarily of Higgins's writings, photographs, and clippings.  Materials relate to Higgins's position as a prominent ink manufacturer, activities in the Anti-Vaccination League of America and Kings County Historical Society, and interests in religious ethics and morality.  Items also relate to Higgins's death in 1929 and the history of Brooklyn, particularly in regards to Green-Wood Cemetery.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e4732c3149de129d24b40910a1615d51">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to users without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_46e13a9faa6ff8e34a9606f9c8778711">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Rachel Higgins Everson, 1976.  Formally accessioned in 1978.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_7f26b53f89d9c485b2c412bf5a113797">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Brooklyn clubs collection (ARC.172)</p><p>Charles A. Ditmas collectin (ARC.196)</p><p>Charles Hamm collection (2019.004)</p><p>Kings County Historical Society records (ARC.058)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <phystech id="aspace_6c32abe5f056e62545a102f09df7f389">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.</p>  </phystech>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <genreform source="aat">Pamphlets</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vaccination -- Complications</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tetanus -- Vaccination</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Banks and banking -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Vaccination</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prohibition</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Park Slope (New York, N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Long Island, Battle of, New York, N.Y., 1776</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Businessmen -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <persname source="local">Gavin, John E.</persname>
    <persname source="local">Higgins, Tracy</persname>
    <persname source="local">Higgins, Alexandra Fransioli</persname>
    <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Higgins, Chas. M. (Charles Michael)</persname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Green-Wood Cemetery (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Manufacturer's Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Brooklyn Society for Ethical Culture</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Anti-Vaccination League of America</corpname>
    <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences</corpname>
    <corpname source="local">Charles M. Higgins &amp; Company</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
