<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/cbhm_0032">cbhm_0032</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the William Coleman research files <num>CBHM.0032</num></titleproper><author>Dee Bowers</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Center for Brooklyn History</publisher><p><date>September 2025</date></p><address><addressline>Brooklyn Public Library</addressline><addressline>128 Pierrepont St.</addressline><addressline>Brooklyn, NY 11201</addressline><addressline>cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-09-18 17:41:42 +0000</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Center for Brooklyn History</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William Coleman research files</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="com" source="local">Coleman, William R. "Bill"</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="dnr" source="local">Coleman, Marjorie T.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>CBHM.0032</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/resources/2009</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.5 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1698/2021" type="inclusive">1698-2021</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_2855e9fe59f8324d2a79f919b63b1bc4">Primary and secondary sources, notes, correspondence, and other documents relating to William "Bill" Coleman's research into the history of the slave trade.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_25258a5621da8980bdba7a046b46d2b8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open to researchers without restriction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_168ce4b8c0be21c6a58f27bed3dc2b65">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of the Coleman family, 2025.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_39875e348e76397751ed439850a3c27c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into three series by type: primary sources, secondary sources, and Coleman's notes and correspondence. For simplicity, the archivist sorted pre-1900 documents as primary sources and post-1900 sources as secondary sources. Each series is further sub-divided by type. There are additional arrangement notes at the sub-series and folder level where appropriate.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2fdbdf66dd189385e571daf56fa49788">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>William R. "Bill" Coleman was born in 1947. He earned a BA in Political Science from the University of Wisconsin Madison in 1969 and a JD from New York Law School in 1972, after which he practiced law professionally until his retirement in 2006. He was elected to the board of the Brooklyn Historical Society in 1986 and served for 16 years before resigning in 2001, though he and his wife continued to support the Society. He was the honoree of the Society's 4th annual library dinner in 2008, and his speech from that occasion is included in this collection. He was also involved with the Brooklyn Bar Association, the Brooklyn Heights Synagogue, and the Prospect Park Alliance. In addition, Coleman was an independent researcher and historian who planned to write a book on the history of the African slave trade in America.</p>  </bioghist>
  <odd id="aspace_c5967cab61a38025432c00900e5967ea">
    <head>General</head>
<p>Users of this collection should note that research notes and files represent a work in progress, or an interpretation that might change over time. History is always subject to debate and new inquiry. This collection represents a researcher's interpretation of the archival material, and we invite you to look at the relevant original material, either at CBH or elsewhere.</p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_183f34038d748b93af41b8b4c9baa2ac">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date (if known); William Coleman research files, CBHM.0032, Box and Folder number; Brooklyn Public Library, Center for Brooklyn History.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f8ead5186a3ab8175ffef69ee575f45b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection was rearranged for clarity and ease of use, but a listing of Coleman's original folder headings and order is preserved in the accession file. The archivist discarded duplicate copies of materials with no distinguishing markings, but retained duplicates if they had unique markings or notes from Coleman. Original folders were discarded and replaced with acid-free archival folders, but in cases where Coleman had made notes on a folder, it was photocopied and filed with the folder's contents. Email addresses of Coleman's correspondents were redacted for privacy.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_25d677e630aca31752549809f164d058">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>William R. Coleman papers ARC.018 (papers of Coleman's grandfather)</p><p>William R. Coleman collection of New York City waterfront pollution slides (2012.017)</p><p>Henry J. Van Dyke sermon 2005.010</p><p>CBH's Black History research guide includes detailed information on collections at CBH that document the history of enslavement in Brooklyn, and the online project In Pursuit of Freedom (https://pursuitoffreedom.org/) documents abolitionist history in Brooklyn.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8a80f4a988c2db55323104e30dba5626">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection consists of the research files of William Coleman on the history of the slave trade. The collection is divided into three series: primary sources, secondary sources, and William Coleman notes and correspondence. Series 1: Primary Sources consists primarily of modern copies of pre-1900 sources, though there are some original documents. Series 2: Secondary Sources is largly computer printouts of post-1900 sources, though there are also photocopies of books and clippings. Series 3 contains both printed emails as well as typed and handwritten notes.</p><p>Primary source documents include books and articles, sermons and addresses, legal and government documents, and newspaper clippings. Secondary source documents include articles, books and book excerpts, indexes, lists, and guides, reviews, and theses and dissertations.</p><p>Though Coleman's overarching research topic was the African slave trade, this collection also includes significant materials on several related topics. These include the Oaksmith family (accused slave trader Appleton Oaksmith and his parents, the writers Seba Smith and Elizabeth Oakes Smith), the case of Nathaniel Gordon, Southern businessman Gazaway Bugg Lamar, and the slave trade from Asia.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_cde8a6b8389efe364a8253c0db630443">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>While many items at the Center for Brooklyn History are unrestricted, we do not own reproduction rights to all materials. Be aware of the several kinds of rights that might apply: copyright, licensing and trademarks. The researcher assumes all responsibility for copyright questions.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- New York (State) -- Kings County</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- United States -- History</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Research notes</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">History -- Research -- North America</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Great Britain -- Politics and government</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Northeastern States -- Politics and government</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 18th century</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Social aspects</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slave trade</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Slave trade -- United States</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Newspaper clippings</genreform>
    <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
    <persname role="dnr" source="local">Coleman, Marjorie T.</persname>
    <persname>Oaksmith, Appleton, 1827 or 1828-1887</persname>
    <persname>Smith, Elizabeth Oakes Prince, 1806-1893</persname>
    <persname>Lamar, Gazaway Bugg, 1798-1874</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_c54af66333a55cfa8f9f64dc4e23cb33" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 1: Primary sources </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452505</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1698/1896" type="inclusive">1698-1896</unitdate></did><processinfo id="aspace_790978d62124210045b578a02cefcc21"><head>Processing Information</head><p>For simplicity, the archivist sorted pre-1900 publications as primary, and post-1900 sources as secondary.</p></processinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_cc7e307e5714aa43be04ee6f037512d1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Unless otherwise specified, these are all modern copies of the original sources. Some folders contain Coleman's related notes or correspondence.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_24509791a7e8274aadc59d9c9b80805d" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 1.1: Books and articles</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452506</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1824/1879" type="inclusive">1824-circa 1870s</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_ae3049590d9a974917170a3c19079627" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_0224151fd04ceaee636eea2952dd2498"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by author name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ddd6bf83897fd39ca027454ccf9f0af4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The American Almanac and Repository of Useful Knowledge, for the Year 1853. Boston, MA: Little, Brown and Company, 1853, pp. 130, 132, 135, and 137.</p><p>The American Colonization Society. "List of Life Members" (p. 23), "List of Emigrants by the Liberia Packet" (p. 24), "Brazilian Law Against the Slave Trade" and "Sketches of Liberia" (p. 25), "Character of the Emigrants by the Liberia Packet" (pp. 42-43), "Annual Report of the Am. Col. Society" (pp. 78-80), "Emigration to Liberia" (pp. 149-150). In The African Repository 27, 1851.</p><p>American Lloyd's Register of American and Foreign Shipping, 1859, 1861, 1862.</p><p>Appleton, D. &amp; Co., ed. "Habeas Corpus" to "Houston, Sam." In The (Appleton's) American Annual Cyclopedia and Register of Important Events of the Year 1861. New York, NY: D. Appleton &amp; Company, 1867, pp. 354-366.</p><p>Baker, George E., ed. The Works of William H. Seward, Vol. I. New York, NY: Redfield, 1853, pp. lxii-lxviii.</p><p>Baker, George E., ed. "The Virginia Controversy" and "The Georgia Controversy." In The Works of William H. Seward, Vol. II. Boston, MA: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, 1884, pp. 449-546.</p><p>Barrett, Walker. The Old Merchants of New York City. New York, NY: Carleton, 1864, pp. 223-224.</p><p>Bergen, Teunis G. Register in Alphabetical Order, of the Early Settlers of Kings County…New York, NY: S.W. Green's Son, 1881, select pages.</p><p>Broadway Tabernacle Anti-slavery Society. Proceedings of the Session of Broadway Tabernacle, against Lewis Tappan, with the action of the Presbytery and General Assembly. New York, NY: The Society, 1839.</p><p>Browne, Junius Henri. The Great Metropolis: A Mirror of New York. Hartford, CT: American Publishing Co., 1869, pp.637-638.</p><p>Carey, Henry Charles. The Slave Trade, Domestic and Foreign: Why it Exists, and How it May Be Extinguished. Philadelphia, PA: 1853.</p><p>De Peyster, Frederic. Memoir of Rip Van Dam. New York, NY: Press of Edmund Jones &amp; Co., 1865. [original pamphlet]</p><p>Derby, J.C. Fifty Years Among Authors--Books and Publishers. New York, NY: G.W. Carleton &amp; Co., 1884. Sections on Alice and Phoebe Cary, Elizabeth Oakes Smith, and Richard Henry Stoddard.</p><p>Fernow, Berthold, ed. The Records of New Amsterdam from 1653-1674. Volume I: Minutes of the Court of Burgomasters and Schepens, 1653-1655. Published under the authority of the City of New York. New York, NY: The Knickerbocker Press, 1897.</p><p>Foote, Andrew H. Africa and the American Flag. New York, NY: D. Appleton and Company, 1862, pp. 344-347.
Gelston, David. [Papers], 1802-1803.</p><p>Great Union Meeting Committee of Arrangements. Official Report of the Great Union Meeting, Held at the Academy of Music, New York, December 19, 1859. Published by Order of the Committee of Arrangements. New York, NY: Davis &amp; Kent, 1859.</p><p>Green, Duff. "Commercial Importance and Future of the South." De Bow's Review 32, February 1862, pp. 120-134.</p><p>Griswold, Rufus Wilmot. Passages from the Correspondence and Other Papers of Rufus W. Griswold. W.M. Griswold, 1898, pp. 129-133.</p><p>Hunt, Freeman (conducted by). "Art. I - Duties on Portuguese Wines." The Merchants' Magazine, and Commercial Review. New York, NY: Volume 11, November 1844.</p><p>Lossing, Benson John. The Pictorial Field-Book of the Revolution. New York, NY: Harper &amp; Bros., 1851-1852, pp. 210-211.</p><p>"[Announcement of formation of the] Maine Anti-Slavery Society." The Liberator. May 18, 1833.</p><p>Mars, James. Life of James Mars, A Slave Born and Sold in Connecticut. Hartford, CT: Press of Case, Lockwood &amp; Company, 1864.</p><p>Moore, John Bassett. A Treatise on Extradition and Interstate Rendition, Vol. II. Boston, MA: The Boston Book Company, 1891, pp. 846-858.</p><p>New York Committee of Vigilance. The First Annual Report...for the Year 1837. Published by direction of the committee, [1837].</p><p>Nichols, Clarina Irene Howard. To the Women of the State of New York [circular], circa 1856.</p><p>Niles, H., ed. Niles' Weekly Register. Baltimore, MD: Printed for the editor by William Ogden Niles, 1819-1822. Selections including "Chronicle," "Editorial Articles," "Slave Trade," "Law Intelligence," and "Congress."</p><p>Onderdonk, Henry Jr. Farming in Olden Times in Queens County, circa 1868. Reprinted in Journal of Long Island History 5.1, 1965.</p><p>Onderdonk, Henry Jr. Suffolk County in Olden Times Parts II and III, circa 1860s-1870s. Reprinted in Journal of Long Island History 6.1 and 6.2, 1966.</p><p>Onderdonk, Henry Jr. Notes on the History of Queens County Parts I and II, 1864. Reprinted in Journal of Long Island History 7.1 and 7.2, 1967.</p><p>Religious Society of Friends. The Present State of the African Slave Trade. Published by direction of a meeting representing the Religious Society of Friends in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, &amp;c. Philadelphia, PA: William Brown, 1824.</p><p>San Francisco Committee of Vigilance. Constitution, 1851. Edited by Porter Garnett and printed in the Publications of the Academy of Pacific Coast History 1.7, 1910.</p><p>San Francisco Committee of Vigilance. List of Names, 1851. Edited by Porter Garnett and printed in the Publications of the Academy of Pacific Coast History 2.2, 1911.</p><p>Seabury, Samuel. American Slavery Distinguished from the Slavery of the English Theorists, and Justified by the Law of Nature. New York, NY: Mason Brothers, 1861.</p><p>Thompson, Mary W. Sketches of the History, Character and Dying Testimony, of Beneficiaries of the Colored Home, in the City of New-York. New York, NY: John F. Trow, 1851.</p><p>Truth, Sojourner. Narrative of Sojourner Truth. Edited by Olive Gilbert. Battle Creek, MI: Review and Herald Office, 1884.</p><p>Unknown author. [Review of] Fifteenth Report of the American Colonization Society, Washington, 1832 and Letters on the Colonization Society; with a View of its Probable Results; addressed to the Hon. C.F. Mercer by M. Carey, 1832. The North American Review 35.76, July 1832, pp. 118-165.</p><p>Unknown author. "The Slave-trade in 1858." The Edinburgh Review 108, 1858, pp. 541-586. </p><p>Unknown author. "A Slave Trader's Letter-Book." The North American Review 143.360, November 1886, pp. 447-462.</p><p>Van Rensselaer, Mrs. John King. The Goede Vrouw of Mana-ha-ta at Home and in Society 1609-1760. New York, NY: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1898, pp. 238-243.</p><p>Weeden, William B. "The Early African Slave-Trade in New England." American Antiquarian Society Journal, October 1887, pp. 107-128.</p><p>Whitman, Walt. Ode by Walt Whitman to be sung on Fort Greene, 4th of July, 1846. Reprinted in Journal of Long Island History 1.2, 1939.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_81c71931343351b17c978ad0a3bbc590" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 1.2: Sermons and addresses </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452507</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1833/1866" type="inclusive">1833-1866</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_c805b674250d44105677ddd5352e9f5e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_ca86a685a04076f57ec4fcfb5cfec12f"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by author name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_cefd9f42b9f3ca0358550c3bce6c4457"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Degrauw, John W. An Address Delivered Before the Brooklyn Horticultural Society December 7th, 1854; also the report of the treasurer, W.S. Dunham; with the report of the executive committee. Brooklyn, NY: J.W. Heighway &amp; Co., 1855. [catalog record only]</p><p>Otis, James F. A Sketch of the Character, and Defence of the Principles of William Lloyd Garrison. Being an address, delivered before the board of managers of the "Maine Anti-Slavery Society," in Portland, Me. on...1st November. 1833, by one of the board. New York, NY: Henry R. Piercy, 1833.</p><p>Sloan, J.R.W. Review of Rev. Henry J. Van Dyke's Discouse on 'The Character and Influence of Abolitionism,' a Sermon Preached in the Third Reformed Presbyterian Church…New York, on…December 23, 1860…Also, by Special Request, in the Church of the Puritans (Rev. Dr. Cheever's), on...January 6, 1861. New York, NY: William Erving, 1861.</p><p>Van Dyke, Henry Jackson:</p><p>The Commandment with Promise: a sermon preached in the First Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn, on…No. 24th, 1859. New York, NY: George W. Wood, 1859. [original pamphlet]</p><p>The Character and Influence of Abolitionism: a sermon preached in the First Presbyterian Church, Brooklyn, on...Dec. 9th, 1860. New York, NY: George F. Nesbitt &amp; Co., 1860. [original pamphlet]</p><p>The Character and Influence of Abolitionism: a sermon preached in the First Presbyterian Church, Brooklyn, on...Dec. 9th, 1860. New York, NY: D. Appleton and Company., 1860. [original pamphlet]</p><p>Memorial of George L. Sampson: an address delivered at this funeral in the First Presbyterian Church, Brooklyn, Jan. 5, 1866. New York, NY: John F. Trow &amp; Co., 1866. [catalog record only]</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_41655ee0ab3fa03db0da83d38bdfb560" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 1.3: Legal and government documents </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452508</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1698/1879" type="inclusive">1698-1879</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_0671612b52f58b2a46001e98081fe016"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_b0f49298f7c27522bb18c8a55dcf6a8e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kings County census documents</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452509</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1698/1820" type="inclusive">1698-1820</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_8bea3bcc101aed47e2e513a70bdea1a6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_536d1dd4c8b4a10bd0cc2174d4e5d434"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Censuses for 1698, 1738, 1786, 1800, 1810, and 1820 as well as 1755 census of slaves.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_51cc690afb4a43769ac75aad2c572c13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal cases</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452510</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1735/1867" type="inclusive">1735-1867</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_14699112244f301e8f19aa790bda0ba6" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c53bc45fa813778df3028b3e5750049"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[Libel] Trial of John Peter Zenger. August 4, 1735.</p><p>Skinner v. May. Circuit Court District Maine 1792. Jay C. Justice. Civil action for fines for slaving in violation of Maine slaving law.</p><p>Libel of forfeiture against the brig Francis F. Johnson for alleged violation of the laws relating to the slave trade. April 6, 1821.</p><p>Polydore v. Prince. 19 F.  Cas. 550. District Court Maine (1837). Photocopies from NARA Northeast Region.</p><p>Report of the Committee Appointed by the Government of the "Board of Trade," to take into consideration the communication of Messrs. Sampson and Tappan, dated April 24th, 1856. Boston, MA: J.H. Eastburn's Press, 1856. [original pamphlet]</p><p>In the Supreme Court of the United States, December Sessions, 1858. No. 188. The Ship Sarah, Sampson &amp; Tappan, Claimants and Appellants, vs. S. &amp; W. Welsh. Appeal from the Circuit Court of the United States, in and for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania...Philadelphia, PA: Crissy &amp; Markley, [1858]. [original pamphlet]</p><p>United States vs. Samuel Skinner. District Court…for the District of Massachusetts. Slaver Margaret Scott. 1861.</p><p>Opinion in the matter of the claims of G.B. Lamar and others: to certain cotton held by the Treasury Department as captured and confiscable property. 1867.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_bff5b8d427614daf9c597b2206cec57c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nathaniel Gordon case</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452511</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1861/1861">1861</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_d2c8fc0bc7fe3968a954acce9da1bfd1" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_96a457c56699b87176cc1133a014be8a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Case documents, chronology of case, and Lincoln correspondence from the National Archives.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_8d8b5a907a99205f41cb7d637715a0bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Congressional documents</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452512</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1774/1872" type="inclusive">1774-1872</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_323869de1cbd62ad93f8e007d5033f51" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><c id="aspace_d0557765cde9df313866a252615618b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>[Acts of Congress and Messages of the Presidents]</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452513</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1774/1858" type="inclusive">1774-1858</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_7f48dc665c4da511ff0c7684a87ae5de" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e26452a5f43fefb114535b216f1494ac" level="file"><did><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452514</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1800/1820" type="inclusive">1800-1820</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_6f0cdf8835e19b094c1e5c0ff4923129" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fed35cc0f84a48bbb5729837440909bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>8-1-171 (8th Congress, 1st session, No. 171). Application to prohibit the import of slaves into the territory of Louisiana. January 23, 1804.</p><p>8-1-173. Slavery, Elective Franchise, and Public Land in Indiana Territory. February 17, 1804.</p><p>8-1-177. Importation of slaves into Louisiana. March 8, 1804.</p><p>9-1-202, 203. Slave Trade [letter from the American Convention for Promoting the Abolition of Slavery]; Extension of the Right of Suffrage, and the Admission of Slavery, for a Limited Time, in the Indiana Territory, and the Division Thereof. February 13-14, 1806.</p><p>9-2-214, 215, 216. Slave Trade; Colonization of People of Color from Virginia; Slavery in the Indiana Territory. January 16, 1807.</p><p>10-1-244. Slave Trade [constitutional amendment prohibiting import of slaves]. February 23, 1808.</p><p>10-2-269. Violation of the Act Prohibiting the Importation of Slaves [New Orleans--domestic slaves (children)]. December 22, 1809.</p><p>11-1-5,7,8. [Slave trade; act for remission of certain penalties and forfeitures--relations with France]. June 24, 1809.</p><p>15-1-290. Suppression of Piratical Establishments. January 10, 1818.</p><p>15-1-441. Slaves Brought into the United States from Amelia Island. January 10, 1818.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_02bbe948568481700cb52c64b5434b9d" level="file"><did><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452515</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1820/1840" type="inclusive">1820-1840</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_3e2e4e50052bf8655efb9f06d4cd06e8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_80000ea1b94807a535fc2072256d18ab"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>16-2-342, 343, 344, 345, 346. Correspondence Respecting Suppression of the Slave Trade; Foreign Vessels Engaged in Smuggling Through Florida; British West India and North America Colonial Trade; Suppression of the Slave Trade--Conference of Foreign Governments on the Subject. January 4-February 9, 1821.</p><p>17-1-351. Suppression of the Slave Trade. April 12, 1822.</p><p>17-1-529. Slaves Imported by an Indian Agent Contrary to Law. May 6, 1822.</p><p>18-1-371. Suppression of Slave Trade. 1824.</p><p>18-2-403. Suppression of the African Slave Trade. February 16, 1825.</p><p>19-1-319. Annual Report of the Secretary of the Navy, Showing the Condition of the Navy in the Year 1826. December 5, 1826.</p><p>19-1-414. Correspondence with Great Britain Relative to the Suppression of the Slave Trade. December 27, 1825.</p><p>20-1-193. Information…in relation to…the United States' Agency for Recaptured Africans... March 12, 1828.</p><p>21-2-435. On the Capture...of the Spanish Ship Fenix, with African Slaves on Board and Under Suspicion of Piratical Intent. January 18, 1831.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_caf62120b320217e53f0f850117cc274" level="file"><did><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452516</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1840/1849" type="inclusive">1840s</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_c7715b82658c2bcdf9d1f01421ffe26f" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f3c5a0af960ddc7c9c0c58d3b80ab077"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>27-1-34. Seizure of American Vessels--Slave Trade. July 14, 1841.</p><p>28-1-217.…information in relation to the abuse of the flag of the United States in subservience to the African slave trade…March 1844.</p><p>29-1-43. African Slave Trade. December 22, 1845.</p><p>30-1-23. …correspondence of Mr. Wise, late United States Minister to Brazil, in relation to the slave trade. March 3, 1848.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_371d4ada14d774aba27c1a5e520ab563" level="file"><did><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452517</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1861" type="inclusive">1850-1861</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_33f86178f605ca0aa4cad7ce006cd939" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_e522821e18c0ed3714e4aa63fcc913bb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4ffd007b4d33dbece69e35da5623dea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>31-2- 6. …documents relating to the African slave trade. December 17, 1850.</p><p>33-1-47. …correspondence between Mr. Schenck, United States Minister to Brazil, and the Secretary of State, in relation to the African slave trade. March 14, 1854.</p><p>33-1-88. …correspondence between Ferdinand Cox, late charge d'affaires of the United States at Brazil, and the Brazilian government... August 2, 1854.</p><p>34-1-99. A resolution of the Senate of April 24, calling for information relative to the coolie trade. 1856.</p><p>34-1-105. Information in regard to the slave and coolie trade. May 19, 1856.</p><p>35-1-49. …reports of the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Navy…in relation to the African slave trade. April 23, 1858.</p><p>35-1-59. In answer to a resolution of the Senate, information concerning the recent search or seizure of American vessels...in the Gulf of Mexico. May 19, 1858.</p><p>35-1-61. …papers in regard to the seizure of the American barque Panchita on the Coast of Africa. May 29, 1858.</p><p>35.2. Central America--Slave Trade--Cuba. Speech of Hon. James B. Clay of Kentucky in the House of Representatives. February 7, 1859.</p><p>36th Congress. [Various documents relating to the slave trade]. 1859-61.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_b332dbfa5267a698bd5a04a3cde99017" level="file"><did><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452518</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1862/1873" type="inclusive">1862-1873</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_3864e5aa52222ebc5ca37af164da8efc" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_00e79a1ba8a795bb48e0c30fbdb68036"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>37-2-53. …information in relation to persons who have been arrested in the southern district of New York, from…May, 1852, to…May, 1862, charged with being engaged in the slave trade… May 30, 1862.</p><p>37-2-57. A copy of the treaty between the United States and her Britannic Majesty for the suppression of the African slave trade. June 10, 1862.</p><p>40-2-260. Information relating to the imprisonment and destruction of the property of Antonio Pelletier by the people and authorities of Hayti. April 3, 1868.</p><p>42.2-30, 31, 32, 33, 34. [Various documents relating to Brazil and Figaniere]. 1871-1872.</p><p>44-1-420. Appleton Oaksmith [Amelia and Magnolia]. 1873.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_7d6ca94749fb0e283f4f325c2d2a2386" level="file"><did><unittitle>Other legal and government documents</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452519</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1807/1879" type="inclusive">1807-1879</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_038dc5f2c71cfe357e66ac7482778461" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c450f4f154a37c09aa436428551f5dd0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The Laws of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts from November 28, 1780 to February 28, 1807…Published by order of the general court. Volume I. Boston, MA: Printed by J.T. Buckingham, for Thomas &amp; Andrews and Manning &amp; Loring, 1807.</p><p>Foreign Slave Trade. Abstract of the information recently laid on the table of the House of Commons on the subject of the slave trade; being a report made…to the Directors of the African Institution… London, UK: Ellerton and Henderson, 1821.</p><p>Potter, Henry, ed. Laws of the State of North Carolina… Raleigh, NC: J. Gales, 1821.</p><p>Prince, Oliver H. A Digest of the Laws of the State of Georgia: containing all statutes and the substance of all resolutions...which have been passed in this state previous to the session of the General Assembly of December, 1820. Milledgeville, GA: Grantland &amp; Orme, 1822.</p><p>Toulmin, Harry. A Digest of the Laws of the State of Alabama: containing the statutes and resolutions in force at the end of the General Assembly in January, 1823. Cahawba, AL: Ginn &amp; Curtis, 1828.</p><p>Private and Special Acts of the State of Maine, passed by the sixteenth legislature. Augusta, ME: Smith and Robinson, 1836.</p><p>Peters, Richard, ed. "Treaties Between the United States of America and Foreign Nations, from [1776]…to 1845."
"The Late Cuba State Trials." United States Democratic Review 30.166, April 1852.</p><p>Rapalje, Stewart. A digest of NY decisions, from the earliest period to July, 1878… Jersey City, NJ: F.D. Linn, 1879.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_25cdfdbabf8c0bc450b17ca340d2e945" level="file"><did><unittitle>British government documents</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452520</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1821/1854" type="inclusive">1821-1854</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_aa74d2cc200068494fd257fd913cea32" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_ed89d4198556c6fb2c1f17d100613c75" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 1.4: Clippings</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452521</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1729/1885" type="inclusive">1729-1885</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_267d1f6f1f6db39f18389f39d96b9fcf" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_8a72e9e84a1064ecef8a96d42f2fa92e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_470f1d7da4550f2600a729ac8a7bb0c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shipping and trade news</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452522</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1729/1862" type="inclusive">1729-1862</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_932dd88166b553616be77cebbec184e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Runaway slave advertisements</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452523</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1730/1835" type="inclusive">1730-1835</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_91a9ebdea2c1791890440c594475f679" level="file"><did><unittitle>Slave sale advertisements</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452524</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1730/1839" type="inclusive">1730-1839</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_bf7e4f99cd2ecadc71bcee83c56b07e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal and legislative news</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452525</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1758/1863" type="inclusive">1758-1863</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_3fd5427e6fa9b1d7dee33942b0e1e31a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Other clippings</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452526</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1760/1885" type="inclusive">1760-1885</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_43e72fc63f263a6153b8a6b20e9770fc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes, among others:</p><p>"The Pirates." Connecticut Courant, September 8 1834. [Coleman notes: Discussion of Spanish-Cuban Pirates and Salem vessel the "Mexican." Note-Spanish that were slavers and pirates.]</p><p>"The Slave Trade.--Our Late Consul at Rio, Mr. Gordon." Daily Atlas, Boston, August 27 1846.</p><p>"North American Slavery: Practical Difficulties in the Way of Emancipation." From the London "Household Words," edited by Charles Dickens. New York Times, November 10 1852, p. 3.</p><p>"Enslavement of a British Subject." New York Times, July 10 1857, p. 1.</p><p>"The Slave-Trade. 'Something is Rotten in the State of Denmark.'" [letter to the editor]. New York Times, January 17 1861.</p><p>"Parson Beecher and the Fugitive Slave Law." Brooklyn Eagle, June 27 1861.</p><p>"Hon. Moses F. Odell." Harper's Weekly, June 14 1862, p. 381.</p><p>"Greeley's Scout. Confession Made by the Notorious Blumenberg." New York Times, August 7 1872, p. 3.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_98f1c4c214ee965f63d6ae8af62d3fe8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nathaniel Gordon case</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452527</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846/1849" type="inclusive">1846-1849</unitdate></did></c><c id="aspace_760bb0c9463aec73918ea43f0a154018" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gazaway Bugg Lamar</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452528</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1876" type="inclusive">1851-1876</unitdate></did><relatedmaterial id="aspace_966a748286c8df19181fe72f44252907"><head>Related Materials</head><p>See also related content in Series 2.</p></relatedmaterial><scopecontent id="aspace_f2e40ea88dda58f3e71bca904c5898da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Some of these articles relate to Rev. Henry Van Dyke, but were filed by Coleman under the folder heading indicated here and have been kept as such.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_58ec603b769a0abc53afaa29ee78b151" level="file"><did><unittitle>Slave trade from Asia</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452529</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1878" type="inclusive">1851-1878</unitdate></did><processinfo id="aspace_3476f742e473a91cae826afbc501a091"><head>Processing Information</head><p>The original files that make up this folder all had "coolie" in the title. The archivist renamed this file.</p></processinfo><scopecontent id="aspace_33429857494ec0139ff299c1502578ef"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to clippings, this file includes printouts of 1850s-60s register entries for the ships Norway, Wm. M. Groton, Flora Temple, and Sunny South, arranged alphabetically by ship name. There is also a page of Coleman's notes as well as printouts about Amoy, China and the ship Sea Witch.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_65f16f656b022ac998eb850709b05fc2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harrison S. Vining New York Times articles</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452530</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1867" type="inclusive">1855-1867</unitdate></did></c></c><c id="aspace_42ce0e2a7c75c90800921c32a9744a62" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 1.5: Oaksmith family</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452531</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846/1896" type="inclusive">1846-1896</unitdate></did><arrangement id="aspace_b56bcdeb1c857d055ba0f9fe3f0433f8"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Within each section, documents are arranged roughly chronologically.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_e756a5f1c24c3e5ff8b4ea74af698632" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452532</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857/1870" type="inclusive">1857-1870</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_05ebdf4b8ed70b80d97a14233eee1f99" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f4534944e2c47a61c44f00c24ce5dbf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Is the Thomas Watson A Slaver." New York Times, November 30 1857.</p><p>"The Capture of the Schooner Lydia Gibbs." New York Herald 23.304, November 2 1858.</p><p>"The African Slave Trade. Five New Slavers Under Way. Two Vessels Captured." Evening Post 59.293, December 14 1860.</p><p>"City Religious Press." New York Evangelist, June 26 1862.</p><p>"The Case of the People Against Mr. Woodford," "Greeley and Woodford," "New Evidence Against Gen. Woodford," "The Slave Trader Convicted to a Demonstration." Brooklyn Eagle, October 1870. (Stewart L. Woodford, scandal over escape of Oaksmith.)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_43fa609c65c0a4112b57f6cd3e584af9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Legal and government documents</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452533</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1876" type="inclusive">1851-1876</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_a1499bb4ff25b64f3e807da5f325ac6e" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">2</container><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_f9ac5bfa97478b7afcf29cabbd40cffb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_616a8fbd835056adcd25c2ab6995b88a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Wm. Bourgoyne and John Plume vs. The Steam Ship Gold Hunter. United States District Court, San Francisco. August 18, 1851.</p><p>United States v. Appleton Oaksmith, U.S. D.C. Mass (1861). Margaret Scott</p><p>Bark Augusta--cargo seized and related documents. June 25, 1862.</p><p>44-1-123. Connection of Hon. Robert C. Schenck with the Emma Mine and Machado Claim. February 25, 1876. (Vessels Thomas Watson &amp; Mary Varney.)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_fd1e3537d8dccc6f34ccbbb9ebc9165f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Appleton Oaksmith</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452534</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1873" type="inclusive">circa 1850s-1873</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_a2450d3f5da6530ab262b2276d558fad" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b380d22de52a31bbb24cda1ae8ac9b04"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Appleton Oaksmith documents from East Carolina University, Special Collections Department, Joyner Library. circa 1850s-1880s.</p><p>Brig Mary Adeline and Brig Camargo documents, 1851.</p><p>Haitian shipping manifests, 1854.</p><p>Appleton Oaksmith journal [held at Duke]. 1855.</p><p>[Appleton Oaksmith writings], 1855-1874.</p><p>Goicouria and Avezzano letters, 1856.</p><p>Document regarding Oaksmith's appointment as a commissioner from NYC to the Southern states, 1861.</p><p>Dispatches from the United States Consul in Havana relating to Appleton Oaksmith [from vertical files at Rosenberg Library, Galveston, TX], 1864.</p><p>"Southern State Debts and the National Currency..." The Southern Magazine 8, 1873.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_07e6b9171373d47e8f91f7849de4dd65" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elizabeth Oakes Smith</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452535</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846/1896" type="inclusive">1846-1896</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_d2197a3d6734bbf24027b64c95e4dd54" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af14c4dd4a905da5b53b84bb080290f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Letters to and from John Neal and Mary Neal Sherwood, 1846-1856.</p><p>May, Caroline. The American Female Poets: with biographical and critical notices. Philadelphia, PA: Lindsay &amp; Blakiston, 1853.</p><p>Scrapbook pages with clippings. 1869-1880</p><p>Elizabeth Oakes Smith documents at New York Public Library. circa 1870s-1890s</p><p>A Human Life, Being the Autobiography of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. circa 1885</p><p>Cohen, Isabel E., compiler. Readings and Recitations for Jewish Homes and Schools. Philadelphia, PA: The Jewish Publication Society of America, 1896, pp. 118-120, "The Jewish Captive" by Elizabeth Oakes Smith.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_aea577b856bdbf784d940072dc203672" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seba Smith</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452536</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/2019" type="inclusive">1851-1872, 2019</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_7012355f1d94249b7bc506171bdab264" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba56a1e262ecb1a6536acc6dc0a8e739"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Seba Smith-Jack Downing letter, 1851. [Coleman notes: "probably not real."]</p><p>Camp, David N., ed. The American year book and national register for 1869… p. 796. Entry for Seba Smith.</p><p>Griffin, Joseph, ed. History of the press of Maine, Bowdoin. 1872. pp. 54-55 re: The Courier, founded by Seba Smith.</p><p>Seba Smith family tree, 2019.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_51eca6867d44b087f0a28edd2e73f3d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Other documents</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452537</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1852/1883" type="inclusive">1852-1883</unitdate><container altrender="Full Manuscript Box Legal" id="aspace_ad05042b937efcff18e7e12ff2df8e47" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_86c94343bc93a97b998c00cbb0a7a738"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[Naval correspondence], 1852-1853.</p><p>The Appeal of the Religious Society of Friends in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Delaware, etc., to their fellow-citizens of the United States on behalf of the Coloured Races. Philadelphia, PA: Friends' Book-store, 1858, pp. 18-21.</p><p>The Great Republic Monthly, July 1859. New York, NY: Oaksmith &amp; Co. [original magazine]</p><p>Mix, Jacob. "The Biter Bit; or the Robert Macaire of Journalism. Being a Narrative of Some of the Black-mailing Operations of Charles A. Dana's 'Sun.'" Washington, DC: 1870, pp. 59-69.</p><p>[Selections from magazine] Old Times in North Yarmouth, Maine. Yarmouth, ME: Augustus W. Corliss, 1877-1884. [family history]</p><p>Betts, George F. "Memorial of Chancellor Erastus Cornelius Benedict." Proceedings of the Nineteenth Meeting of the University Convocation of the State of New York, held July 12-14, 1881. Albany, NY: Weed, Parsons and Company, 1883.</p></scopecontent></c></c></c><c id="aspace_161a3da8af637645aa44e08c36888415" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 2: Secondary sources </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452538</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1900/2021" type="inclusive">1900-2021</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_5a7cb3ca582f5266d8ff2548b09f08d7" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 2.1: Articles </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452539</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1900/2021" type="inclusive">1900-2021</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_081a9e463a6a01e94089325b3cd39cab" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">4</container><container id="aspace_cb3a54cb09c6ac4899f439ef5f873989" parent="aspace_081a9e463a6a01e94089325b3cd39cab" type="Folder">A-P</container><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_888c1448ee0e28a1f07c566d25707a44" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container><container id="aspace_effd40e5329fdefce03a32dc8c61ca97" parent="aspace_888c1448ee0e28a1f07c566d25707a44" type="Folder">R-Y</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_cb3ce548fa993e886919956fdf0f6900"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by author name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_51c10bb432a4375767dca52f84950448"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Alexander, Arthur J., Federal Officeholders in New York State as Slaveholders 1789-1805. The Journal of Negro History 28.3, July 1943.</p><p>Allen, Richard B., Licentious and Unbridled Proceedings: The Illegal Slave Trade to Mauritius and the Seychelles During the Early Nineteenth Century. The Journal of African History 42.1, January 2001.</p><p>American Historical Association, AHA Council Issues Policy Resolution about Jews and the Slave Trade. Perspectives, March 1995.</p><p>Andrews, Charles M., Colonial Commerce. The American Historical Review 20.1, October 1914.</p><p>Anonymous, Eighteenth Century Slaves as Advertised by their Masters. The Journal of Negro History 1.2, April 1916.</p><p>Avallone, Charlene, Catharine Sedgwick and the Circles of New York. Legacy 23.2, 2006.</p><p>Bankoff, H. Arthur and Frederick A. Winter, The Archaeology of Slavery at the Van Cortlandt Plantation in the Bronx, New York. International Journal of Historical Archaeology 9.4, December 2005.</p><p>Barker, Eugene C., The African Slave Trade in Texas. Southwestern Historical Quarterly 6.2, October 1902.</p><p>BBC News, Ex-Slave Takes Niger to Court. BBC News, April 7 2008.</p><p>Bearss, Sara B., Henry Clay and the American Claims Against Portugal, 1850. Journal of the Early Republic 7.2, Summer 1987.</p><p>Behrendt, Stephen D., The Annual Volume and Regional Distribution of the British Slave Trade, 1780-1807. The Journal of African History 38.2, July 1997.</p><p>Bell, Herbert C., The West India Trade Before the American Revolution. American Historical Review 22, January 1917.</p><p>Berlin, Ira, From Creole to African: Atlantic Creoles and the Origins of African American Society in Mainland North America. The William and Mary Quarterly 53.2, April 1996.</p><p>Block, W.T., Sabine Lake: Focal Point of the Illegal African Slave Trade. Reprinted from the Beaumont Enterprise, April 4 1974, February 5, 1984.</p><p>Blue, A.D., Chinese Emigration and the Deck Passenger Trade. Journal of the Hong Kong Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society 10, 1970.</p><p>Blumberg, Arnold, Diplomacy of the Mexican Empire, 1863-1867. Transactions of the American Philosophical Society 61 Part 8, 1971.</p><p>Boardman, Helen M., First Families of Manhattan. Phylon (1940-1956) 5.2, 1944.</p><p>Bonner, Willard Hallam, "Clamors and False Stories": The Reputation of Captain Kidd. The New England Quarterly 17.2, June 1944.</p><p>Brookhiser, Richard, Alexander Hamilton: New Yorker. City Journal, Autumn 1996.</p><p>Brown, Everett S., The Presidential Election of 1824-1825. Political Science Quarterly 40.3, September 1925.</p><p>Buranelli, Vincent, The Myth of Anna Zenger. The William and Mary Quarterly 13.2, April 1956.</p><p>Burnard, Trevor and Kenneth Morgan, The Dynamics of the Slave Market and Slave Purchasing Patterns in Jamaica, 1655-1788. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.</p><p>Burr, John E., International Repercussions of the Haitian Revolution. The Americas 26.4, April 1970.</p><p>Cahill, Barry, The Black Loyalists Myth in Atlantic Canada. Acadiensis: Journal of the History of the Atlantic Region 29.1, Autumn 1999.</p><p>Calhoun, Gordon, The Flagship in Africa: USS Cumberland and the Slave Trade Patrols. The Daybook: A Publication of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 10.3, circa 2006.</p><p>Cameron, Catherine M., How Captives Changed the World. Scientific American, December 2017.</p><p>Capizzi, Joseph E., For What Shall We Repent? Reflections on the American Bishops, Their Teachings, and Slavery in the United States, 1839-1861. Theological Studies 65.4, December 2004.</p><p>Carrington, Selwyn H.H., Capitalism &amp; Slavery and Caribbean Historiography: An Evaluation. The Journal of African American History 88.3, Summer 2003.</p><p>Chaney, Michael A., Gender Reversal and Cultural Critique in Frances Osgood's Poetry. ATQ (The American Transcendental Quarterly) 14.1, March 2000.</p><p>Coddington, Edwin B. The Activities and Attitudes of a Confederate Business Man: Gazaway B. Lamar. The Journal of Southern History 9.1, February 1943.</p><p>Cohen, Lucy, The Chinese of the Panama Railroad: Preliminary Notes on the Migrants of 1854 Who "Failed." Ethnohistory 18.4, Autumn 1971.</p><p>Corbitt, Duvon C., Immigration in Cuba. The Hispanic American Historical Review 22.2, May 1942.</p><p>Corbitt, D.C., Shipment of Slaves from the United States to Cuba, 1789-1807, pp.548-549. The Journal of Southern History 7.4, November 1941.</p><p>Cox, James M., New England Humor: From the Revolutionary War to the Civil War. The Journal of American History 81.4, March 1995.</p><p>Curry-Machado, How Cuba Burned with the Ghosts of British Slavery: Race, Abolition, and the Escalera. Slavery and Abolition 25.1, April 2004.</p><p>Davis, Robert Ralph Jr., James Buchanan and the Suppression of the Slave Trade, 1858-1861. Pennsylvania History 33.4, October 1966.</p><p>Davis, Robert Ralph Jr., Buchanian Espionage: A Report on Illegal Slave Trading in the South in 1859. The Journal of Southern History 37.2, May 1971.</p><p>de la Cova, Antonio Rafael, Cuban Filibustering in Jacksonville in 1851. Northeast Florida History: The Journal of the Jacksonville Historical Society, 1996.</p><p>de la Cova, Antonio Rafael, Filibusters and Freemasons: The Sworn Obligation. Journal of the Early Republic 17.1, Spring 1997.</p><p>DeJong, Gerald Francis, The Dutch Reformed Church and Negro Slavery in Colonial America. Church History 40.4, December 1971.</p><p>Delaney, Norman C., Raphael Semmes: The Philosophical Mariner. The Journal of Military History 62.3, July 1998.</p><p>Desrocjers, Robert E. Jr., Slave-for-Sale Advertisements and Slavery in Massachussetts, 1704-1781. The William and Mary Quarterly 59.3, July 2002.</p><p>Dierksheide, Christa, "The Great Improvement and Civilization of that Race": Jefferson and the "Amelioration" of Slavery, ca. 1770-1826. Early American Studies, Spring 2008.</p><p>Dodd, Dorothy, The Schooner Emperor: An Incident of the Illegal Slave Trade in Florida. The Florida Historical Society Quarterly 13.3, January 1935.</p><p>Drake, Frederick C. and R.W. Shufeldt, Secret History of the Slave Trade to Cuba Written By an American Naval Officer, Robert Wilson Schufeldt, 1861. The Journal of Negro History 55.3, 1970.</p><p>Eltis, David, Free and Coerced Transatlantic Migrations: Some Comparisons. The American Historical Review 88.2, April 1983.</p><p>Eltis, David, Senegambia and the African Slave Trade (Review). The Journal of Interdisciplanary History 30.3, Winter 1999.</p><p>Eltis, David, The Volume and Structure of the Transatlantic Slave Trade: A Reassessment. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, 2001.</p><p>Eltis, David, The U.S. Transatlantic Slave Trade, 1644-1867: An Assessment. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.</p><p>Ely, Roland T., The Old Cuba Trade: Highlights and Case Studies of Cuban-American Interdependence during the Nineteenth Century. The Business History Review 38.4, Winter 1964.</p><p>Fattah, Hassan M., A Nation with a Long Memory, but a Truncated History. The New York Times, January 10 2007.</p><p>Fickling, David, Pacific islands appeal to UK for "slave voyages" compensation. The Guardian, April 13 2004.</p><p>Fiehrer, Thomas, Saint-Dominigue/Haiti: Louisiana's Caribbean Connection. Louisiana History: The Journal of the Louisiana Historical Association 30.4, Autumn 1989.</p><p>Finkelman, Paul, Regulating the African Slave Trade. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.</p><p>Fitzgerald, Frances, Peculiar Instiutions: Brown University Looks at the Slave Traders in its Past. The New Yorker, September 12 2005.</p><p>Foschio, Leslie G., A History of the Development of the Office of United States Commisioner and Magistrate Judge System. Federal Courts Law Review 4, 1999.</p><p>Foy, Charles R., Seeking Freedom in the Atlantic World, 1713-1783. Early American Studies: An Interdisciplanary Journal 4.1, 2006.</p><p>Franke, Katherine, Making Good on the Broken Promise of Reparations. New York Review of Books, March 2019.</p><p>Freechling, William W., The Founding Fathers and Slavery. The American Historical Review 77.1, February 1972.</p><p>Freudenberger, Herman and Jonathon B. Pritchett, The Domestic United States Slave Trade: New Evidence. Journal of Interdisciplinary History 21.3, Winter 1991.</p><p>Friedman, Lee M., The First Chamber of Commerce in the United States. Bulletin of the Business Historical Society 21.5, November 1947.</p><p>Gardiner, Clinton Harvey, Early Diplomatic Relations Between Mexico and the Far East. The Americas 6.4, April 1950.</p><p>Geggus, David, The French Slave Trade: An Overview. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.</p><p>Gellman, David, Pirates, Sugar, Debtors, and Slaves: Political Economy and the Case for Gradual Abolition in New York. Slavery and Abolition 22.2, August 2001.</p><p>Ghachem, Malick W., The Slave's Two Bodies: The Life of an American Legal Fiction. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.4, 2003.</p><p>Gray, Elizabeth Kelly, "Whisper to him the word 'India'': Trans-Atlantic Critics and American Slavery, 1830-1860. Journal of the Early Republic 27, Fall 2008.</p><p>Guyatt, Nicholas, America's Conservatory: Race, Reconstruction, and the Santo Domingo Debate. The Journal of American History, March 2011.</p><p>Harmon, George D., The Northern Clergy and the Impending Crisis, 1830-1860. Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography 65, April 1941.</p><p>Harp, Susan, Panama Railroad Heyday 1848-1869, 2001.</p><p>Harper, Douglas, Northern Profits from Slavery. Early America Review, 2004.</p><p>Harris, Dilue I., The Reminiscences of Mrs. Dilue Harris. Southwestern Historical Quarterly 4, 1901.</p><p>Helfman, Tata, The Court of Vice Admiralty at Sierra Leone and the Abolition of the West African Slave Trade. Yale Law Journal 115.5, March 2006.</p><p>Hershkowitz, Leo, Original Inventories of Early New York Jews (1682-1763). American Jewish History 90.3, September 2002.</p><p>Hill, Lawrence F., The Abolition of the African Slave Trade to Brazil. The Hispanic American Historical Review 11.2, May 1931.</p><p>Hirsch, Leo H., Jr., The Slave in New York. The Journal of Negro History 16.4, October 1931.</p><p>Hoganson, Kristin, "As Badly Off as the Filipinos": U.S. Women's Suffragists and the Imperial Issue at the Turn of the Twentieth Century. Journal of Women's History 13.2, Summer 2001.</p><p>Horton, Welsey W., The Pre-Civil War Connecticut Supreme Court. The Connecticut Law Review 34, 2002.</p><p>Howard, Allen M., Nineteenth Century Coastal Slave Trading and the British Abolition Campaign in Sierra Leone. Slavery and Abolition 27.1, April 2006.</p><p>Howe, Adrian, The Bayard Treason Trial: Dramatizing Anglo-Dutch Politics in Early Eighteenth Century New York City. The William and Mary Quarterly 47.1, January 1990.</p><p>Hughes, Lynn Gordon, Richard Hildreth. Dictionary of Unitarian and Universalist Biography, circa 1999-2005.</p><p>Ireland, Ralph R., Slavery on Long Island: A Study of Economic Motivation. Journal of Long Island History 6.2, 1966.</p><p>Jordon, Philip D., Humor of the Backwoods, 1820-1840. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 25.1, June 1938.</p><p>Judd, Jacob, Brooklyn's Changing Population in the Pre-Civil War Era. Journal of Long Island History 4.2, 1964.</p><p>Judd, Jacob, Frederick Philipse and the Madagascar Trade. New York Historical Society Quarterly 51, 1967.</p><p>Junh, Moon-Ho, Outlawing Coolies: Race, Nation, and Empire in the Age of Emancipation. American Quarterly 57.3, 2005.</p><p>Kelley, Sean, Blackbirders and Bozales: African-Born Slaves on the Lower Brazos River of Texas in the Nineteenth Century. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.</p><p>Kim, Sung Bok, A New Look at the Great Landlords of Eighteenth-Century New York. The William and Mary Quarterly 27.4, October 1970.</p><p>Klein, Herbert S., The English Slave Trade to Jamaica, 1782-1808. The Economic History Review 31.1, February 11 2008.</p><p>Klein, Herbert S., Stanley L. Engerman, Robin Haines, and Ralph Shlomowitz, Transatlantic Mortality: The Slave Trade in Comparative Perspective. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.</p><p>Knox, Bruce, The Queen's Letter of 1865 and British Policy towards Emancipation and Indentured Labor in the West Indies, 1830-1865. The Historical Journal 29.2, June 1986.</p><p>Landry, Harral E., Slavery and the Slave Trade in Atlantic Diplomacy, 1850-1861. The Journal of Southern History 27.2 [2 copies], May 1961.</p><p>Lane, Calvin, The African Squadron: The U.S. Navy and the Slave Trade, 1820-1862. The Log of Mystic Seaport 50.4, 1999.</p><p>Lebergott, Stanley. Why the South Lost: Commercial Purpose in the Confederacy 1861-1865. The Journal of American History 70.1, June 1983.</p><p>Leisy, Ernest E., American Idiom in the Major Downing Letters, pp.78-79. American Speech 8.2, April 1933.</p><p>Lin, Rachel Chernos, The Rhode Island Slave-Traders: Butchers, Bakers and Candlestick-Makers. Slavery and Abolition 23.3, December 2002.</p><p>Lock, Sarah J., Legacy Bookshelf (Bibliography). Leagcy: A Journal of American Women Writers 20.1-2, January-June 2003.</p><p>Lockett, James D., The Last Ship That Brought Slaves From Africa to America: The Landing of the Cotilde at Mobile in the Autumn of 1859. The Western Journal of Black Studies 22.3, Fall 1998.</p><p>Lorimer, Douglas A., Black Slaves and English Liberty: A Re-examination of Racial Slavery in England. Immigrants &amp; Minorities 3.2, 1984.</p><p>Luis-Brown, David, An 1848 for the Americas: The Black Atlantic, "El Negro mártir," and Cuban Exile Anticolonialism in New York City. Oxford University Press, 2009.</p><p>Lydon, James G., New York and the Slave Trade. The William and Mary Quarterly 35.2, April 1978.</p><p>MacMaster, Richard K., ed., Long Islandiana: Negro loyalists of Long Island: unpublished petitions from the American loyalist transcripts, New York Public Library. Journal of Long Island History 4.2, 1964.</p><p>Manz, William H., "A Just Cause for War": New York's Dred Scott Decision. NYSBA Journal, November-December 2007.</p><p>Marsh, Richard C. The Military Trial of Gazaway Bugg Lamar. The Georgia Historical Quarterly 85.4, Winter 2001.</p><p>Mason, Matthew, The Battle of the Slaveholding Liberators: Great Britain, the United States, and Slavery in the Early Nineteenth Century. The William and Mary Quarterly 59.3, July 2002.</p><p>Mathis, Robert Neil. "Gazaway Bugg Lamar: A Southern Businessman and Confidant in New York City." New York History 56.3, July 1975.</p><p>Matthews, Jean, Race, Sex, and the Dimensions of Liberty in Antebellum America. Journal of the Early Republic 6.3, Autumn 1986.</p><p>May, Robert E., Young American Males and Filibustering in the Age of Manifest Destiny: The United States Army as a Cultural Mirror. The Journal of American History 78.3, December 1991.</p><p>McAdams Sibley, Marilyn. James Hamilton, Jr. vs. Sam Houston: Repurcussions of the Nullification Controversy. The Southwestern Historical Quarterly 89.2, October 1985.</p><p>McCain, William D., The Filibuster: The Career of William Walker. The Hispanic American Historical Review 18.4, November 1938.</p><p>McGrath, Ben, Strangers on the Mountain. The New Yorker, March 1 2010.</p><p>McKenzie, Robert Tracy, Contesting Secession: Parson Brownlow and the Rhetoric of Proslavery Unionism, 1860-1861. Civil War History 48.4, December 2002.</p><p>McKinley, Albert E., The English and Dutch Towns of New Netherland. American Historical Review 6, October 1900.</p><p>Menschel, David, Abolition Without Deliverance: the Law of Connecticut Slavery 1784-1848. Yale Law Journal 111, 2001.</p><p>Middleton, Simon, "How it Came that the Bakers Bake no Bread": A Struggle for Trade Privileges in Seventeenth-Century New Amsterdam. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.2, 2001.</p><p>Mitton, Steven Heath, The Upshur Inquiry: Lost Lessons of the Great Experiment. Slavery and Abolition 27.1, April 2006.</p><p>Moglen, Eben, Considering Zenger: Partisan Politics and the Legal Profession in Provincial New York. Columbia Law Review, 1994.</p><p>Moore, Rayburn S., "A Great Poet and Original Genius": Hayne Champions Poe. The Southern Literary Journal 16.1, Fall 1983.</p><p>Morgan, Kenneth, Slave Sales in Colonial Charleston. The English Historical Review 113.453 [2 copies], September 1998.</p><p>Morrison, Michael A., American Reaction to European Revolutions, 1848-1852 Sectionalism, Memory, and the Revolutionary Heritage. Civil War History 49.2, June 2003.</p><p>Mosier, Joe, We Are Mere Scarecrows: USS Dale in the Africa Squadron, 1857-1859. The Day Book: A Newsletter for the Supporters of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 4.6, September-October 1998.</p><p>Mosier, Joe, United States v. The Bark William G. Lewis: The Navy Brings a Slave Ship to Norfolk. The Daybook: A Publication of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 10.4, 2006.</p><p>Mosier, Joe, Fighting Terror on the High Seas: The Navy Organizes to Fight the Real Pirates of the Caribbean. The Daybook: A Publication of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 14.1, 2009.</p><p>Moss, Simeon F., The Persistence of Slavery and Involuntary Servitude in a Free State (1685-1866.) The Journal of Negro History 35.3, July 1950.</p><p>Nash, Gary B., Slaves and Slaveowners in Colonial Philadelphia. The William and Mary Quarterly 30.2, April 1973.</p><p>Needell, Jeffrey D., The Abolition of the Brazilian Slave Trade in 1850: Historiography, slave agency and statesmenship. Journal of Latin American Studies 33.4, November 2001.</p><p>Nickels, Cameron C., Seba Smith. Dictionary of Literary Biography, Volume 243: The American Renaissance in New England, 2001.</p><p>Nickels, Cameron C., Seba Smith Embattled. Maine Historical Society Quarterly 13.1, Summer 1973.</p><p>Northrup, David, Free and Unfree Labor Migration, 1600-1900: An Introduction. Journal of World History 14.2, June 2003.</p><p>Orenstein, Jeffrey, Joseph Almeida: Portrait of a Privateer, Pirate &amp; Plaintiff, Part I. The Green Bag 10.3, Spring 2007.</p><p>Patterson, Cynthia, "Illustration of a Picture": Nineteenth-Century Writers and the Philadelphia Pictorials. American Periodicals 19.2, 2009.</p><p>Pearson, Susan J., "Infantile Specimens": Showing Babies in Nineteenth-Century America. Journal of Social History, Winter 2008.</p><p>Perkins, Howard C., The Defense of Slavery in the Northern Press on the Eve of the Civil War. The Journal of Southern History 9.4, November 1943.</p><p>Petrulionis, Sandra Harbert, "Swelling that Great Tide of Himanity": The Concord, Massachusetts, Female Anti-Slavery Society. The New England Quarterly 74.3, September 2001.</p><p>Pettit, Marilyn H., Slavery, Abolition, and Columbia University. Journal of Archival Organization 1.4, 2002.</p><p>Phillips, Lawrence, British Slavery after Abolition: the Pacific Trade. Race and Class 41.3, January-March 2000.</p><p>Pitts, Charles O Jr., Shadows on a Hillside: Robert E. Lee and Elizabeth Oakes Prince Smith, circa 1980s-1990s.</p><p>Platt, Virginia Bever, The East India Company and the Madagascar Slave Trade. The William and Mary Quarterly 26.4, October 1969.</p><p>Pybus, Cassandra, Jefferson's Faulty Math: The Question of Slave Defections in the American Revolution. The William and Mary Quarterly 62.2, 2005.</p><p>Ray, Angela G., Performing Womanhood: The Lyceum Lectures of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Society for the Study of American Women Writers Conference, November 2006.</p><p>Ray, Angela G., What Hath She Wrought? Woman's Rights and the Nineteenth-Century Lyceum. Rhetoric and Public Affairs 9.2, 2006.</p><p>Redway, Virginia Larkin, A New York Concert in 1736. The Musical Quarterly 22.2, April 1936.</p><p>Reilly, Kevin S., Slavers in Disguise: American Whaling and the African Slave Trade, 1845-1862, circa 1992.</p><p>Riddell, William Renwick, The Slave in Early New York. The Journal of Negro History 13.1, January 1928.</p><p>Riding, Alan, Britain Confronts Legacy of Slave Trade. The New York Times, March 20 2007.</p><p>Rink, Oliver A., The People of New Netherland: Notes on Non-English Immigration to New York and the Seventeenth Century. New York History, circa 1980.</p><p>Rippy, J. Fred, Diplomacy of the United States and Mexico Regarding the Isthmus of Tehuantepec, 1848-1860. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 6.4, March 1920.</p><p>Rippy, J. Fred, Anglo-American Filibusters and the Gadson Treaty. The Hispanic American Historical Review 5.2, May 1922.</p><p>Roberts, William I., III, Samuel Storke: An Eighteenth-Century London Merchant Trading to the American Colonies. The Business History Review 39.2, Summer 1965.</p><p>Robson Hay, Thomas. Gazaway Bugg Lamar, Confederate Banker and Business Man. The Georgia Historical Quarterly 37.2, June 1953.</p><p>Rodriguez, J. Javier, The US-Mexican War in James Lowell's The Biglow Papers. Arizona Quarterly 63.3, Autumn 2007.</p><p>Rommel-Ruiz, W. Bryan, Colonizing the Black Atlantic: The African Colonization Movements in Postwar Rhode Island and Nova Scotia. Slavery and Abolition 27.3, December 2006.</p><p>Rose, Jane F., Expanding Woman's Sphere, Dismantling Class, and Building Community: The Feminism of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. CLA Journal 45.2, December 2001.</p><p>Rothstein, Richard, Books Often Give History a Facelift. The New York Times, October 2 2002.</p><p>Rutman, Darrett B., Governor Winthrop's Garden Crop: The Significance of Agriculture in the Early Commerce of Massachusetts Bay. The William and Mary Quarterly 20.3, July 1963.</p><p>Salas, Antonion, Angel Carracedo, Martin Richards and Vincent Macauley, Charting the Ancestry of African Americans (Report). American Journal of Human Genetics 77.4, October 2005.</p><p>Scherman, Timothy H., "Onward!" New Paths of Inquiry for the Future of Oakes Smith Studies. Society for the Study of Women Writers Conference, November 2006.</p><p>Schlesinger, Arthur M. Jr., The Problem of Richard Hildreth. The New England Quarterly 13.2, June 1940.</p><p>Schorsch, Jonathan, American Jewish Historians, Colonial Jews and Blacks, and the Limits of Wissenschaft: A Critical Review. Jewish Social Studies 6.2, Winter 2000.</p><p>Schroeder, John H., Major Jack Downing and American Expansionism: Seba Smith's Political Satire, 1847-1856. The New England Quarterly 50.2, June 1977.</p><p>Scroggins, Mark. Georgia, New York, and Muskets on the Eve of the Civil War. The Georgia Historical Quarterly 89.3, Fall 2005.</p><p>Scroggs, William O., William Walker's Designs on Cuba. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 1.2, September 1914.</p><p>Scudder, Harold, A Note on Major Jack Downing. The New England Quarterly 11.3, September 1938.</p><p>Senechal, Roberta, A Respectable Rebel: Elizabeth Oakes Smith and the Dilemma of Victorian Feminism. University of Virginia lecture draft, 1985.</p><p>Shaw, Wayne, The Plymouth Pulpit: Henry Ward Beecher's Slave Auction Block. ATQ (The American Transcendental Quarterly) 14.4, December 2000.</p><p>Sheridan, R.B., The Commercial and Financial Organization of the British Slave Trade, 1750-1807. The Economic History Review 11.2, 1958.</p><p>Sherwood, Marika, Perfidious Albion: Britain, the USA, and Slavery in the 1840s and 1860s. Contributions in Black Studies 13, 1995.</p><p>Sherwood, Marika, Britain, the slave trade and slavery, 1808-1843. Race and Class 46.2, October-December 2004.</p><p>Shillingburg, Patricia and Edward, The Disposition of Slaves on East End of Long Island from 1680 to 1796, 2003.</p><p>Shorto, Russell, All Political Ideas are Local: Why Liberalism and Most Other American Ways of Thinking About Politics Have Their Roots in Manhattan. The New York Times Magazine, October 2 2005.</p><p>Smallwood, Arwin D., A History of Native American and African Relations from 1502 to 1900. Negro History Bulletin, April-September 1999.</p><p>Smith, Lucille Arthur, The Oaksmith Saga. Prepared for the Carteret County Historical Society meeting, 1960.</p><p>Smythe, Augustine T. and Sister Sue. Excerpts from the Wartime Correspondence of Augustine T. Smythe. The South Carolina Historical Magazine 62.1, January 1961.</p><p>Solow, Barbara L., The Transatlantic Slave Trade: A New Census. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, 2001.</p><p>Spector, Robert M., Lincoln and Taney: A Study in Consitutional Polarization. The American Journal of Legal History 15.3, July 1971.</p><p>Staples, Brent, Slaves in the Family: One Generation's Shame is Another's Revelation. The New York Times, June 15 2003.</p><p>Steward, Irvin, American Treaty Provisions Relating to Consular Privileges and Immunities. The American Journal of International Law 20.1, January 1926.</p><p>Straysbaugh, John, On the Trail of Brooklyn's Underground Railroad. The New York Times, October 12 2007.</p><p>Stryker-Rodda, Harriet Mott, Brooklyn and Long Island Sanitary Fair 1864. Journal of Long Island History 4.1, 1964.</p><p>Swan, Robert J., John Teasman: African-American Educator and the Emergence of Cmomunity in Early Black New York City, 1787-1815. Journal of the Early Republic 12.3, Autumn 1992.</p><p>Swan, Robert J., First Africans into New Netherland, 1625 or 1626? Halve Maen 66, Winter 1993.</p><p>Swan, Robert J., The Other Fort Amsterdam: New Light on Aspects of Slavery in New Netherland. Afro-Americans in New York Life and History 22.2, July 31 1998.</p><p>Sweeney, Kevin, Early American Religious Traditions: Native Visions and Christian Providence. OAH Magazine of History 22.1, January 2008.</p><p>Talbot, Margaret, Supreme Confidence: The Jurisprudence of Justice Antonin Scalia. The New Yorker, March 28, 2005.</p><p>TePaske, John Jay, Appleton Oaksmith, Filibuster Agent. The North Carolina Historical Review 35, January-October 1958.</p><p>Thomas, Robert Paul and Richard Nelson Bean, Fishers of Men: The Profits of the Slave Trade. The Journal of Economic History 34.4, December 1974.</p><p>Thornton, John, Cannibals, Witches, and Slave Traders in the Atlantic World. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.2, 2003.
Tice, Pam, Enslaved African Americans in Bloomingdale. West Side Rag, May 29 2021.</p><p>Treudley, Mary, The United States and Santo Domingo, 1789-1866. The Journal of Race Development 7.1, July 1916.</p><p>Tuchinsky, Adam-Max, "The Bourgeousie Will Fall and Fall Forever": The New-York Tribune, the 1848 French Revolution, and American Social Democratic Discourse. The Journal of American History 92.2, September 2005.</p><p>Tuchinsky, Adam, "Woman and Her Needs": Elizabeth Oakes Smith and the Divorce Question. Journal of Women's History 28.1, Spring 2016.</p><p>Van Cleve, George, Forum: Somerset's Case Revisited: Somerset's Case and Its Antecedents in Imperial Perspective. Law and History Review 24.3, Fall 2006.</p><p>Vink, Marcus, "The world's oldest trade": Dutch slavery and slave trade in the Indian Ocean in the seventeenth century. Journal of World History 14.2, June 2003.</p><p>Vitello, Paul, From Stand in Long Island Slavery Case, a Snapshot of a Hidden U.S. Problem. The New York Times, December 3 2007.</p><p>Wagman, Morton, The Rise of Pieter Claessen Wyckoff: Social Mobility on the Colonial Frontier. New York History, January 1972.</p><p>Wagman, Morton, Corporate Slavery in New Netherland. The Journal of Negro History 65.1, Winter 1980.</p><p>Wakeman, Frederic, Jr., Voyages. The American Historical Review 98.1, February 1993.</p><p>Walters, Rebekah Velsor, Walt Whitman. Journal of Long Island History 2.1, 1940.</p><p>Warren, Wendy Anne, "The Cause of her Grief": The Rape of a Slave in Early New England. The Journal of American History 93.4, March 2007.</p><p>Wax, Darold D., Negro Resistance to the Early American Slave Trade. The Journal of Negro History 51.1, January 1966.</p><p>Wax, Darold D., Preference for Slaves in Colonial America. The Journal of Negro History 58.4, October 1973.</p><p>Wesley, Charles H., Manifests of Slave Shipments Along the Waterways, 1808-1864. The Journal of Negro History 27.2, April 1942.</p><p>Whitfield, Henry Amani, The American Background of Loyalist Slaves. Left History 14.1, 2009.</p><p>Wiecek, William M., Slavery and Abolition Before the United States Supreme Court 1820-1860. Journal of American History 65, 1978.</p><p>Wikipedia, Lewsi Tappan. Wikipedia, accessed 2006.</p><p>Williams, Oscar R., The Regimentation of Blacks on the Urban Frontier in Colonial Albany, New York City and Philadelphia. The Journal of Negro History 63.4, October 1978.</p><p>Williams-Meyers, A.J., Positioning and imaging Caesar: from margin to center in the historiography of colonial New York City. Afro-Americans in New York Life and History 28.2, July 2004.</p><p>Wiltenburg, Joy, Excerpts from the Diary of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Signs 9.3, Spring 1984.</p><p>Wish, Harvey, The Revival of the African Slave Trade in the United States, 1856-1860. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 27.4, March 1941.</p><p>Woidat, Caroline M., Puritan Daughters and "Wild" Indians: Elizabeth Oakes Smith's Narratives of Domestic Captivity. Legacy: A Journal of American Women Writers 18.1, 2001.</p><p>Wood, J. Taylor, The Capture of a Slaver. Atlantic Monthly 86, 1900.</p><p>Yoshpe, Harry B., Record of Slave Manumissions in New York During the Colonial and Early National Periods. The Journal of Negro History 26.1, January 1941.</p><p>Yoshpe, Harry B., Record of Slave Manumissions in Albany, 1800-28. The Journal of Negro History 26.4, October 1941.</p><p>Younger, Karen Fisher, Liberia and the Last Slave Ships. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_6c913199bdcbb11a203c9df94eb8fd26" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 2.2: Books and book excerpts </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452540</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1901/2008" type="inclusive">1901-2008</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_75243607ba4cd9d75abdf3638ae33ec3" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">5</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_668f3732cde94b0e290f55ccf0c7374e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by author name.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_90d53e5e0e406ffb01f7761a32eaaf7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Books and book excerpts by author surname</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452541</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db07f3e567d6605825000e7cfdaebf68"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Alexander, De Alva Stanwood. A Political History of the State of New York (Volume II, 1833-1861), pp.351-352. New York: Henry Holt &amp; Co., 1906</p><p>Beard, Charles A.. An Economic Interpretation of the Constitution of the United States, pp.176-177. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1956</p><p>Bennett, Norman R., George E. Brooks Jr., eds.. New England Merchants in Africa: A History Through Documents 1802 to 1865, p. 104. Boston: Boston University Press, 1965</p><p>Blaustein, Albert P. and Robert L. Zanrando, eds. . Civil Rights and the American Negro: A Documentary History, pp. 4-7, 22-27, 36-41. New York: Washington Square Press, 1970</p><p>Block, W.T.. Chapter IV: Filibustering, Piracy and the African Slave Trade. A History of Jefferson County, Texas, 1976</p><p>Brasseaux, Carl A. and Glenn R. Conrad, eds.. The Road to Louisiana: The Saint-Domingue Refugees, 1792-1809, pp. 92-101, 166-171. The Center for Louisiana Studies, 1992</p><p>Burak, H. Paul. History of the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York. New York: Federal Bar Association of New York, New Jersey, and Connecticut, 1962</p><p>Burrows, Edwin G. and Mike Wallace. In the Kingdom of Sugar. Excerpt published in South Street Magazine from Gotham: A History of New York City to 1898. Oxford University Press, 1998</p><p>Corbitt, Duvon Chough. A Study of the Chinese in Cuba, 1847-1947. Wilmore, KY: Asbury College Press, 1971</p><p>The Cuba Commission. The Cuba Commission Report: A Hidden History of the Chinese in Cuba. Baltimore, MD: Johns Hopkins University Press, 1993</p><p>Custer, E.A. . A synoptical History of the Towns of Kings County from 1525 to Modern Times. New York, Sherwood's, 1911</p><p>Davis, Thomas J.. A Rumor of Revolt: The "Great Negro Plot" in Colonial New York. New York: The Free Press, 1985</p><p>Day, Lydia S.. Making a Way to Freedom: A History of African Americans on Long Island. New York: Empire States Books, circa 2000</p><p>Deschamps, Hubert. Histoire de Madagascar pp.65-66, 76-78, 320. Paris: Editions Berger-Levrault, 1965</p><p>Dewey, Mary E.. Orville Dewey (1794-1882). In Eliot, Samuel Atkins, ed. Heralds of a Liberal Faith, Volume III: The Preachers. Boston: American Unitarian Association, 1910</p><p>Dictionary of American Biography. Gazaway Bugg Lamar. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1936</p><p>Dugdale, Antony, J.J. Fueser and J. Celso de Castro Alves. Yale, Slavery and Aboliton. The Amistad Committee, 2001</p><p>Eltis, David. Extending the Frontiers: Essays on the New Transatlantic Slave Trade Database. New Haven: Yale University Press, 2008</p><p>Emerson, Donald E.. Richard Hildreth [biography]. Baltimore, MD: The Johns Hopkins Press, 1946</p><p>Emmer, P.C.. Chapter 5: The West India Company, 1621-1791: Dutch or Atlantic? In Blusse, Leonard and Femme Gaastra, eds. Companies and Trade. Leiden University Press, 1981</p><p>Faber, Eli. Slavery and the Jews: A Historical Inquiry. Hunter College Jewish Social Studies Program, Occasional Papers in Jewish History and Thought No. 2, 1994</p><p>Faber, Eli. Jews, Slaves, and the Slave Trade: Setting the Record Straight. New York: New York University Press, 1998</p><p>Ford, Paul Leicester, ed.. Pamphlets on the Constitution of the United States Published During Its Discussion by the People 1787-1788, pp. 329-333, 366-371, 378-379. New York: Burt Franklin, 1971</p><p>Fritz, Chritian G.. Federal Justice in California: The Court of Ogden Hoffman, 1851-1891, pp.10-11, 21, 269, 272. Lincoln, NE: University of Nebraska Press, 1991</p><p>Christopher Fyfe. A History of Sierra Leone, pp.150-151, 194-197. Oxford University Press, 1962</p><p>Gordon, John D. III.. The Trial of the Officers and Crew of the Schooner "Savannah." Second Circuit Historical Committee pamphlet, 1983</p><p>Gordon, John Steele. The Great Game: The Emergence of Wall Street as a World Power, 1653-2000. New York: Scribner, 1999</p><p>Gouverneu, Marian. As I Remember: Recollections of American Society During the Nineteenth Century, pp.69-71. New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1911</p><p>Greenhalgh, Albion Robert. Sources Cited in The Rise of New York Port [1815-1860]. New York: Scribner, 1939</p><p>Hemstreet, Charles. The Story of Manhattan. 1901</p><p>Hemstreet, Charles. Literary New York, Its Landmarks and Associations, pp.197-201. New York: Putnam, 1903</p><p>Henry, Alice. The Trade Union Woman. 1915</p><p>Hershkowitz, Leo. Wills of Early New York Jews, 1704-1799, pp. xi-xvi, 5-6, 8-10, 15-17, 21-23, 44-46, 55-56, 59-61, 65-66, 79--81, 84-88, 129, 135-136, 158-159, 161, 208. New York: American Jewish Historical Society, 1967</p><p>Hunt, Gaillard, ed.. The Writings of James Madison…Volume IV: 1787, The Journal of the Consitutional Convention, pp.300-303. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1903</p><p>Ireland, Ralph R.. Slavery on Long Island: A Study of Economic Motivation. Brooklyn: Long Island Historical Society, 1966</p><p>Jameson, John Franklin. Privateering and Piracy in the Colonial Period: Illustrative Documents, pp.14-17, 175-187, 189-199, 220-223, 235, 318-322, 378-415. New York: The Macmillan Company, 1923</p><p>Judge, John H. "Memorial of George P. Andrews." In Association of the Bar of the City of New York, Annual Reports, Charter, Constitution, By-Laws..., 1904.</p><p>Kolchin, Peter. American Slavery 1619-1877, pp.2627, 256-257. New York: Hill and Wang, 2003</p><p>Kupperman, Karen Ordahl. The Jamestown Project, pp.288, 329, 364. Cambridge: The Belknap Press of Harvard University Press, 2007</p><p>LaChance, Paul F. The 1809 Immigration of Saint-Domingue Refugees to New Orleans: Reception, Integration and Impact. In Brasseaux, Carl A., ed. The Louisiana Purchase Bicentennial Series in Louisiana History, Volume X: A Refuge for All Ages: Immigration in Louisiana History. Lafayette, LA: Center for Louisiana Studies, University of Southwestern Louisiana, 1996</p><p>Lauber, Almon Wheeler. Chapter IV, pp.112-115, Chapter VII, p. 193,Chapter IX: Property Relations, pp. 211-241, and Chapter XII, p. 290. In Indian Slavery in Colonial Times Within the Present Limits of the United States. New York: Columbia University, 1913</p><p>Lewis, Roberts G.. Geraldine Oaksmith: Real Estate Developer, Eccentric Recluse---Research Chemist? Morehead City, NC: Carteret County Historical Society, 1997</p><p>Linder, Marc, &amp; Zacharias, Lawrence S. Of Cabbages and Kings County: Agriculture and the Formation of Modern Brooklyn, pp.80-88, 364-367. Iowa City: University of Iowa Press, 1999</p><p>Lubbock, Basil. Coolie Ships and Oil Sailers. Glasgow: Brown, Son &amp; Ferguson, 1935</p><p>Malloy, William M., compiler. Treaties, Conventons, International Acts, Protocols and Agreements between the United States and Other Powers, 1776-1909, Volume II, p.1458. Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1910</p><p>Marcus, Jacob R.. Chapter 37: The Slave Trade. In The Colonial American Jew, 1492-1776. Detroit: Wayne State University Press, 1970</p><p>May, Robert E.. Manifest Destiny's Underworld: FIlibustering in Antebellum America, pp.174-177, 358-359. Chapel Hill, NC: University of North Carolina Press, 2002</p><p>Miller, Joseph C.. The Story of the Atlantic Slave Trade: 1440-1870. The Journal of American History</p><p>Moore, John Bassett. A Digest of International Law…Volume V, pp.19-21, 81. Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1906</p><p>Morris, Richard B.. Selected Cases of the Mayor Court of the City of New York, 1674-1784. Washington, D.C.: The American Historical Association, 1935</p><p>Phillips, Ulrich Bonnell. American Negro Slavery, A Survey of the Supply, Employment and Control of Negro Labor as Determined by the Plantation Regime. New York: Appleton, 1929</p><p>Pierce, J. Kingston. The Magician of San Francisco. Excerpted from San Francisco, You're History, 1995</p><p>Ratner, Lorman. Powder Keg: Northern Opoosition to the Antislavery Movement 1831-1840, pp.20-21, 26-27. New York: Basic Books, Inc., 1966</p><p>The Researcher 14.1 Spring-Summer 1998 [Elizabeth Oakes Smith issue]</p><p>Robbins, Christine Chapman. David Hosack, Citizen of New York, pp.62-65. Philadelphia: The American Philosphical Society, 1964</p><p>Roche, Emma Langdon. Historic Sketches of the South. New York: The Knickerbocker Press, 1914</p><p>Sandbeck, Peter B.. The Historic Architecture of New Bern and Craven County, North Carolina, p.108. New Bern, NC: The Tryon Palace Commission, 1988</p><p>Smyth, Thomas. Autobiographical Notes, Letters and Reflections, pp. 587--607. Charleston, SC: Walker, Evans &amp; Cogswell Company, 1914</p><p>Spears, John D.. Appendix A:…vessels arrested and bonded from…1852, to…1862. In The American Slave Trade. London: Bickers &amp; Son, 1901</p><p>Strange, Douglas C.. Patterns of Antislavery among American Unitarians, 1831-1860, pp.180-183, 218-227. Rutherford, NJ: Fairleigh Dickinson University Press, 1977</p><p>Sullivan, James, ed.. The History of New York State, Book II, Chapter II, Part IV. Lewis Historical Publishing Company, 1927</p><p>United States Bureau of the Census. Chapter XIV: Statistics of Slaves. In A Century of Population Growth. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1909</p><p>Wakeman, Abram. History and Reminscences of Lower Wall Street and Vicinity, pp.20-25, 52-54. New York: The Spice Mill Publishing Co., 1914</p><p>Wyatt-Brown, Betram. Lewis Tappan and the Evangelical War Against Slavery, 178-181, 184-185, 328-331, 342-343. Cleveland: The Press of Case Western Reserve University, 1969</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_4da2dc1ea0c0497ce762bcb04232098c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Selected Rensselaerswijck Seminar Papers</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452542</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b1a9292dc8bbf5a0cc771beb7a2691e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>A Beautiful and Fruitful Place: Selected Rensselaerswijck Seminar Papers, Volume I. Albany, NY: New Netherland Project, 1991.</p><p>Burke, Thomas. The New Netherland Fur Trade, 1657-1661: Response to Crisis.</p><p>Goodfriend, Joyce D. Black Families in New Netherland.</p><p>Matson, Cathy. The 'Hollander Interest' and Ideas about Free Trade in Colonial New York: Persistent Influences of the Dutch, 1884-1764.</p><p>Rink, Oliver A. New Netherland and the Amsterdam Merchants Unraveling a Secret Colonialism.</p><p>Starna, William A. Seventeenth Century Dutch-Indian Trade A Perspective from Iroquoia.</p><p>Wilcoxen, Charlotte. Dutch Trade with New England.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_17bb615db92d45a2390c52d6d4d07123" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 2.3: Indexes, lists and guides </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452543</unitid><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_288888d3ef71e85c6c9882989da156f5" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_893fd02e003b02de0a55edbb835f5ae3"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by title.</p></arrangement><c id="aspace_aa61952e604d274e6ab14c11ac1cd265" level="file"><did><unittitle>Afrigenes.com Inward Slave Manifests</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452544</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b15c98e5e76d2b47be9dc715001be73"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Slave shipping manifests.
McClendon, Alma. Inward Slave Manifests for the Port of New Orleans, Roll 12 1837-1839.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_226c36a453a2a640af35af3033780f33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Afro-Louisiana History and Genealogy 1718-1820</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452545</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c8017f1aaba60b719e585a90500cea3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Hall, Gwendolyn Mildo. Slavery and African Ethnicities in the Americas.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_0590fa57cfde5120d346238c6701f7e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alan Singer teaching materials on slavery in NY state</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452546</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_7b195c671b102b5ff3bc4c71daa7677f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Black Loyalists website</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452547</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63c89b16bdfdd8e1548051f4148efb65"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Canadian site; Black loyalist directory. Interesting comparison to Graham Russell Hodge's book on escaping.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_167761e5ef884350e33c973ec6bc11f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brooklyn Historical Society</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452548</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d46af542412a354b79a9312f1a94341a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>BobCat information on slavery, finding aids for autograph manuscript collections, Onderdonk guide.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_847ce0aa649baac0b38ad48b26417d89" level="file"><did><unittitle>Census slave data by county 1820-1860</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452549</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_d754308ae264ca72d89aa62a1dd1f465" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gilder Lehrman Center resources</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452550</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_7622d7b0be11704d6a8543230645efa4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Map reproductions</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452551</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2feae8845c983b2ad16145b77e4f142a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Photocopies of insurance and zoning maps of sections of Brooklyn, dates unknown, likely late 19th-early 20th centuries.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_e0b0a30ebee288d8b5b7bc6d88afcac0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mystic Seaport Museum</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452552</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cb3b2f6d67631f334c777b886a60a1e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Records of Thomas Dunham's Newphew &amp; Company, Coll. 196, Manuscripts Collection, G.W. Blunt White Library.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_7d1dd6c19c00555c42de9243d5ac158a" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Archives resources</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452553</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_d33220bed2ed597098aac0fa1ede572f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Netherland Institute resources</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452554</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_5cff262218a717045ce7000045880fa0" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Public Library resources</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452555</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_53cae5c3a2d784fc04601cfd32e5383f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York State Council for the Social Studies teaching guide</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452556</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88ebc653f9c2d5dec0fee06c1633063c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>New York and Slavery: Complicity and Resistence.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ccccc06d49e6d9124fba7052689813a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York to New Orleans slave manifests, 1807-1860</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452557</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_60b6a0b0748a1b974a347cee96411c85" level="file"><did><unittitle>New-York Historical Society resources</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452558</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2df293672eba303284bc45988761927"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Slavery in New York exhibition.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_ef2ae3f8bd7fc6e6c667ad5adbedfa9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Race, Racism, and the Law website</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452559</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71bbde2d139892e53fa205de0c2b3841"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Randall, Venellia R. Slavery federal cases, 1790-1865.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_f95b35817684736acdd62422a30d61be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Schuyler family genealogy</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452560</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7607c948a3ee34a8a3740d4f9a8c0733"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Descendents of the Schuyler Family Including Bayards and Livingstons.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_36262a3492222d4d72e6aa937575fdee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Slave trade laws (federal) background materials</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452561</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_f727f8cbbb932fa1deef02b4b5b08d7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Supreme Court Historical Society journal index</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452562</unitid></did></c><c id="aspace_51c85be3273aface635dd026c77733b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>The American People companion website</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452563</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b3f3ee52075cabdd8bc52719f893244"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Slave Trade Documents--inventory.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_de1c686fb928a3521c6dcfa6963c232c" level="file"><did><unittitle>TheShipsList website</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452564</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c85c92cb2b2b951ff74def789bf0818"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Swiggum, S. and M. Kohli. Settlers to Liberia (1843-187?) [information taken from The African Repository, and Colonial Journal, 1843-1867].
Emigrant Ships to the West Indies in the 1850s.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_2864c5bb74bc117fbd99895d7a4d172c" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade Database</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452565</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0df96149c0276be0a1847742feb600c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Eltis, David. Table of Contents and sources, Analysis of data.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_72f978236676a636b599192b6fcbac99" level="file"><did><unittitle>University of Georgia</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452566</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_011715f70ebd908c44ef93225c8c2d63"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Guide to the Gazaway Bugg Lamar papers, MS 10. Hargrett Book and Manuscript Library, University of Georgia Libraries.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_71a74112d046011b95d78de9b3059407" level="file"><did><unittitle>University of Pennsylvania resource list</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452567</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f35a825f82f6fed53260c040e08d855"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>University of Pennsylvania Dept. of History. The Crisis of the Union: An Electronic Archive of Documents about the Causes, Conduct, and Consequences of the US Civil War</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_88e7ea847ce19ae5e998ec3e76b33dca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Virginia Slave Trade in the Eighteenth Century guide</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452568</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3963ddf9c4bc111eac34548246e31830"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Klein, Herbert S. "Virginia Slave Trade in the Eighteenth Century" 1727-1769: A User's Guide to the Machine Readable Data File Study Description</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_fc242ce66d08fed44d57ead19a351657" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 2.4: Reviews</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452569</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/2018" type="inclusive">1928-2018</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_4118f91de75e928ae65ffb70087886e4" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_68f755599753dddae936499201b82aa9"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by author name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_ef314fcd1523c9317e6207bee4902516"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Appiah, Kwame Anthony, What Was Africa to Them? [review of The Door of No Return by William St. Clair, Middle Passages by James T. Campbell, American Africans in Ghana by Kevin K. Gaines, Black Gold of the Sun by Ekow Eshun, and Lose Your Mother by Saidiya Hartman]. The New York Review, September 27 2007.</p><p>Berlin, Ira, Slaves in the Family [review of Inhuman Bondage by David Brion Davis]. New York Times Book Review, May 14 2006.</p><p>Berry, Jason, Urban Gumbo [review of The World that Made New Orleans by Ned Sublette]. The New York Times, February 17 2008.</p><p>Blouet, Olwyn M., Reviews of Books: Apprenticing to Freedom in the West Indies [review of Between Slavery and Freedom, ed. Roderick A. McDonald, and A Narrative of Events, ed. Diana Paton]. The William and Mary Quarterly 59.3, July 2002.</p><p>Bodle, Wayne, Reviews of Books [review of Cadwallader Colden: A Figure of the American Enlightenment by Alfred R. Hoermann]. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.2, April 2003.</p><p>Brewer, John, The Irish Indian Chief [review of White Savage: William Johnson and the Invention of America by Fintan O'Toole]. The New York Review of Books, December 1 2005.</p><p>Buhle, Paul, [Review of] The Rise and Fall of the White Republic: Class Politics and Mass Culture in Nineteenth Century America by Alexander Saxton. The Nation 252.23, June 17 1991.</p><p>Carlson, Thomas C., [Review of] Poe and His Times: The Artist and His Milieu by Benjamin Fisher. The Mississippi Quarterly 46.1, Winter 1992.</p><p>Crain, Caleb, There She Blew: The History of American Whaling [review of Leviathan by Eric Jay Dolin]. The New Yorker, July 23, 2007.</p><p>Cray, Robert E. Jr., Reviews of Books: Generous Enemies: Patriots and Loyalists in Revolutionary New York by Judith L. Van Buskirk. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.2, 2003.</p><p>Dain, Bruce, Reviews of Books: Stories of Freedom in Black New York by Shane White and In the Shadow of Slavery: African Americans in New York City, 1626-1863 by Leslie M. Harris. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.4, 2003.</p><p>Dargis, Manohla, The Imperfect Soul Who Helped Bring an End to the Slave Trade [review of movie Amazing Grace about William Wilberforce]. The New York Times, February 23 2007.</p><p>Dorson, Richard M., Seba Smith [review of the book by that title by Milton and Patricia Rickels]. The Journal of American History 65.2, September 1978.</p><p>Erben, Patrick M., Reviews of Books: Becoming German by Philip Otterness. The William and Mary Quarterly 62.1, circa 2005.</p><p>Finnegan, William, Double-Cross in the Congo [review of The Mission Song by John le Carre]. The New York Review of Books 54.6, April 12 2007.</p><p>Fireman, Janet R., Book Reviews: California, In-Doors and Out by Eliza B. Farnham. The Journal of San Diego History 20.1, Winter 1974.</p><p>Fredrickson, George M., America's Original Sin [review of Challenging the Boundaries of Slavery by David Brion Davis, Generations of Captivity by Ira Berlin, and The Slaveholding Republic by Don E. Fehrenbacher. The New York Review of Books, March 25 2004.</p><p>Fredrickson, George M., The Long Trek to Freedom [review of Though the Heavens May Fall by Steven M. Wise, Slave Country by Adam Rothman, The First Emancipator by Andrew Levy, and Bound for Canaan by Fergus M. Bordewich]. The New York Review of Books, July 14 2005.</p><p>Fredrickson, George M., They'll Take Their Stand [review of Inhuman Bondage by David Brion Davis and The Mind of the Master Class by Elizabeth Fox-Genovese and Eugene D. Genovese]. The New York Review of Books, May 25, 2006.</p><p>Fredrickson, George M., Redcoat Liberation [review of Epic Journeys of Freedom by Cassandra Pybus, Rough Crossings by Simon Schama, and The Forgotten Fifth by Gary B. Nash]. The New York Review of Books, August 10 2006.</p><p>Furbank, P.N., A Capacity for Impudence [review of Beaumarchais in Seville by Hugh Thomas]. The New York Review of Books, April 26 2007.</p><p>Gewen, Barry, The Everyman of Genocide [review of Becoming Eichmann by David Cesarani]. The New York Times Book Review, May 14 2006.</p><p>Gillespie, Michelle, Reviews of Books: Slavery, Freedom and Culture among Early American Workers by Graham Russell Hodges. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.</p><p>Hamill, Pete, Raging Thirst [review of Dry Manhattan by Michael A. Lerner]. The New York Times, March 11 2007.</p><p>Heig, Aline, Review: The Cuba Commission Report: A Hidden History of the Chinese in Cuba by The Cuba Commission and Indentured Labor, Caribbean Sugar by Walton Look Lai. The Hispanic American Historical Review 75.4, November 1995.
Herbert, Bob, In America; Stanton and Anthony. The New York Times, July 4 1999.</p><p>Kazin, Michael, The Original Party Boss [review of Martin Van Buren by Ted Widmer]. The New York Times Book Review, February 27 2005.</p><p>Kirsch, A., The Battle Cry of Freedom [review of The Slaves' War by Andrew Ward]. The New York Sun, June 4 2008.
Lurie Alison, Liberated Girls [review of Little Women, Little Men, Jo's Boys by Louisa May Alcott]. The New York Review of Books, November 3 2005.</p><p>Marietta, Jack D., [Review of] "Rememb'ring our Time and Work is the Lords": The Experiences of Quakers on the Eighteenth-Century Pennsylvania Frontier by Guenther Karen. Journal of American History 93.3, December 2006.</p><p>May, Robert E., Antebellum Americans 'Meet' Their Southern Neighbors [review of Agents of Manifest Destiny by Charles H. Brown]. Reviews in American History 8.3, September 1980.</p><p>McPherson, James M., The Fight for Slavery in California [review of The California Gold Rush by Leonard L. Richards]. TheNew York Review of Books, October 11 2007.</p><p>McPherson, James M., Days of Wrath [review of John Brown, Abolitionist by David S. Reynolds, John Brown by Merrill D. Peterson, and Terrible Swuft Sword ed. Peggy Russo]. The New York Review, May 12 2005.</p><p>Merwick, Donna, Reviews of Books: Zion on the Hudson by Firth Haring Fabend. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.2, 2001.</p><p>Miller, Joseph C., [Review of] The Slave Trade by Hugh Thomas. The Journal of American History 85.2, September 1998.</p><p>Moorehead, Caroline, Amnesia in Australia [review of multiple books on Australian history]. The New York Review of Books 53.18, November 16 2006.</p><p>Olson, Alison G., Reviews of Books: The Imperial Executive in America by Mary Lou Lustig and General Sir Guy Carleton by David Paul Nelson. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.4, 2003.</p><p>Parks, Tim, The Illusionist [review of 3 biographies of Mussolini]. The New York Review of Books, April 7 2005.</p><p>Reynolds, David S., Family Business [review of Sons of Providence by Charles Rappleye]. The New York Times Book Review, May 14, 2006.</p><p>Reynolds, David S., Fine Specimens [review of The Afterlives of Specimens by Linday Tuggle and Drum-Taps by Walt Whitman, ed. Lawrence Kramer]. The New York Review, March 22 2018.</p><p>Rushforth, Brett, Reviews of Books: The Indian Slave Trade: The Rise of the English Empire in the American South, 1670-1717 by Alan Gallay. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.3, 2003.</p><p>Ryden, David, Running the Numbers: An Overview of The Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade CD-ROM. Slavery and Abolition 22.3, December 2001.</p><p>Schlesinger, A.M., [Review of] Two American Pioneers: Seba Smith and Elizabeth Oakes Smith by Mary Alice Wyman. The New England Quarterly 1.2, April 1928.</p><p>Swift, Daniel, "Stephen Spender": The Poet of Autobiography [review of Stephen Spender by John Sutherland]. The New York Times [2 copies], February 27 2005.</p><p>Wheatcroft, Geoffrey, Digging for Moles [review of Treachery by Chapman Pincher]. The New York Review of Books 56.16, October 22 2009.</p><p>Wood, Gordon S., What Slavery Was Really Like [review of Mastery, Tyranny and Desire by Trevor Burnard and Landon Carter's Uneasy Kingdom by Rhys Isaac]. New York Times Book Review, November 18 2004.</p><p>Wood, Gordon S., Apologies to the Iroquois [review of The Divided Gorund by Alan Taylor]. New York Review of Books, April 6 2006.</p><p>Wood, Gordon S., Reading the Founders' Minds [review of Dark Bargain by Lawrence Goldstone and American Taxation, American Slavery by Robin L. Einhorn]. New York Review of Books, June 28 2007.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_302343b567d510d4bea7bb4776511ee5" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Sub-series 2.5: Theses and dissertations </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452570</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1894/2007" type="inclusive">1894-2007</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_4a68194526191c7699231b1171edea17" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container></did><arrangement id="aspace_a49308376c6febf5f4f27ec8f58d0640"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by author name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_688f74cdee02825a8af6ae91ec11f94c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Carroll, Aileen M. Gentle Rebel: Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Masters Thesis at the University of Maine Orono, 1968.</p><p>Du Bois, W.E.B.	Appendix A: A Chronological Conspectus of Colonial and State Legislation Restricting the African Slave-Trade. 1641-1787. In The Suppression of the African Slave-Trade, PhD dissertation at Harvard, 1894.</p><p>Eltis, David. The Transatlantic Slave Trade, 1821-1863. PhD dissertation at University of Rochester, 1978.</p><p>Hohl, Loz. The Temperate Feminist: Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Master's essay at Sarah Lawrence College, 1977.</p><p>Johnson, Erica Robin. Louisiana Identity on Trial: The Superior Court Case of Pierre Benomine Dormenon 1790-1812. Master's thesis at University of Texas Arlington, 2007.</p><p>Kirkland, Leigh. A Human Life: Being the Autobiography of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. A Critical Edition and Introduction. PhD thesis [order form only].</p><p>Moss, Richard Shannon. Slavery on Long Island: Its Rise and Decline during the Seventeenth Through Nineteenth Centuries [order form and notes].</p><p>Richards, Wynola L. A Review of the Life and Writing of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. PhD dissertation at Ball State University, 1981.</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="aspace_7d633201d58e020d62f823f680921c64" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series 3: William Coleman notes and correspondence </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452571</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2000/2020" type="inclusive">circa 2000s-2020</unitdate><container altrender="Record Carton" id="aspace_0c8406883a7fa81903648615dea4e161" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">6</container></did><c id="aspace_37b37bf1d2d892e8aece04b63364c3c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Coleman writings</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452575</unitid></did><scopecontent id="aspace_333b43780dae0d060733db8c8f28db67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>2007 memo to Deborah Schwartz re: NYHS exhibit on slavery; text of 2008 speech at BHS.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_01e14dbb150c00d016c6ad23af9559ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Research correspondence</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452572</unitid></did><arrangement id="aspace_a8574a6715cbf750905c273302edf82c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_d65f3886a0dc36f306728c2fc487c2bb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Printouts of emails between Coleman and other scholars and associates.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_804ef1d7d68dcec0ed19364489d06564" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes on publications</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452573</unitid></did><arrangement id="aspace_4e0abf18a85428d17d8daa49ea1c8032"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by author name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_092358bfff3ce9aded67a5bce39229b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Notes on the following:</p><p>Bernstein, R.B. Thomas Jefferson. Oxford University Press, 2003.</p><p>Brasseuax, Carl A. The Road to Louisiana: the Saint-Domingue Refugees, 1792-1809. University of Louisiana at Lafayette, 1992.</p><p>Drake, Philip. Captain Richard Drake, Revelations of a Slave Smuggler. Robert M. Dewitt, 1860.</p><p>DuBois, W.E.B. Suppression of the Slave Trade, 1638-1870. Langmans, Green &amp; Co., 1896.</p><p>Jameson, J. Franklin. Narratives of New Netherland, 1609-1664. Charles Scribner's Sons, 1909.</p><p>McGuire, James K. The Democratice Party of the State of New York. U.S. History Co., 1905.</p><p>McManus, Edgar J. History of Negro Slavery in New York. Syracuse University Press, 1996.</p><p>Miller, New York Considered and Improved 1689. The Burrows Brothers Company, 1903.</p><p>Mins, Stewart L. Cobert's West India Policy. Yale University Press, 1912.</p><p>O'Callaghan, E.B. New York Colonial Tracts Number III. J. Muncell, 1867.</p><p>Pettit, Marilyn H., Slavery, Abolition, and Columbia University. Journal of Archival Organization 1.4, 2002.</p><p>Pitman, Frank Wesley. The Development of the British West Indies 1700-1763. Yale University Press, 1917.</p><p>Scoville, Joseph Alfred. Old Merchants of New York City. Thomas R. Knox, 1885.</p><p>Todd, Charles Burr. The Story of the City of New York. G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1888.</p><p>Townsend, Craig. Faith in Their Own Color. Columbia University Press, 2005.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="aspace_9a912a44000a76fee15ff8fde94b9358" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes on research topics</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/5/archival_objects/452574</unitid></did><arrangement id="aspace_7e25483b24c6913eebaa0ea5ce167da3"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="aspace_8d9f9964e7c5636ad4bf437a36add607"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Notes, correspondence and documents regarding the Nathaniel Gordon case, Appleton Oaksmith and Elizabeth Oakes Smith, David Eltis's Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade Database ("comments and backup materials"), and general information on shipping and the slave trade.</p></scopecontent></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
