<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD" url="https://findingaids.library.nyu.edu/nyuad/ad_mc_164/">ad_mc_164</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the A.S. Rogers collection of correspondence with Sultans of Zanzibar <num>AD.MC.164</num></titleproper><author>Brad Bauer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</publisher><p><date>April 2026</date></p><address><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi, C-2</addressline><addressline>P.O. 129188</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/library.html" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/library.html" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-04-17 12:01:34 +0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>A.S. Rogers collection of correspondence with Sultans of Zanzibar</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <persname role="col" source="local">Rogers, A.S. (Alexander Stuart) (1862-1930)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.164</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/240</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.10  Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">containing 17 letters, and one photographic portrait (silver gelatin print), in 18 folders.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1901/1905" type="inclusive">1901-1905, and undated</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_406b75d34388e9b3a83e0c366dbb954f" label="Abstract">Correspondence, documents, and one photograph, between Capt. A.S. (Alexander Stuart) Rogers, a British colonial official in East Africa, and Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad, Sultan of Zanzibar (ruled 1896-1902) and his son, ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd (ruled 1902-1911), with most correspondence dating from Rogers' tenure as First Minister to the Sultan, when he served as regent for ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd until the latter reached the age of majority in 1905.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      <language langcode="ara">Arabic</language>
    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_35fd99d5951191ac2bee5a8e30cbcba6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>The A.S. Rogers collection is open and available for use in the Archives and Special Collections department of the New York University Abu Dhabi Library.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_cec8618f102871ca1471508c8eda1550">
    <head>Immediate source of acquisition</head>
<p>Acquired by purchase, November 2025.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5b26f145730053e1ff148cc824025bff">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged into four series:  I.  Sultan Ḥammūd bin Muḥammad, letters sent to A.S. Rogers, II.  Sultan ʻAlī bin Ḥammūd , letters sent to Rogers, III. Correspondence with Lord Lansdowne, and IV.  Miscellaneous.  The materials are largely arranged within each series in chronological order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_17c1262901f688a3fd4eeaf4174fd576">
    <head>Biographical and Historical Note</head>
<p>A.S. (Alexander Stuart) Rogers (1862-1930), was a British army officer and colonial official who was based in what later became Kenya and in Zanzibar between 1890 and 1905.  Born in Peshawar, British India (modern-day Pakistan) on 13 November 1862, he joined the Punjab Native Police, and in that capacity was sent, with 200 of his policemen, to assist the Imperial British East Africa Company in Mombasa in August 1890.  His initial task was to help the IBEA suppress a rebellion in the region of Witu, which had been ceded by the German colonists in what is now Tanzania to the IBEA, and where rebels had resisted British control.  In 1895 Rogers was named British vice-consul at Mombasa, after the IBEA ceased to exist and the British government took control of the region that comprises modern-day Kenya and Uganda.  His administration was fraught with accusations of cruelty and harsh treatment of the locals, with numerous complaints filed against him.</p><p>In 1902 he was transferred to Zanzibar, to serve as First Minister, alongside the British Consul, Basil Cave.  Since 1890, Zanzibar had been a British protectorate, which allowed the British to play a key role in choosing the Sultans from the ruling Al-Busaidi family to govern the island nation, which in turn facilitated further British financial and administrative control of it.  After Sultan Hamid bin Thuwaini died in 1896, his nephew, Khalid bin Bargash, sought to seize power, in defiance of British wishes to name his successor.  This resulted in the British bombardment of the city of Zanzibar and the Sultan's Palace, and following the defeat of Khalid, the British government appointed Ḥammūd bin Muḥammad (1853-1902) as the new Sultan, seeing him as a ruler who would be more receptive to British aims.  Sultan Ḥammūd, wishing to avoid a struggle for succession after his own death, requested First Minister Sir Lloyd Mathews to take up this question with the British Government upon the latter's return to Britain, and requested him to suggest that he be succeeded by his son, ʻAlī bin Ḥammūd (1884-1918).  This would have broken with established precedent among the Al-Busaidis, where normally the eldest male in the ruling family would have taken over, which in this case would have been Ḥammūd's brother, Khalid bin Muḥammad.  British officials liked the idea of appointing ʻAli, however, since he had been educated at British public schools and could communicate fluently in English, and was perceived, like his father, to be supportive of British aims in the region.  </p><p>When Sultan Ḥammūd died in July 1902 Rogers, who by then was the First Minister, immediately suggested that ʻAlī be appointed the new Sultan.   Yet, since ʻAli was not yet of the age of majority, being only 18, it was also decided that Rogers would be appointed regent until ʻAli reached the age of 21.  While ʻAli was initially receptive to this idea, during the next two years he became increasingly dissatisfied with this arrangement, as he saw that Rogers used the regency as a pretext to take greater control of the affairs of state, often bypassing Sultan ʻAli in making major decisions, in particular those that involved the budget of the Sultanate.  After repeated complaints to the British Foreign Office, including to the Foreign Secretary, Lord Lansdowne, Rogers was removed from his post in 1905 and the regency was abolished at that time.  However, the power of the Sultan by this point had been greatly diminished, and was clearly subservient to that of the British government.  Facing health problems of his own, Sultan ʻAli abdicated in favor of his brother-in-law, Khalīfah ibn Ḥārib, in 1911, and he moved to France, where he died in 1918.</p><p>Rogers, after his dismissal as First Minister, returned to England and was given a pension.  He died on 15 July 1930, in Carshalton, Surrey.</p><p>Sources:
Christine Nicholls, "A.S. Rogers, controversial British official," in Old Africa:  Stories from East Africa's Past, June 22, 2014 (accessed April 2026)
https://oldafricamagazine.com/a-s-rogers-controversial-british-official/l</p><p>Turki, Dr. Benyan Saud.  "The Sultan of the Arab state of Zanzibar and the Regent 1902-1905.  Bulletin of the Documentation and Humanities Research Centre, University of Qatar, Vol. 9,  (1997): 1-27.</p>  </bioghist>
  <custodhist id="aspace_e2704b4a242d2281c8e1c8c886a715a5">
    <head>Custodial history</head>
<p>The collection originated from the estate of Cpt. Alexander Rogers (1862–1930); by descent to his son, Gordon Alex Hugh Rogers (1908–1979). It was offered at the sale of his family papers, through Phillips Mayfair, Books and Documents, in February 1980, as lot 131, and was purchased for a British-Hungarian private collector, from whom it was acquired and re-sold in 2025.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_aee18268724812bbdb11afe43c689dfd">
    <head>Preferred citation</head>
<p>[item], [box/folder number], A.S. Rogers collection of correspondence with Sultans of Zanzibar, MC-164, New York University Abu Dhabi Library, Abu Dhabi, UAE.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_50b6857af1768284a76d79796e8f3fe9">
    <head>Processing information</head>
<p>Processed by Brad Bauer, April 2026.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_7c2b6ce43c27fe3476835a5ab8a718dc">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The "A.S. Rogers collection of correspondence with the Sultans of Zanzibar" consists of correspondence and one photograph, between Capt. A.S. (Alexander Stuart) Rogers, a British colonial official in East Africa, and Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad, Sultan of Zanzibar (ruled 1896-1902) and his son, ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd (ruled 1902-1911), with most of the correspondence dating from Rogers' tenure as First Minister to the Sultan, when he served as regent for ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd until the latter reached the age of majority in 1905.  </p><p>The collection of letters, privately retained by A.S. Rogers, provides partial documentation of his relationship with the two sultans, as well as with the officials in the British Foreign Office to whom he reported, chiefly Lord Lansdowne (the Marquess of Lansdowne), the Foreign Secretary.</p><p>The correspondence in this collection that Rogers received from Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad consists of letters prior to and shortly after Rogers' arrival in Zanzibar as First Minister, with Ḥammūd urging him to come to Zanzibar, and offering him the Hamudi medal, in recognition of Rogers' work as a consultant to the rulers of Zanzibar.  The original letters are handwritten in Arabic, but handwritten translated letters, written by a member of the sultan's court for his signature, are also present.  </p><p>The correspondence from ʻAlī begins two years later, and shows the young sultan seeking to assert his power and command respect.  ʻAlī's correspondence is by turns cordial, offering on several occasions to bestow medals and honors on Rogers, but also demonstrates points of friction between the two men, such as ʻAlī's request to have exclusive access to two white horses, which Rogers and his aides were often seen riding; or when Rogers passed budgetary reports onto other British officials for approval, without consulting ʻAlī.  The last two letters from ʻAlī to Rogers include an invitation to attend a private dinner with the sultan on 28 July 1905, which Rogers apparently ignored, as a letter dated the following day takes Rogers to task for not acknowledging the significance of that date, as the anniversary of ʻAlī's accession to the position of Sultan.  In addition, ʻAlī was greatly displeased that as First Minister, Rogers apparently did nothing to ensure that this anniversary would be observed by the public in Zanzibar as well.  </p><p>Additional letters from Lansdowne detail the displeasure of the Foreign Office with Rogers in his handling of the relationship with ʻAlī, with some of the letters having evidently been written after ʻAlī had contacted the Foreign Office, and with Lansdowne urging Rogers to show greater sensitivity toward ʻAlī.</p><p>The collection also includes one photographic portrait of Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad, originally mounted on a matte board, from which the silver gelatin print has become separated, and with Ḥammūd's signature in Arabic on the border.  The collection also contains a letter partially in Swahili and in Arabic, from an unknown correspondent.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_114b119e419447b21f7e6b1224e2edb6">
    <head>Conditions governing use</head>
<p>Given the age of the material, it is presumed that the content of these letters are no longer protected by copyright and are in the public domain.  However, it is still the responsibility of researchers to fully investigate the rights status of these materials before quoting from them in a published work, for any uses that exceed those that would be considered as "fair-use."</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Great Britain -- Foreign relations</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Zanzibar -- History -- 1890-1964</geogname>
    <persname role="col" source="local">Rogers, A.S. (Alexander Stuart) (1862-1930)</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="2018040226" source="naf">Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad ( Sultan of Zanzibar) (1853-1902)</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="2018040232" source="naf">ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd (Sultan of Zanzibar)</persname>
    <persname>Lansdowne  , Henry Charles Keith Petty-FitzMaurice (Marquess of), 1845-1927</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_865394f2a7b7bacc98909ed1b5d7d6f4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sultan Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad, letters sent to A.S. Rogers</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41213</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1901/1902" type="inclusive">1901-1902</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_8a027f99a9d393d1205962baf1409fdd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad to A.S. Rogers [English translation, ALS], with envelope, 2 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41195</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1901-12-19/1901-12-19">19 December 1901 = 8 Ramadan 1319</unitdate><container id="aspace_6344b10b93d2684cd2dc72b2c7d9ac5d" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_eaf03484b98e56316fefd8d263180d4d" parent="aspace_6344b10b93d2684cd2dc72b2c7d9ac5d" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e13b82061046f6a8cc00510af8809182" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad to A.S. Rogers [English translation, ALS], 1 leaf, 2 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41196</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902-01-15/1902-01-15">15 January 1902 = 5 Shawwal 1319</unitdate><container id="aspace_ccca1b1757fc74fd078981bdb845a35d" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_84d63eb3453906c77bec1232274f0839" parent="aspace_ccca1b1757fc74fd078981bdb845a35d" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="aspace_df6da58e9f1e64e7246769637f37a99c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad to A.S. Rogers [Arabic original, ALS], 1 leaf, 1 page</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41197</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902-02-05/1902-02-05">4 February 1902 = 25 Shawwal 1319</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d22fc9fd150cd75b402fb610f9268b3" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_98742f035abfb79ab60761b3011be81f" parent="aspace_9d22fc9fd150cd75b402fb610f9268b3" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_ca71a3374381a51eb9302c98ae20271a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad to A.S. Rogers [Arabic original, ALS], 1 leaf, 1 page</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41198</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902-02-13/1902-02-13">13 February 1902 = 5 Dhu al-Qa'da 1319</unitdate><container id="aspace_7234ab14e3c6c3e3eeefb03b27096031" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_9863624d34298cd4e8da2381520b5388" parent="aspace_7234ab14e3c6c3e3eeefb03b27096031" type="folder">4</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_9a454fd4af498c40d287bd9b05190428" level="series"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd, letters sent to A.S. Rogers</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41214</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904/1905" type="inclusive">1904-1905</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_d763bd30297cd1fdf5962bbf7e869766" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (TLS, English), 1 leaf, 2 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41199</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904-08-10/1904-08-10">10 August 1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_81c7f61794a56c94bbd6ab99bd7479c9" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4ebb325cc9ea2b379d527b52cf752978" parent="aspace_81c7f61794a56c94bbd6ab99bd7479c9" type="folder">5</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d96ad78f7f8762ceaeaa3c8ca57369df" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (TLS, English), 1 leaf, 1 page</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41200</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904-08-27/1904-08-27">27 August 1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a0464800385587146307f7002310c4b" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d3025d905095bec19ebe71fd020f402f" parent="aspace_2a0464800385587146307f7002310c4b" type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="aspace_11de27db54de04913f68f6d054022d8e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (TLS, English), 1 leaf, 1 page</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41202</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904-11-02/1904-11-02">2 November 1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8b9cdfcbebc0ff0d217c9a379455560" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_fd642f91702543628232ecf9eb3e2cc0" parent="aspace_c8b9cdfcbebc0ff0d217c9a379455560" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="aspace_74e1d9170c166fd35c08839a3a2f4f58" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (TLS, English), 1 leaf, 1 page, with attached manuscript draft response from Rogers, 2 leaves, 6 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41203</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904-11-11/1904-11-11">11 November 1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_03e53d81ee196814fc9e786a10e88fd8" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_eb9173a6e6697ce4af690ef1d68b6942" parent="aspace_03e53d81ee196814fc9e786a10e88fd8" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d1d321ae1648ca0ae5c7ad467a49100b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (ALS, Arabic), conferring Medal of the Sa'idi Order, 1 leaf, 1 page, with seal</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41201</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1905-06-07/1905-06-07">7 June 1905 = 3 Rabi' al-Thani 1323</unitdate><container id="aspace_97e88c97e5254bad59a45ef40beee15c" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7014d03e0311c466488222d1b2558e3d" parent="aspace_97e88c97e5254bad59a45ef40beee15c" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9bb8b4ec517e5a0a7d5db97b7fd9f02a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (ALS, English), 1 leaf, 1 page, with envelope</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41204</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904-06-25/1904-06-25">25 June 1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_cfc939023177c762fcc0f89d4ecd6f14" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_577ae60bad30a49a83618d03f15315c6" parent="aspace_cfc939023177c762fcc0f89d4ecd6f14" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bf49552ee17508fac38266765dc42b16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (ALS, English), 1 leaf, 2 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41205</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1905-07-05/1905-07-05">5 July 1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_044fc638ee1635987d763f3174d37cce" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_b3d843d56889e5066fd31081a9d85bd6" parent="aspace_044fc638ee1635987d763f3174d37cce" type="folder">11</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8a8bfba33e71f5ecda629d9bb6f00916" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (ALS, English), 1 leaf, 2 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41206</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1905-07-28/1905-07-28">28 July 1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e5e83bf3bf6fe041f91b88bd4587536" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_20d953ec6be9cc86e1abc102a2e80c82" parent="aspace_1e5e83bf3bf6fe041f91b88bd4587536" type="folder">12</container></did></c><c id="aspace_9c3ef6cc77614ecfd61d428a2f62d63b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan ʻAlī ibn Ḥammūd to A.S. Rogers (ALS, English), 1 leaf, 2 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41207</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1905-07-29/1905-07-29">29 July 1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c249c292d9b9ab312251f27b55b6075" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c321144038bbd587ae4ed097de245e0c" parent="aspace_3c249c292d9b9ab312251f27b55b6075" type="folder">13</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_5d4c493d224429ad0de2ca2e712dcbd4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence with Lord Lansdowne (Henry Petty-Fitzmaurice), Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41215</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904/1905" type="inclusive">1904-1905</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_a845533a4da243f9cc6628745838e78d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansdowne to A.S. Rogers, 7 pages, TLS, with enclosed typescript copy of letter from Landsdowne to Sultan 'Ali bin Hamoud (7 pages)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41208</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904-03-31/1904-03-31">31 March 1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fd5f52c97fae5c3ed703ce3e065d7e7" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e9add056aad42fb3dd52f175c23dfe82" parent="aspace_6fd5f52c97fae5c3ed703ce3e065d7e7" type="folder">14</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8d7390401a5893e5a9a13b2c9a05c72b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansdowne to A.S. Rogers, 7 pages, TLS, with enclosed typescript copy of letter from Lansdowne to Sultan 'Ali bin Hamoud (6 pages)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41209</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904-09-14/1904-09-14">14 September 1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_52056f23e49fcc654b46461e8aa60d02" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_72d15157c1046d7d0d3744aa2e79ee83" parent="aspace_52056f23e49fcc654b46461e8aa60d02" type="folder">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_b3cd3944c376ec5c503817ffda7fb6f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sultan 'Ali bin Hamoud to Lansdowne, typescript copy, 9 pages</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41210</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1905-10-26/1905-10-26">26 October 1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_eeacc43672e6a6a0c8d6270394f86c1d" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1ce571802042b945407bc5d0a2d83163" parent="aspace_eeacc43672e6a6a0c8d6270394f86c1d" type="folder">16</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_41e09220d647e8b650dacaef8601ce7b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41216</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1898/1900" type="inclusive">undated, circa 1898-1900</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_3366e21cebb8b765e8a00f1120a2b118" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photograph:  portrait of Sultan Ḥammūd ibn Muḥammad (silver gelatin print, matted, with signature)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41211</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902">undated, circa 1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_86f98e7162257db163f62774c603de4a" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_76d7a5d021a85848e25269057042fc36" parent="aspace_86f98e7162257db163f62774c603de4a" type="folder">17</container></did></c><c id="aspace_12691466e4ed30cba72d57993e876155" level="file"><did><unittitle>Unidentified letter, in Arabic and Swahili, 1 page, ALS</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41212</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1898/1899" type="inclusive">circa 1898-1899 = 1316 H.</unitdate><container id="aspace_c38205d29110e58db15484c88b18bd23" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5f5c1a6e85b92d688af86a16914a2be5" parent="aspace_c38205d29110e58db15484c88b18bd23" type="folder">18</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
