<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD" url="https://findingaids.library.nyu.edu/nyuad/ad_mc_136/">ad_mc_136</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the William J. Frazer photograph album of the H.M.S. St. George <num>AD.MC.136</num></titleproper><author>Brad Bauer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</publisher><p><date>December 2024</date></p><address><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi, C-2</addressline><addressline>P.O. 129188</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/library.html" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/library.html" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-04-01 14:07:56 +0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William J. Frazer photograph album of the H.M.S. St. George</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Frazer, William John (1862-1938)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.136</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/184</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.10  Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in one album</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">122 Photographic Prints</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">on 60 pages.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1895/1898" type="inclusive">1895-1898</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_16e2c0553b20ad4e32a8b8506979f6e9" label="Abstract">Album compiled by Lieutenant William J. Frazer, of the British Royal Navy, chiefly documenting the voyages of the H.M.S. St. George, and the involvement of British forces in attacks on the Omani Arab insurgent Mubarak bin Rashid al-Mazrui at Mwele (present-day Kenya) in 1895, on Zanzibar in 1896, and on Benin in 1897.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c53e7d13ce5adb067234e5bc2710cee7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>The album is available for use in the Reading Room of the Archives and Special Collections department of the NYU Abu Dhabi Library.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e4369b722bb83ac17af48a6c3305dc25">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Acquired by purchase, November 2023.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f953e3e93cb670653e4c3e4570c697f5">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection consists of one photograph album, with photographs and maps arranged by their creator in largely chronological order.  Individual photographs may appear out of sequence, due to space limitations, but otherwise the contents are in chronological order.  The present finding aid lists the images in sections, according to date, location, or depicted events, with page numbers supplied by the processing archivist, as the volume is otherwise unpaginated.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4cb393d99c89d98571d933ecbaa920e6">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>William J. (John) Frazer (1862-1938) was born on 31 July, 1862, in Guntur (at that time part of Madras, now in Andhra Pradesh state), India, the son of William Morgan Frazer (1830-1884), a colonel in the British Army in India and Clementina Maria (née Hooper) Frazer (1838-1865). Given that his mother died when he was very young, he was likely sent back to England, and the earliest census records in which he is listed (1881) show him at a boy's school in Cheltenham, with his occupation listed as "cadet in the Merchant Naval Service."  </p><p>After a decade as a merchant seaman, he was commissioned into the Royal Navy Reserve as a sub-lieutenant in January 1892 and served aboard the H.M.S. St. George, beginning in October 1894, and being promoted in rank to Lieutenant in January 1895.  In February 1895, he participated in the punitive expedition on the Brass River, in the Niger Delta of West Africa, which was in response to an attack led by the Nembe king William Koko against the headquarters of the Royal Niger Company.  The H.M.S. St. George was one of four Royal Navy ships that participated in this raid, which led to the destruction of the city of Nembe. In August 1895, Frazer participated in another punitive expedition, this time in East Africa, against the Arab Mazrui chieftain Mbaruk bin Rashid, who had rebelled against efforts by the British to supplant his rule an area southwest of Mombasa with that of the Zanzibari Sultan's forces.  The British naval expeditionary force, which included the crew of the H.M.S. St. George, landed at Mombasa and proceeded inland, routing Mbaruk's forces at his stronghold in Mwele, although Mbaruk escaped and the rebellion was suppressed the following year. </p><p>Frazer was also present on the H.M.S. St. George the following year, when it participated in the Anglo-Zanzibar War on 27 August 1896.  The war, which consisted of a British naval bombardment of the Sultan's Palace in Zanzibar that lasted approximately 40 minutes, was the result of the efforts of prince Khalid bin Barghash to ascend to the position of Sultan after the death of his uncle, Hamad bin Thuwaini, in contradiction to an earlier agreement between Zanzibari and British officials.  When Khalid refused to relinquish control of the palace, the British ships moored in Zanzibar harbor attacked, forcing Khalid to surrender and be replaced by Hamoud bin Mohammed, the preferred choice of the British to be sultan.  Frazer's last military engagement as a member of the H.M.S. St. George took place as a member of the Benin Expedition in February 1897.  this punitive expedition was in response to an ambush and murder of the British consul-general in the region, James Robert Phillips, and most of his party of over 250 soldiers and porters, as they were en route to the city of Benin to meet with Ovonramwen, the oba, or ruler, to discuss trade disagreements.  The expedition that Frazer participated in led to the capture of Benin, the exile of its ruler, and following destruction of the ruler's palace, the confiscation of a large quantity of religious artifacts and artworks, which were sent to England and later became known as the "Benin Bronzes."</p><p>After leaving the H.M.S. St. George, Frazer continued his naval career for another decade, serving as a first-lieutenant aboard the H.M.S. Theseus (1899), the Duke of Wellington (1902) and the Erebus (1904), among other postings, before retiring with the rank of Commander in October 1907.  He was called back into service during World War I, and placed in command of several ships, including the Cambria (1914), the Columbine (1915) and the Satellite (1917), before retiring once again, with the rank of Captain, in November 1918. </p><p>He lived his retirement years in Acton, Middlesex, with his sisters Clementina and Anna. He died in Acton Hospital on 12 May 1938.</p><p>[Sources:  Auction records, Noonan's Mayfair, 12 February 1997, https://www.noonans.co.uk/auctions/archive/lot-archive/results/30948/, as accessed on 12 December 2024; plus British birth, census, and probate records found on Ancestry.com.]</p>  </bioghist>
  <custodhist id="aspace_465b55498f3041c9df3a08681f065968">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>This album was part of the library of Esmond Bradley Martin (1941-2018), an American- born geographer and wildlife conservationist who lived in Nairobi, Kenya.  It was likely acquired by him at auction in London in 1997, as online records indicate that it was auctioned by Noonan's of Mayfair as lot 307 on 12 February 1997.  See:  https://www.noonans.co.uk/archive/lot-archive/results/30948/ .  This album, along with other selected titles from Martin's library, were auctioned as part of his estate in late 2023.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_8b35c6952415631dc0d13e2eef65b8c8">
    <head>Preferred citation</head>
<p>[item], [page number], William J. Frazer photograph album of the H.M.S. St. George, MC-136, New York University Abu Dhabi Library, Abu Dhabi, UAE.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b852f5c95b7120207b27f7f255e760b2">
    <head>Processing information</head>
<p>Processed by Brad Bauer, December 2025.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_47c9bbc659a60e61bdc40306b664ce8b">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>This album, compiled by Lieutenant William J. Frazer, of the British Royal Navy, chiefly documented the voyages of the H.M.S. St. George, and the involvement of British forces in attacks on the Omani Arab insurgent Mubarak bin Rashid al-Mazrui at Mwele (present-day Kenya) in 1895, on Zanzibar in 1896, and on Benin in 1897.</p><p>The album begins with the journey of the St. George to the South Atlantic, presumably in 1894, showing stops in Las Palmas (Canary Islands), Simon's Bay (present day South Africa), and St. Helena and Ascension Islands. Images include portraits of the ship's crew and landscapes of the places visited.  Although this section of the album contains a hand-drawn map of the Brass River Expedition in the Niger Delta against the Nembe king, William Koko, in February 1895, there are no contemporary photographs, only a reproduction of an artistic depiction of that raid.  The album resumes with other images from South Africa, such as scenes of Durban and Port Elizabeth, immediately following.  </p><p>A hand drawn map of the British expedition against the forces of Mubarak bin Rashid, in the territory of present-day Tanzania, in July and August 1885, is followed 8 images, chiefly of British encampments and soldiers, and then a map of a more specific raid against Mubarak bin Rashid at Mwele (in present-day Kenya) on 17 August 1895, followed by 7 images of his stockade, after the battle.  A further hand drawn map of Zanzibar, depicting the position of British ships off of the coast of Zanzibar Town on 27 August 1896, prefaces a section of photographs showing the bombardment of Zanzibar in what later came to be known as Anglo-Zanzibar War, or the "40 minute war," as that was the duration of the attack.  This war was precipitated by the refusal of the Zanzibari prince Khalid ibn Barghash, following the death of the previous sultan, to accept British demands that he renounce his claim to power in favor of that of his brother.  The St. George was one of the six British ships pictured on the map that shelled Zanzibar, and the following 20 images depict the battle, and the damage to buildings--including the Sultan's palace--and loss of life.</p><p>The next segment of the album depicts the British attack against the King of Benin in February 1897, with two hand drawn maps and 14 images related to this.  Following that, the album concludes with 6 images from a visit to South Africa (Simons Bay, Cape Town in April-June 1897, followed by images of ceremonies and events following the ship's return to Britain in February 1898.  Other naval ships at anchor in Portsmouth are depicted in the closing pages, and a portrait of the officers of the St. George includes William Frazer.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8ffec3afe5b4425a466f19d622a5bcce">
    <head>Conditions governing use</head>
<p>The copyright status of images in this album is unknown.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Great Britain. Royal Navy -- Officers</geogname>
    <title source="lcsh">Great Britain.  Royal Navy -- Ships</title>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Zanzibar</geogname>
    <title source="lcsh">Benin Punitive Expedition, Nigeria, 1897</title>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_7a892104efe49f73dc4250ef1f641e61" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 1:  the journey from England to South Africa (ship and ship's crew, Las Palmas, Simon's Bay)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33511</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1894/1894">1894</unitdate><container id="aspace_679d4c6a5f4820bea35e162c3dc6d3fe" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[1-8]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f953ead17cb4853ad39087d619311db7" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 2:  St. Helena Island and Ascension Island</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33512</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1895-01/1895-01">January 1895, and undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c90efd773e42bd3e0dcfa44a42b97f6" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[9-15]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_aa537225631b25ae98b200e1a78a21c4" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 3:  Brass River expedition, Niger River delta (includes hand-drawn map)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33513</unitid><container id="aspace_20ab27d875e57fcf0588f12ffb0e9899" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[16, 30]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_1ea400594080c2d345e60ea81ce59a4c" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 4:  South Africa, Durban and Port Elizabeth</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33514</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1895/1895">undated, circa mid-1895</unitdate><container id="aspace_92b465fd777762cd5b5e89b962232e5f" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[16-20, 42]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_0c8d1425133eb73e600129df636d8bc1" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 5:  Mwele, punitive expeditions against Mubarak bin Rashid (includes 2 hand-drawn maps)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33515</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1895-07/1895-08" type="inclusive">July - August 1895</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe8b9dffb399215de316482ecc9e0245" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[21-30]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_8ea323eb02fc62e7e30f10b4acc598b9" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 6:  Zanzibar, attack on (includes hand-drawn map)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33516</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1896-08-26/1896-08-27" type="inclusive">August 26-27, 1896</unitdate><container id="aspace_87546fed64effb444de227287e98f2c4" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[31-41]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_81bc7611be0dcd19be1a1f9263120442" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 7:  Benin punitive expedition (includes two hand-drawn maps)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33517</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1897-02-08/1897-02-28" type="inclusive">February 8 - 28, 1897</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d45ac226f6319447e15649531d1ba2f" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[42-47]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_e9d2d9f1b5bc800a497ef6558ddda68c" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 8: Simons Town, South Africa</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33518</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1897-02/1897-02">April 1897 and undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e34431ed20dc233a86b226f228b5ee7" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[48-49]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_21e2114cfa37adc6f0545cb56fa2d54c" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="pages"><did><unittitle>Section 9:  return to England, including ships at Portsmouth and Plymouth, crews</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/33519</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1898-02/1898-06" type="inclusive">February - June 1898</unitdate><container id="aspace_45ac46263347034c167f6ab66d900648" label="Graphic Materials" type="page">[50-60]</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
