<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="AE" mainagencycode="AE-NyNyUAD" url="https://findingaids.library.nyu.edu/nyuad/ad_mc_163/">ad_mc_163</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Selywn T.C. Harrison naval logbooks <num>AD.MC.163</num></titleproper><author>Brad Bauer</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</publisher><p><date>June 2026</date></p><address><addressline>New York University Abu Dhabi, C-2</addressline><addressline>P.O. 129188</addressline><addressline>Abu Dhabi</addressline><addressline>nyuad-asc-group@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/library.html" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://nyuad.nyu.edu/en/library.html" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2026-06-25 15:40:20 +0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Selwyn T.C. Harrison naval logbooks</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Harrison, Selwyn T.C. (Thorpe Cholmeley) (1908-1980)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AD.MC.163</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/239</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.34 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">contained in 2 volumes (2 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926/1928" type="inclusive">1926-1980</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" type="bulk">1926-1928</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_3e8510800e078929a26022cc56f7187f" label="Abstract">Two Royal Navy Midshipman's manuscript journals belonging to Selwyn T. C. Harrison, covering the period from January 1926 to December 1928, when he served aboard HMS Frobisher, HMS Emerald and HMS Enterprise, while on training assignments in the Mediterranean and Aegean Seas (based in Malta), and later in Hong Kong, Sri Lanka, and the Arabian (Persian) Gulf.  The journals describe daily life onboard, tasks assigned to midshipmen, and impressions of the countries where the ships were stationed and events witnessed there.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_76a2d17b32a9cf1e7f1c4446ef6fbc92">
    <head>Conditions governing access</head>
<p>The Selwyn T.C. Harrison naval logbooks are open and available for use in the Archives and Special Collections department of the New York University Abu Dhabi Library.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_c6e2caa855897ec8b54519404ae6ae9c">
    <head>Immediate source of acquisition</head>
<p>Acquired by purchase, October 2025.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3cd65e43a4747fd553942b0ffdfd485e">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Selwyn T.C. Harrison naval logbooks are arranged in two volumes, in the chronological order in which the entries were kept, save for a few inserted illustrations and photographs added after the conclusion of the text in the second volume.  Since the logbooks were not paginated, the description of its contents are divided by month in this finding aid, and delineated by counted page numbers that are added in brackets by the processing archivist.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_4cd585077e62cd4350397ed22a585d51">
    <head>Biographical note</head>
<p>Selwyn T.C. Harrison (1908-1980) was born at Darwa Dam in Igatpuri, located in the present-day state of Maharashtra, India on 11 November 1908, the son of Sir Charlton Scott Cholmeley Harrison, KCIE and Violet (née Monamy Buckell) Harrison. Harrison's father was a civil engineer who was active in India from 1902 to 1933, and best known for his work on constructing dams and canals.  Selwyn was one of three children of the Harrisons, but little else is known about his childhood and upbringing.  </p><p>At the age of 17, in January 1926, he enlisted in the Royal Navy, and as a cadet joined the crew of the H.M.S. Frobisher, based in the Mediterranean.  In September 1926, he attained the rank of midshipman, and the following year in November, transferred to the H.M.S. Emerald, while the two ships were based in Hong Kong, and in June 1928 he was attached to the H.M.S. Enterprise, another cruiser, based at that time in the Indian Ocean region.  At the end of that year, he returned to London, where he attended a promotion course at the Royal Naval College in Greenwich, during which time he received a promotion to the rank of sub-lieutenant.  He was reassigned to the H.M.S. Enterprise in April 1930, and by the time he was assigned to his next ship, the destroyer H.M.S. Vanessa (October 1931-March 1932), he had risen to the rank of lieutenant (March 1931).  Following the completion of an observers' course while attached to the H.M.S. Excellent (October 1933 to July 1934), most of his subsequent postings were as an observer on board various vessels.  In March 1939 he was promoted to the rank of Lieutenant Commander.  During World War II, his postings focused on naval aviation, being based at naval air stations in Arbroath (Scotland) and in the Caribbean, in Trinidad, and lastly on an aircraft carrier, the H.M.S. Furious (January 1943 - June 1944).  From 1945 to 1950 he was attached to the aircraft carrier H.M.S. President, for duty with the Ministry of Aircraft Production, at the rank of Auxiliary Commander. In either 1952 or 1953 he retired from active duty in the Royal Navy.</p><p>Harrison was married twice, first to Louise af Petersens, who he married in Singapore in 1935 and with whom he had two children, and later with Anne Forbes Panton (1926-1967) in 1952.  That same year, following the death of his father in England, he changed his surname to "Harrison-Wallace," and not much is known about his later years other than he became a tea planter in British East Africa, and remained in the region after the independence of Tanzania and Kenya, until he died in Malindi, Kenya on 7 July 1980.</p><p>Sources:  
World War II Unit Histories and Officers, compiled by Hans Houterman and Jeroen Koppes; https://www.unithistories.com/officers/RN_officersH2.html (accessed in March 2026)
Ancestry.com</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_34b6d85fe255363e05e05daa71817590">
    <head>Preferred citation</head>
<p>[date of entry],[volume number], Selwyn T.C. Harrison naval logbooks, MC-163, New York University Abu Dhabi Library, Abu Dhabi, UAE.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_c0a41f3f51b42cad2bee2836dd1d9ea8">
    <head>Processing information</head>
<p>Processed by Brad Bauer, April - June 2026.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3e5e1fca98479a680b1e7d0c8e8b5f82">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>The Selywn T.C. Harrison naval logbooks consist of two volumes of Royal Navy midshipman's manuscript journals belonging to Selwyn T. C. Harrison, covering the period from January 1926 to December 1928, when he served aboard HMS Frobisher, HMS Emerald and HMS Enterprise, while on training assignments in the Mediterranean and Aegean Seas (based in Malta), and later in Hong Kong, Sri Lanka, and the Arabian (Persian) Gulf.  The journals describe daily life onboard, tasks assigned to midshipmen, and impressions of the countries where the ships were stationed and events witnessed there.  In addition, the journals are hand-illustrated with technical drawings, maps, ship's silhouettes, sketches and watercolors depicting other ships and subjects of local interest.</p><p>The journals are divided into two volumes, with the first covering the period from January 1926, when Harrison joined the HMS Frobisher in Malta, through mid-1928, when the ship to which he was assigned at that time, the HMS Enterprise, returned to Colombo, Ceylon (Sri Lanka) following several months of duty in the Arabian (Persian) Gulf.  The second volume covers the second half of 1928, when Harrison attended training camps in Ceylon and then served on the HMS Enterprise, as it traversed the western Indian Ocean, the east coast of Africa and the Suez Canal, on its way back to England, where it arrived in December.  Harrison's tour of duty as a midshipman seemed to be fairly evenly divided between the Mediterranean, where he served on the HMS Frobisher, based in Malta, from January through December 1926; the Far East, while based in Hong Kong, but also visiting Shanghai and experiencing ports of call in Singapore and Malaya, aboard both the HMS Frobisher and the HMS Emerald, between January and December 1927; and the Indian Ocean and Arabian (Persian) Gulf, while serving on the HMS Emerald and HMS Enterprise, from January through December 1928.</p><p>Much of the journals consist of handwritten entries by Harrison, with pen and ink illustrations by him tipped into the journals at various points, and often recounting mundane details of shipboard life, with descriptions of maintenance activities and training exercises, such as target practice; regular activities, such as church services, and mock battles and drills involving other nearby ships.  Much attention is given to athletic competitions and at times, social events with civilian populations onshore, including dances and other festivities.  It is apparent that both the handwritten entries and illustrations were reviewed by a commanding officer, whose signature appears next to entries at regular intervals while Harrison is stationed on the HMS Frobisher, and when he is assigned to the Emerald, the officer there adds comments in addition to his signature, even chiding Harrison at one point for his negative comments regarding the cleanliness of another naval vessel they inspected at port in Ceylon.  From this, it appears that the maintenance of these journals was yet another task that Harrison was evaluated on as part of his training as a midshipman in the Royal Navy.  </p><p>Interspersed among the descriptions of seafaring activities, however, are descriptions of key events during this time period in which the ships that Harrison served on played a supporting role.  While based in Hong Kong in 1927, the Frobisher made multiple trips to Shanghai and other locations along the Chinese coast, around the same time that tensions between Kuomintang (Nationalist) and Communist forces in Shanghai boiled over, leading to mass arrests, executions, and fighting between these forces, some of which was witnessed by the crew of the Frobisher. In early 1928, after the ikhwan, the irregular army of Bedouin warriors who enabled the rise in Ibn Sa'ud in central Arabia, attacked Kuwait, the HMS Emerald was sent to Kuwait to support the Royal Air Force in its efforts to defend the city and country, remaining there until the ikhwan were defeated and British forces were scaled back in April of that year.  </p><p>The final leg of Harrison's training as a midshipman, aboard the HMS Enterprise in the second half of 1928, led him to various places in the western Indian Ocean, including Seychelles, Dar-es-Salaam, and Mombasa, including a short period when the ship transported the Prince of Wales and his entourage during a hunting expedition in Tanganyika, and their subsequent return to Europe via Italy.  This last leg of the trip may have been a propitious one for Harrison, as following his retirement from active duty in the Royal Navy around 1950 he settled in Malindi, Kenya, and lived there for the remaining thirty years of his life.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_56ce60b52a8a175726999e7211a37c56">
    <head>Conditions governing use</head>
<p>The copyright status of these materials is unknown, and unpublished content within the collection may be protected by copyright.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <title source="lcsh">Great Britain.  Royal Navy -- Ships</title>
    <geogname source="tgn">Kuwait</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n 80123145" source="lcsh">Basra, Iraq</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Abadan, Khuzestan Province, Iran</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Khor Fakkan, United Arab Emirates</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Colombo (Sri Lanka)</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n 79055155" source="lcsh">Mombasa (Kenya)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Zanzibar</geogname>
    <geogname authfilenumber="n 79145770" source="lcsh">Malta</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong</geogname>
    <title source="lcsh">Great Britain. Royal Navy -- Officers -- Training of</title>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_2d97c971d5033703afd12390e109552c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Volume 1</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41122</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-01/1982-07" type="inclusive">January 1926 - July 1928</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_dd0f0b8c74e70b3ca1206928a92d3620" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41178</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-01-22/1926-01-31" type="inclusive">January 22 - 31, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_2880a03f8cb5d746d64e8f550acd885f" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7a850f3ce7518313f8dcc525879eef61" parent="aspace_2880a03f8cb5d746d64e8f550acd885f" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_4ecb5d908ea0b001464d54c600dc4709" parent="aspace_7a850f3ce7518313f8dcc525879eef61" type="page">[5-13]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_686e4e9aa06952305834d6cdf1edbffa" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41366</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-03-02/1926-03-23" type="inclusive">March 2 - 23, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_9faff058231c1f546c685cd53e385534" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_46c7d537874de226f8c8a4eff943f469" parent="aspace_9faff058231c1f546c685cd53e385534" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_105ebc45ba11d1ed63335c5b91f09b9d" parent="aspace_46c7d537874de226f8c8a4eff943f469" type="page">[13-20]</container></did><odd id="aspace_9fbf9fd28199647c3a29d7b845a36de6"><head>Contents</head><p>Contents:  training exercises at sea during first two weeks, then return to Malta, where go ashore to a camp for field training for 12 days.  Descriptions of shooting exercises, mock battles, as well as recreation, such as football matches and balls.  Tipped-in hand-drawn diagrams of "Air Leads of Firing Gear," between pp. 16-17.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_0ca09fa3e33506278a4a3619a84c71c1" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41367</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-04-12/1926-04-30" type="inclusive">April 12 - 30, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_049e633b3c40ab46d3367d5b773f70b6" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_96bb3b8cc4d7987318e2cc3834291166" parent="aspace_049e633b3c40ab46d3367d5b773f70b6" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_83f4701eab354385735a311150138fef" parent="aspace_96bb3b8cc4d7987318e2cc3834291166" type="page">[20-24]</container></did><odd id="aspace_8a87c80172ef4701aeea62207f717446"><head>General</head><p>Return to ship on April 12, and most activities recorded took place there, except for going onshore to use firing ranges.  Notes visits of ships from the Italian fleet (20-24 April) and the French fleet (27-30 April) and visits to ships of both fleets, and includes two tipped-in pen and ink illustrations of ships from both fleets.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_f5054898000ef57afe80be24971180b8" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta and at sea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41368</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-05-01/1926-05-31" type="inclusive">May 1 - 31, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6b501d5a6a2c7165b8cf69d983e170b" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2ae6bbb538c941ff65c4733b06db8116" parent="aspace_a6b501d5a6a2c7165b8cf69d983e170b" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_bb0253c9da278a749cd82a63c56072f5" parent="aspace_2ae6bbb538c941ff65c4733b06db8116" type="page">[25-33]</container></did><odd id="aspace_70cfb8f708e823d9cef125a1a3db25cb"><head>Contents</head><p>In port at Malta and at sea, describing drills, exercises, examination, with one ink and gouache illustration of "Adjustable Receiver for Forbes' Distance Recorder" tipped in between pages 26-27.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_70666f652f1638a9efce7afb84906580" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta and at sea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41369</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-06-01/1926-06-30" type="inclusive">June 1 - 30, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_627bedfd377b51afa260ace0951099bf" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cebdeda2b610a31492fe2f6afe6435df" parent="aspace_627bedfd377b51afa260ace0951099bf" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_e29e00170318a52ef5b6ad5c0eb78d4a" parent="aspace_cebdeda2b610a31492fe2f6afe6435df" type="page">[33-42]</container></did><odd id="aspace_c6b8a21f58905a6fc03a3f0051c72cad"><head>Contents</head><p>In port at Malta and at sea, conducting efficiency tests and usual exercises, until leave port on 22 June and head to Cephalonia Island and Argostoli until July 5.  Description of training activities, including seaplane flights, and time ashore for picnics, and training with Australian ships.  Includes tipped-in ink illustrations of "Mill's Bomb" and "Neil Robertson's Stretcher."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_33013ea43025d90752a42b23e0348773" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at sea (Adriatic)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41370</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-07-01/1926-07-31" type="inclusive">July 1 - 31, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd2e1ddf36ebd28a4cac4386c2989047" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_0723c13187eb66265fa66d1400a1ee0d" parent="aspace_cd2e1ddf36ebd28a4cac4386c2989047" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_20499e11bed0017209a139c3e28ff41e" parent="aspace_0723c13187eb66265fa66d1400a1ee0d" type="page">[43-57]</container></did><odd id="aspace_25d1d097088b30e701e44961952adb7b"><head>Contents</head><p>Leave Argostoli on 5 July and proceed to Ancona, where arrive on 8th.  Arrived at Brioni Island on the 17th, left on 27th for Dragomesti.  Noting concentration drills, exercises firing torpedos at sea, onshore activities include boxing matches with local clubs, football matches, dances, searchlight demonstrations for locals, etc.  Illustrations include "Laying out a sheet anchor," "Listing ship," "Barr and Stroud Step by Step Motor," and insignia of the Frobisher (latter done in pencil).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_428d172119a08b9839e66f6758e6c964" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at sea (Adriatic and Aegean) and at Malta</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41371</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-08-01/1926-08-31" type="inclusive">August 1 - 31, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_d328d3d9c47d91943dd3a6a6e6934eed" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cefe65fcbd25e836f4a4c2255c3c0d62" parent="aspace_d328d3d9c47d91943dd3a6a6e6934eed" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_0871718627373588b4d83dda21b1c393" parent="aspace_cefe65fcbd25e836f4a4c2255c3c0d62" type="page">[57-68]</container></did><odd id="aspace_204cab3eb5c83198c47161d8815b03e6"><head>Contents</head><p>Details war games and other exercises conducted at Dragomesti, from which they left on 8 August, and at sea until returned to Malta on 11 August, and then at sea again from 21-27 August, when arrived in Sigri harbor.  All the time, they were conducting drills, mock warfare, maneuvering exercises, firing of guns, etc.  At Sigri, they left on launch to explore the Dardanelles, and from description, battlefield sites of the World War I Gallipoli campaign.  Tipped-in illustrations of "High Speed Mine Sweep, 4 August 1926" and "Compass Platform and Fore Control."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_1011b5893e71dc67b0bbe357334b52b7" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at sea (Aegean)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41372</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-09-01/1926-09-26" type="inclusive">September 1 - 26, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_35239b3efc4851af3e1017b8736d1321" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_cb707c09f70ee68755ca91f12c76354d" parent="aspace_35239b3efc4851af3e1017b8736d1321" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_b3bc1e0d0ee0bf3831fbe4462ed280ad" parent="aspace_cb707c09f70ee68755ca91f12c76354d" type="page">[68-78]</container></did><odd id="aspace_39ed1a3cef50de3fc3bba129ed4b440a"><head>Contents</head><p>At Karystos Bay (Sept 1-6), where there is an inspection of the ship by admiral (unnamed), Skiathos (Sept 7-8, 11-13), where between exercises had a shore excursion and camping trip as a break, then to Volo (Sept. 17-25) where participated in regatta, went ashore for excursion to Mount Pelion, before needed to be towed back to Malta.  Tipped-in illustration (pen and ink) of "Protector Paravane."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_5ff43e202f2defd60f1f624659d4115d" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41373</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-10-05/1926-10-31" type="inclusive">October 5 - 31, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac1dba52587846695d8a345e4358e478" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c96d5ac2cabacebcb71d69673aecb36d" parent="aspace_ac1dba52587846695d8a345e4358e478" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_71fb07b0e7f8f043e685b9f042095de5" parent="aspace_c96d5ac2cabacebcb71d69673aecb36d" type="page">[78-89]</container></did><odd id="aspace_c5e31363ebd9de3d3554046be59c6851"><head>Contents</head><p>Back at Malta, where the ship was in dry-dock for the annual "bottom-scraping," and later, painting of the ship, and usual other activities (at sea for torpedo practice, onshore for football and hockey matches, etc.)
Tipped-in illustrations include ink and gouache "Coloring of Projectiles," pen and ink "In Paravanes" and "First Cutter's Fore Davit."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_e64c3252991d72280fa09a9092e2c1b4" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta and at sea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41374</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-11-01/1926-11-30" type="inclusive">November 1 - 30, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7d7e4d5be6353e571f42b0a038324f4" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2564bb20b74d4d319f1707799c35e1d7" parent="aspace_c7d7e4d5be6353e571f42b0a038324f4" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_1dd2a6bc2848ede1db7656f9d91336c7" parent="aspace_2564bb20b74d4d319f1707799c35e1d7" type="page">[89-97]</container></did><odd id="aspace_648be1259777bbfee03592fb2de4dc19"><head>Contents</head><p>At Malta, at sea nearby, and at training course at "Pembroke Hutments."  Pretty similar activities to previous months.
Illustrations:  "Sheer Legs" and "Springs"</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_161502058b3f18fd41d52f5b1fa220d2" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta and at sea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41375</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1926-12-01/1926-12-31" type="inclusive">December 1 - 31, 1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9bd1fe168562832ee89e1cd369953ed" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2034484ecd0f4742c76abce87497a564" parent="aspace_f9bd1fe168562832ee89e1cd369953ed" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_0747cba24717d0ca35cd6ebdd4b767d6" parent="aspace_2034484ecd0f4742c76abce87497a564" type="page">[97-108]</container></did><odd id="aspace_da08097dbc0af3ee6ce3e1333e499d41"><head>Contents</head><p>In Malta or short excursions at sea to run practice drills,etc.
Tipped in illustrations:  "Davit Heads," "Method of Rigging a Dan Buoy," "Ton Bucket," "Euphroe," "Crane Lighter No. 4", and ink and gouache map depictings journeys of Frobisher throughout the Mediterranean during the year 1926.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_9079a349889f2df933d1d0ab9b4948fe" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Malta, and then at sea (Mediterranean, Athens, Suez Canal, Aden, Colombo)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41376</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-01-01/1927-01-29" type="inclusive">January 1 - 29, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c117f1ac8966eb99cee5140d9b57bca" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_b389ffc3adbb9844f59ab7411f75160c" parent="aspace_7c117f1ac8966eb99cee5140d9b57bca" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_b0bfe3f5484933cd5a5c22cd4a433c5a" parent="aspace_b389ffc3adbb9844f59ab7411f75160c" type="page">[109-120]</container></did><odd id="aspace_8a55c6f4fad10e6960194a6ea7025b8c"><head>Contents</head><p>In first part of month, the crew trained in and around Malta, then proceeded on a voyage to Greece which ended in Athens, on the 15th, when they received orders to proceed to China.  During voyage lost two men, one overboard, one to suicide.  Returned to Malta, and on 19th set sail from Malta bound for Shanghai.  Reached mouth of Nile and Suez Canal by 21st, passed the canal and into Red Sea on 22nd, Aden on the 24th, Ceylon and Colombo on the 29th, shore leave to Mt. Lavinia Hotel and beach.  Departed that evening.  
Tipped-in illustrations:  "W.T. Door Clip," "Large River Gunboat," "Oil Supplies, Freshwater Island, Singapore," "Sail Plans."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_9e6753fe8867b9e7c881b2991874d872" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at sea, Singapore, Hong Kong</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41377</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-02-02/1927-02-28" type="inclusive">February [2] - 28, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe84e9cde1d8a74c00369f2dd8dc1db2" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_47448934f66db302a1197036c1b2db03" parent="aspace_fe84e9cde1d8a74c00369f2dd8dc1db2" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_5607523dcb8cd555eebc460d402fd659" parent="aspace_47448934f66db302a1197036c1b2db03" type="page">[120-128]</container></did><odd id="aspace_44e0c6a2a94c2185b1341ae4465da136"><head>Contents</head><p>Arrived in Singapore, only there for one day, with limited shore leave, and machine gun exercises prior to that, before departing for Hong Kong, where arrived a little over a week later, on February 8.  Described maintenance and painting of ship, field hockey games, arrival of S.S. Empress with American tourists, onshore parade cancelled due to rain, and exercises with field guns (firing on targets at an island 3 miles away) also postponed due to rain.  Lecture about role they were playing in defense of British territory in China, observance of George Washington's birthday on February 22 with visit onboard of American ensign.  
Tipped-in illustrations (4) include "Sail Plans," "Line Sketch Midships", "Diagram of Detphc Charge "D" (all ink illustrations) and pencil sketch of "Typical [Chinese] Junk" (latter with patched sails and what looks like an American flag on the stern).</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_028a4566fb58e7f36b598a23860b4bbf" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Hong Kong</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41378</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-03-01/1927-03-31" type="inclusive">March 1 - 31, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_448b950584289c85fd8bfab7db3582b4" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_fbbd07ac56fec39e84f6b43470643f0e" parent="aspace_448b950584289c85fd8bfab7db3582b4" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_898ffbf486811f898b66126f5c4aaf20" parent="aspace_fbbd07ac56fec39e84f6b43470643f0e" type="page">[128-138]</container></did><odd id="aspace_abfd5ac1d7d030e0a580c139c611320d"><head>Contents</head><p>Most of description includes daily maintenance tasks, lectures, artillery drills, then had a punitive expedition starting on the 22nd, as a result of pirates attacking a civilian ship  ("S.S. Hop Sang, belonging to Messrs. Jardine and Matheson"), which led serval ships to Bias Bay, where they anchored and then landed onshore the next day, blowing up two villages (Kwai Chau and Hoi Chau), and destroying four junks.  Noted movement of other ships to and from Shanghai, and that of the HMS Emerald to Colombo to pick up crew sent from England and to bring them back to Hong Kong.
Tipped-in illustrations (4) include "Weighing by Deck Tackle," "Arrangement of Steering Gear," "Collision Mat," "Punitive Expedtion at Bias Bay, against the pirate villages of Kwai Chau and Hoi Chau,"</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_d0b9cc7b842fd9c7b1dbf3b96a00941e" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Hong Kong</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41379</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-04-02/1927-04-29" type="inclusive">April 2 - 29, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_0339771b95784f12008d3fb68f5b9d8c" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_52e115ac401482e3d8f81f047d381b6e" parent="aspace_0339771b95784f12008d3fb68f5b9d8c" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_42281bb611b9a2330514da31643de9ef" parent="aspace_52e115ac401482e3d8f81f047d381b6e" type="page">[139-146]</container></did><odd id="aspace_eabcffe8e047b265f3f3cd06bceeabdc"><head>Contents</head><p>Mainly described maintenance and training exercises.  At one point (April 5), a civilian ship, S.S. Tjileboet, ran aground at Ting Ling Island, and the Frobisher and several other ships headed there to help with transferring passengers from that ship, etc.  Visit an American ship at harbor, and comments on how undisciplined the crew seemed and how messy the ship seemed compared to a British ship (Apr. 24)
Tipped-in illustrations (3) include:  "Browns patent Telemotor Transmitter," "7.5 C.P. MK. V. Mounting," and "Sloop Rig Skiff."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_c76a527f59c793aca4d626b522c3590f" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Hong Kong</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41381</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-05-01/1927-05-31" type="inclusive">May 1 - 31, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_7cd0c1cfd2790cf2d3b4da27f6ae5a15" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2a3839dbb9a6300e44cd1bbaeb528a11" parent="aspace_7cd0c1cfd2790cf2d3b4da27f6ae5a15" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_fb7c4cad43ec71554d57acf3d9908e91" parent="aspace_2a3839dbb9a6300e44cd1bbaeb528a11" type="page">[146-153]</container></did><odd id="aspace_f0c836f3dba2eb928273afdbf23a2e97"><head>Contents</head><p>Describes mostly exercises onboard and onshore, with a typhoon warning at end of month.  As with the previous month, they had very rainy weather, which curtailed some of their activities.
Tipped-in illustrations (4) :  "32 ft Dipping Lug Cutter," "27 ft Montagu Rig Whaler," "32 ft Sloop Rig Cutter," "32 ft De Horsey Rig Cutter."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_2ab6207711ace5a46479331fb538b53f" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Hong Kong</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41382</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-06-01/1927-06-30" type="inclusive">June 1 - 30, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a9276ca3064980a7ff8f549d01374e9" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_b6bea04bd2b737e5136b3378494d2fb9" parent="aspace_0a9276ca3064980a7ff8f549d01374e9" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_660db19d03272522f9385d1ce373bae2" parent="aspace_b6bea04bd2b737e5136b3378494d2fb9" type="page">[153-161]</container></did><odd id="aspace_d0b2730e08e8deb81e373ef6b6490cab"><head>Contents</head><p>Hong Kong and at sea.  The King's Birthday is commemorated on the 3rd with ceremonies and a parade.  Otherwise, the entries describe exercises (signal, torpedo, searchlight display, etc.) and some time to get off of the ship  and play golf.
Tipped-in illustrations (3) : "30 ft Dipping Lug Gig," "Cockburn's Full Bore Safety Valve," "Mitchell's Thrust Block," with latter two in pen and gouache.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_a7e1804a0dee115959825bf9d106307d" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at sea and in Shanghai</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41383</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-07-01/1927-07-31" type="inclusive">July 1 - 31, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_c84016707bfaf47d1574ab7a5a1c59cd" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6100ba93b8b8390dd91694025369a242" parent="aspace_c84016707bfaf47d1574ab7a5a1c59cd" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_4c1e6392fbf4a54ee74da35951b4c8ff" parent="aspace_6100ba93b8b8390dd91694025369a242" type="page">[161-167]</container></did><odd id="aspace_265545b358228d14872a51d259a8085d"><head>Contents</head><p>Departure from Hong Kong, visit to Amoy, entry to Whangpo River, docking in Shanghai in time to witness French celebration of Bastille Day, as well as subsequent collision of the French cruiser "Michelet" with "President Cleveland." Also witness the raiding of a Chinese steamer by Cantonese troops, with executions of purported Communists onboard.</p><p>Tipped-in illustrations (2) :  "Amoy Harbor" and "Depth Charge Pistol." </p></odd></c><c id="aspace_1c3ebce37fc851ab7130044aade614ee" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at sea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41384</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-08-01/1927-08-31" type="inclusive">August 1 - 31, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_d45ca44f108bea755f7604f99640b73e" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_20f9b80e1ebfb4b6d9193f71a56d128b" parent="aspace_d45ca44f108bea755f7604f99640b73e" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_1e53d18a1066aea79ece33f3e3b122a4" parent="aspace_20f9b80e1ebfb4b6d9193f71a56d128b" type="page">[167-177]</container></did><odd id="aspace_8e1a5a78b8e73d765eb10af2c7fe58f0"><head>Contents</head><p>At sea, with visits to Wei Hai Wei, Liu Kung Tao island.  Described the usual exercises, on ship and a couple of opportunities to go onshore to picnic, play golf, swim, visit unused temple. 
Tipped-in illustration (1):  maps of Wei Hai Wei.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_ca644d8c63e98ea364a2bba18f72cf0a" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Wusung, Shanghai, at sea, and Hong Kong  </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41385</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-09-01/1927-09-30" type="inclusive">September 1 - 30, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_082faff61af85ec11a891373c9090ae7" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e7bc4529579606a12bf8b96656de7df2" parent="aspace_082faff61af85ec11a891373c9090ae7" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_717d7ccd7fafeab87748cdf2f9c142e2" parent="aspace_e7bc4529579606a12bf8b96656de7df2" type="page">[177-186]</container></did><odd id="aspace_c7b4e85ee22712997d1f71179b3a59f9"><head>Contents</head><p>Anchorage at Wusung, witness fight between Chinese authorities and enemy ships, return journey to Hong Kong, including routine shipboard training exercises and maintenance, along with descriptions of the Portuguese gunboat, the "Senhor Barbosa," and American ships in Hong Kong harbor.
 
Tipped-in illustrations (3) :  "Rough track chart of engagement between Wusung Fort and three Northern Cruisers," "Hong Kong Harbour," "Cockburn's Safety Valve."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_63d7c177fd221dee02a19b537a1540a7" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Hong Kong</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41386</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-10-01/1927-10-31" type="inclusive">October 1 - 31, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c52da7797c4d9a99592eb1789edf8df" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c06c9e97556de86d79c41e9e938040b0" parent="aspace_2c52da7797c4d9a99592eb1789edf8df" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_402f51d567df201df14c97790fd9e64c" parent="aspace_c06c9e97556de86d79c41e9e938040b0" type="page">[186-194]</container></did><odd id="aspace_d8c718ff78718138fa2378a4f95878ab"><head>Contents</head><p>War games and other drills, maintenance.  Observed Sikh riflemen at practice one evening.  Went onshore in middle of month so that the Frobisher could go into dry dock for maintenance and repairs.  
Tipped-in illustrations (3):  "High Pressure Turbine," "Submerged Fire Pistol," "Above Water Pistol."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_1c987309eb3ec3e1fe710e634d44d374" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Frobisher at Hong Kong and at sea, H.M.S. Emerald at Trincomalee and Colombo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41387</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-11-01/1927-11-30" type="inclusive">November 1 - 30, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_815ceab0f177ca2963416290e267d206" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_9197a579a11cf58126ea7b94b7b6d3f5" parent="aspace_815ceab0f177ca2963416290e267d206" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_c1d2a5b0cc38479a137ef753560fe62e" parent="aspace_9197a579a11cf58126ea7b94b7b6d3f5" type="page">[195-206]</container></did><odd id="aspace_1c29d1ea115530a445285daea4143dc4"><head>Contents</head><p>Big send off in Hong Kong as the Frobisher and accompanying ships leave for Ceylon. Followed by descriptions of mock battles and exercises at sea, docking in Singapore, shore leave in Malaya (Port Swettenham), including overnight trip to Kuala Lumpur for swimming and dancing.  Arrived in Colombo on the 18th, where Harrison disembarked and took a train to Trincomalee on the 19th, so that he could join his new ship, the Emerald.  Surprised by seemingly more relaxed atmosphere on new ship, lack of constant training exercises, etc.
Tipped-in illustrations :  map of Trincomali [sic]</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_35cefa46ff27083452563b28bf8b4b82" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Emerald at Trincomalee, Colombo, at sea, and Karachi</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41388</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927-12-01/1927-12-09" type="inclusive">December 1 - 9, 1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d9b8e09350c890fb89ece7a3d1c141e" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6fbbecda29c375768a0dbfae8be419fe" parent="aspace_8d9b8e09350c890fb89ece7a3d1c141e" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_feeecfc3bbc6b8bdd377d24796d263a2" parent="aspace_6fbbecda29c375768a0dbfae8be419fe" type="page">[206-210]</container></did><odd id="aspace_86e93b3be7270e525b4e5e9644fbf17f"><head>Contents</head><p>Left Trincomalee for Colombo, docked there. Harrison boarded the HMS Effingham to look around, notes his impressions in his journal. Following this, the Emerald is at sea, passes the southern coast of India, sees lunar eclipse, proceeds to Karachi, where they arrive on the 9th, and Harrison is given leave for 3 weeks to visit his parents for Christmas.  
Tipped-in illustrations (3) :  pencil sketch of "Southampton" plane, ink drawing of ship, pencil sketch of logo for Emerald.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_39f8c5a3ee438a83dba19136518964ec" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Emerald at Basra, Abadan, Kuwait and Bushire</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41389</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-01-01/1928-01-31" type="inclusive">January 5 - 31, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_8475c7947b18fd1216305010d3466b4d" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4652a85942cb65181799c4f2dfd3e939" parent="aspace_8475c7947b18fd1216305010d3466b4d" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_260ef59849feabf329ef7a0c4b7a26bc" parent="aspace_4652a85942cb65181799c4f2dfd3e939" type="page">[211-223]</container></did><odd id="aspace_27aeb79d8c6e5773afe55b9da33f0cb1"><head>Contents</head><p>Rejoined the Emerald on January 5, arriving in Basra on the HMS Verala.  Description of a punitive raid on January 7 "against a tribe of Arabs in the south [that] have been raiding villages and murdering the inhabitants."  At Basra, Harrison went ashore and visited the local bazaars, comments on level of skill displayed in crafts on sale.  On the 14th, he toured the A.P.O.C. refinery at Abadan, and then provides a detailed description on several pages of the journal.  On the 23rd the Emerald sails for Kuwait, where he visits the local bazaar, tours the city, joins a picnic hosted by the British Political Agent, before the Emerald sails for Bushire on the 30th.</p><p>Tipped in illustrations:  pen and ink drawing of HMS Emerald, "Section at 14 Ordinate," "Tanker Oiling from White Oil Jetty at Abadan," "Mid-Fort at Chiru."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_e4d4c96aded5183568488425152c9f79" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Emerald at Chiru, Hengam, and Kuwait</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41390</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-02-01/1928-02-29" type="inclusive">February 1 - 29, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0e9572d3b9eec5385e9ae509d74d09c" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_8179a3f9fc67194cb59b518a36793c17" parent="aspace_c0e9572d3b9eec5385e9ae509d74d09c" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_60bfb1bb44010eac9c1a4447950aed9d" parent="aspace_8179a3f9fc67194cb59b518a36793c17" type="page">[223-235]</container></did><odd id="aspace_1cf38961dd1ce85647b4e14562648ae0"><head>Contents</head><p>In the first half of month they go from Chiru to Hengam (on island of Qeshm), where spend a week and a half, and aside from maintenance of ship (painting), they fished, engaged in sports matches (hockey, tennis), and one morning went ashore to hunt gazelle.  On the 16th, when they were ready to sail to Bandar Abbas, they learned that the sheikh of Kuwait was threatened by an attack of a group called the "Darweish," who also threatened Ibn Saud.  So they were ordered to sail for Kuwait, arriving there the next day.  The bulk of the journal for the remainder of the month explains the context of the situation and details efforts to support the sheikh by sending bombardment groups and other parties ashore, and positioning the ship in a location to properly defend Kuwait from the attackers.</p><p>Tipped in illustrations:  H.M.S. Australia, Rolls-Royce armoured car, H.M.S. Emerald (latter is pen and ink wash).  </p></odd></c><c id="aspace_c1b5b09011cd42050535b17a18bc1266" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Emerald at Kuwait</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41391</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-03-01/1928-03-31" type="inclusive">March 1 - 31, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e2606bdfca5b595913abe7f92652baf" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3c97772c9a45b6d6d203648c6ee01a06" parent="aspace_6e2606bdfca5b595913abe7f92652baf" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_afc76a1eacc0c99f88dfbd16b41e0e7b" parent="aspace_3c97772c9a45b6d6d203648c6ee01a06" type="page">[235-249]</container></did><odd id="aspace_5e0517a2962fe29245ec4e57104593af"><head>Contents</head><p>Describes chores on ship, landing guns/cannon, and personnel onshore, and the reported threats of Ibn Saud to ally with "Darweesh" to attack Kuwait (with the Ikhwan).  Detailed description of preparations, events on shore, to which Harrison provided a summary and history of Wahhabism based on reading he had been doing.  Most of the remaining descriptions are of athletic contests between crews of Emerald and other Royal Navy ships, as well as descriptions of visits onboard by VIPs, such as a commanding officer from Baghdad or the ruling family of Kuwait.  </p><p>Tipped in illustration:  map of "Persian Gulf and its approaches, HMS Emerald," "diagrammatic arrangement of [racing] car / Malcolm Campbell, 19 Feb 1928," "HMS Royal Oak," "Transverse Watertight Bulkhead." </p></odd></c><c id="aspace_e7d2734dad1bff89f216c4dcb3ca9dd2" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Emerald at Kuwait, H.M.S. Enterprise at Kuwait, Shatt-al-Arab, Abadan, Basra</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41392</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-04-03/1928-04-30" type="inclusive">April 3 - 30, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_17f72212906356d7c8e29a65d2e4fa18" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1d0355b0c2a69eeee0fe1d4e3a23ba38" parent="aspace_17f72212906356d7c8e29a65d2e4fa18" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_9de71332b6e58f0623aae5d1d22ed1ba" parent="aspace_1d0355b0c2a69eeee0fe1d4e3a23ba38" type="page">[249-260]</container></did><odd id="aspace_ed4c2bc632158779a8672d7b5f0cd1b6"><head>Contents</head><p>On April 3, Harrison was one of a number of crew members who switched places with the crew of the HMS Enterprise, so that the sailors joining the Emerald could complete their tour of duty and sail for England, while those transferred to the Enterprise would stay on until the end of the year.  Noted the departure of the Emerald on April 4, describing differences in features between the two ships.  By the 15th they have brought everything (people, guns, etc.) back on board from the shore and set sail for the Shatt-al-Arab, anchoring at Abadan and near Mohammera, ending at a brief stay in Basra before returning to Kuwait.
Tipped-in illustrations:  Seal of the Enterprise (in pencil); ink and watercolor map of "Approaches to Shatt-al-Arab and Kuwait Harbour."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_0358164f970f6e6ad0fe26a37822bddd" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Enterprise at Kuwait, Qeshm Island, Khor Fakkan, Colombo</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41393</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-05-02/1928-05-21" type="inclusive">May 2 - 21, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_d87ed461b500155678e10e56290c3d0d" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ecf6c3c45263f3e9049ad6b10d6e1aec" parent="aspace_d87ed461b500155678e10e56290c3d0d" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_d8201359768bb84e20700d07f3bb8e97" parent="aspace_ecf6c3c45263f3e9049ad6b10d6e1aec" type="page">[260-266]</container></did><odd id="aspace_2c6b2f2e9c149a239b2340f25efb5dd5"><head>Contents</head><p>After receiving news of a conflict between the "Sheikh of Henjam" and Persian authorities at Bandar Abbas, due to the murder of a Persian customs official, and the crew of the Enterprise gets orders to travel there "to protect the telegraph concession which is threatened by both sides." While monitoring the situation, the crew occassionally went ashore to hunt gazelle.  Around the 10th, they departed for Khor Fakkan, and by the 19th, left the region for Ceylon, arriving in Colombo on the 24th.</p><p>Tipped-in illustrations:  water color scenes, "Port of Kuwait" and "Hor Fakkan" [sic].</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_5ef2c8cea1d0d76e20d323913d8d0071" level="item"><did><unittitle>Onshore, at training camps in Ceylon</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41394</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-06/1928-07" type="inclusive">June - July 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8a9fd4b312f99209a23c84127a20ed8" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_c039eb0acafab044186eab4af2470785" parent="aspace_f8a9fd4b312f99209a23c84127a20ed8" type="volume">1</container><container id="aspace_2703d90c621dd7832fcdecab3c4a4565" parent="aspace_c039eb0acafab044186eab4af2470785" type="page">[266-274]</container></did><odd id="aspace_0da6e6bbe7ee4024fb3fabbeed3f3baa"><head>Contents</head><p>The entries are not labeled by dates anymore, but by names of various training camps and installations in Ceylon where Harrison spent time:  "R.N. Camp Diyatawala," "First Camp," "Second Camp," "Ceylon Defence Force."  Describes various "entertainments," from sporting competitions to cinema nights, as well as training and military exercises.</p></odd></c></c><c id="aspace_e41545c75614c95dc96d20391144fba3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Volume 2</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41123</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-07/1980" type="inclusive">July - December 1928, 1930-1931, 1980</unitdate></did><c id="aspace_de3c9ad5df6190e17a2a6ff88cca5dc2" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Enterprise at Colombo, Ceylon</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41380</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-07-26/1928-07-31" type="inclusive">July 26-31, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_987b3fc52ce10c784be645f9cfa5b2e8" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_3ddfb31aeed0cb2d5bd82b0f9a08891b" parent="aspace_987b3fc52ce10c784be645f9cfa5b2e8" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_83a42ebbc475d9d86ae3a5a107377883" parent="aspace_3ddfb31aeed0cb2d5bd82b0f9a08891b" type="page">[2-4]</container></did><odd id="aspace_34ba8338921319942e27bcd9e83014c6"><head>General</head><p>Arrive in Colombo from their last camp, describes sporting activities (rugby, hockey, etc.) with crew from other ships. Describes other ships anchored at Colombo Harbour, including the HMS Effingham.
Tipped-in illustration: pen-and-ink map of Colombo, Ceylon.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_182f043707d37a69195e485acf27f10d" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Enterprise at Colombo and at sea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41395</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-08-01/1928-08-31" type="inclusive">August 1 - 31, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bac92a5b9c160c5887f38a863ad293a" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_6669892f9bfc807c26d7cae0a0ca87fa" parent="aspace_2bac92a5b9c160c5887f38a863ad293a" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_8e950db6e741c7933823dadfb8228893" parent="aspace_6669892f9bfc807c26d7cae0a0ca87fa" type="page">[4-13]</container></did><odd id="aspace_650a978cf58a11da22a81f8c168a5ae9"><head>Contents</head><p>Description of inspection of ship by Commander-in-Chief and Admiral, then with trip to Pattipala (at 7,000 feet elevation) to spend time at a "shooting camp," where they the sailors their hands at hunting.  Upon return to Colombo, the crew participates in various events related to "August Week," such as athletic competitions, dances, and a racing week at the Royal Yacht Club.  On the 29th they received orders to set sail for Mauritius.</p><p>Tipped-in illustrations:  pencil sketch of "The King's Yacht, 'Brittania,'" ink drawing, "Pilot House, Colombo Harbour," ink sketch of "D.H. 66 Aeroplanes at used by Imperial Airways"</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_8a54dd73fd8b7ac048ccc6dbf1f32489" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Enterprise at sea, Mauritius, Mombasa</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41396</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-09-01/1928-09-29" type="inclusive">September 1 - 29, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce24d3fd53ea45a2b9c08c31f6deaa21" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f420c04eab90d569c72a59bf34540331" parent="aspace_ce24d3fd53ea45a2b9c08c31f6deaa21" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_bfe0d2fefee2e0e3f18d8713d077ec06" parent="aspace_f420c04eab90d569c72a59bf34540331" type="page">[13-25]</container></did><odd id="aspace_452045195ae0a14c7d382974a05c8a69"><head>Contents</head><p>Describes the "Neptune Ceremony" upon the crossing of the Equator, and arrival in Mauritius on the 6th, as well as descriptions of the harbor at Port-Louis, the island's people and industries (sugar refining and sisal), and the crew's stay with the island's governor, Herbert Read, at his residence.  On the 14th the ship sets sail for Mombasa, where they arrive on the 19th, with Harrison providing a description of the town and its preparations for a visit from the Prince of Wales, who arrived on the 28th.
  
Tipped-in illustrations:  "Laying out a bower anchor at Mauritius," pen and ink illustration titled "HMS Enterprise illuminated at Killindini" [sic], and watercolor illustration of "Brig at Sunset".</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_8e34f4f36965a4f6f87552672c8a4db3" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Enterprise at Mombasa, Zanzibar, Dar-es-Salaam, Tanga</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41397</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-10-02/1928-10-26" type="inclusive">October 2 - 26, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ac9f8c0064f9e9f0c0de9e3f8cef1b8" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_91861d2c9ca7a470f75ea3021d77c559" parent="aspace_9ac9f8c0064f9e9f0c0de9e3f8cef1b8" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_7368e5b7e7aea561c5eaa47c1704c76a" parent="aspace_91861d2c9ca7a470f75ea3021d77c559" type="page">[25-35]</container></did><odd id="aspace_1a3c57f83244f3d07fa6bfc6e8852d11"><head>Contents</head><p>Description of the Prince of Wales' visit continued, followed by a journey to Zanzibar, where they arrived on the 4th.  Impressions of the town, descriptions of sporting events, including rugby and football matches, latter played against teams of "Goans and Hindus."  Festive dance at the English club, followed by a visit to the offices of the Eastern Telegraph Company and detailed description of the work done there.  On the 15th they sailed for Dar-es-Salaam, where they stayed until the 24th.  Descriptions are given of sporting events, swimming at the beach, shipboard exercises, and the town itself and harbor.  Following that, the crew sailed for Tanga, where there are more sports, and the ship's commanding officers go inland to hunt rhinoceros and giraffe.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_2bc19349e4403508c5867b14997be739" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Enterprise at Seychelles, Aden, and Mombasa</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41398</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-11-01/1928-11-27" type="inclusive">November 1 - 27, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2030739b6fd22e70662aac994338b36" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_c8a29efc5b8f66eabb3b154e93ce5daa" parent="aspace_f2030739b6fd22e70662aac994338b36" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_9ea17ffa6f369d4610849fb3ff1ee65c" parent="aspace_c8a29efc5b8f66eabb3b154e93ce5daa" type="page">[35-42]</container></did><odd id="aspace_baf4cad7be1d2466352fa15106f1ea91"><head>Contents</head><p>Ship sails from Tanga for Port Victoria, Mahe, Seychelles, where it remains until the 12th. Descriptions are provided of the history and topography of the Seychelles island group, its crops (vanilla, rubber, copra, cinnamon), with detailed description of the processing of cinnamon.  Recreational activities while there included several dances, swimming, and catching crayfish.  Left Seychelles on the 12th, bound for Aden, where arrived on the 17th.  Spent time doing maintenance tasks on ship, chiefly painting it.  Left Aden on the 22nd, bound for Mombasa and then Dar-es-Salaam.
Tipped-in illustrations:  pencil sketch, "Approaching Mahe Island."</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_60915b23483b8e710940a681b62f6e0e" level="item"><did><unittitle>H.M.S. Enterprise at Mombasa, Dar-es-Salaam, Aden, Suez Canal, and at sea</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41399</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-12-01/1928-12-12" type="inclusive">December 1 - 12, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_06fed43a33e4c11b2ef78e05be533137" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_efe72fc2a3532513538968147fb70f1f" parent="aspace_06fed43a33e4c11b2ef78e05be533137" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_423a018de8cfceae7b649753acf1602a" parent="aspace_efe72fc2a3532513538968147fb70f1f" type="page">[42-45]</container></did><odd id="aspace_3932429a3c4cd580beb133ef01bd2902"><head>Contents</head><p>Sail from Seychelles to Mombasa, then after refueling, to Dar-es-Salaam, where the ship picked up the Prince of Wales and his entourage, who had been on a hunting expedition in Tanganyika.  Arrived in Aden on the 5th, then proceeded to the Suez Canal, where the Prince and his group disembarked for Cairo, but later rejoined the ship, sailing with them as far as Brinidisi, Italy, where he disembarked and gave a speech commending the ship and crew.  They arrived in Malta on the 11th, departing the next day for Britain, and "the last lap of the commission."
Tipped-in illustrations;  ink and water color map of the Mediterranean Sea and Indian Ocean, and surrounding lands, showing the journey of the three ships that Harrison sailed on during his two-year commission as a midshipman.</p></odd></c><c id="aspace_a869bea10a82bd941782e46dd630de2f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Ink drawing of H.M.S. Enterprise, by Harrison, mounted on sheet of paper with heading "Wallace Agency, Accounts and Secretarial Services," Malindi, Kenya</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41400</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930">1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_dde61b533606ca838b4c2c2fa3010733" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_dfac686b3ba810723c481d716b7dd5b5" parent="aspace_dde61b533606ca838b4c2c2fa3010733" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_3f004f53f94370ab93f0e578e5205518" parent="aspace_dfac686b3ba810723c481d716b7dd5b5" type="page">[46-47]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_2e2190d3a1c881704982fd2bab5eb697" level="item"><did><unittitle>Five pencil sketches of naval battle scenes, mounted on sheet of paper with heading "Wallace Agency, Accounts and Secretarial Services," Malindi, Kenya</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41401</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="0000/0000">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4bd1beeecb644c1c9e9c3cdf0edfb2f8" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f0f91a4616e55c812f8da66e4902b747" parent="aspace_4bd1beeecb644c1c9e9c3cdf0edfb2f8" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_05546a2e7909374e333d2d9cc650b8b5" parent="aspace_f0f91a4616e55c812f8da66e4902b747" type="page">[48-49]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c8b0a3e6d9919b9432fe0a06f44c2b8d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Untitled Ink drawing of a local ship (dhow?)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41402</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="0000/0000">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_4176962386446373dca14bd9b9adb927" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_11feeb79e9992ddca090d7c00e618a7c" parent="aspace_4176962386446373dca14bd9b9adb927" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_22a7766ff836ee9debc585b9f38316db" parent="aspace_11feeb79e9992ddca090d7c00e618a7c" type="page">[50-51]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_62e2cf0c04f9d48493a638a18af328c0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Water color painting of a seascape</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41403</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="0000/0000">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe56792d372d3fd4aeaefe3a1b7781b6" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_5fa508bfa29e3d472743b83616a20164" parent="aspace_fe56792d372d3fd4aeaefe3a1b7781b6" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_df7b97fd0405e04d0e4669068c75da01" parent="aspace_5fa508bfa29e3d472743b83616a20164" type="page">[52-53]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_d25a11b02aa0c14ef22d2a2d897fc1f1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Two water colors of tropical coastline, with legend on verso of each "Gt. Lake Island" and "Gt. Saka Island" [?]</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41404</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="0000/0000">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e425b7c22b5cdbe195c95bbf8bff3d21" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_0ab21d3f5103c2af5a837ff90cdc5981" parent="aspace_e425b7c22b5cdbe195c95bbf8bff3d21" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_52968e309c307725169394db9522c2d7" parent="aspace_0ab21d3f5103c2af5a837ff90cdc5981" type="page">[54-55]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_c3b1082a8cd9f604eb58cc3d91e934cf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Printed ticket to Ceylon Turf Club, and printed invitation to exhibition of art work, both Columbo, mounted on sheet of paper with heading "Wallace Agency, Accounts and Secretarial Services," Malindi, Kenya</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41405</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928-08/1928-08">August 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_c352cc1e97b5cb1ad5a2512db3e7c0f6" label="Realia" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_513fd13e48b8f86c06ade8fe14153b6c" parent="aspace_c352cc1e97b5cb1ad5a2512db3e7c0f6" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_33a1091dad16b91addd601f4261436ad" parent="aspace_513fd13e48b8f86c06ade8fe14153b6c" type="page">[56-57]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_a4d57c217499f766ee08325e38395180" level="item"><did><unittitle>Three printed postcards of cruise ships:  Cunard liner, "Ansonia," and two White-Star Line ships, the RMS Olypmic and RMS Adriatic, printed on letterhead sheet of Wallace Agency, Malindi, Kenya</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41406</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1920/1929" type="inclusive">undated, circa 1920s</unitdate><container id="aspace_aac059a9de972216c5ed6313b0a6145d" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_927dac862362e5118f816513bdc20733" parent="aspace_aac059a9de972216c5ed6313b0a6145d" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_4d79a0d021d798451dbf875ab820e60c" parent="aspace_927dac862362e5118f816513bdc20733" type="page">[58-59]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_442a385db267382acfba89280457b72d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Menu for an unspecified event, Tanga, with pen and ink illustration of ship on cover</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41407</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_2420962f0c2ec5fdca3a2e70bac9a9bf" label="Realia" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_3add5b14ed1ed4cb6a8a0f860500cc3c" parent="aspace_2420962f0c2ec5fdca3a2e70bac9a9bf" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_b6f53b870a6c32e9f51e3d0755276cfc" parent="aspace_3add5b14ed1ed4cb6a8a0f860500cc3c" type="page">[60-61]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_479a203264da785557189de5c56b229f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Two color photographs, badly faded, showing what appear to be Harrison's belonging, including naval uniform, likely taken after his death in 1980, and what could be his gravesite in Malindi </unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41408</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1980">undated, circa 1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a116cdc9f70281c25bf23fd89a775e0" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_075e7611065b027d53bfff67b60b18c9" parent="aspace_3a116cdc9f70281c25bf23fd89a775e0" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_5f4318528825871920334760cd2c7964" parent="aspace_075e7611065b027d53bfff67b60b18c9" type="page">[62-63]</container></did></c><c id="aspace_f40797a9ee5b539ba3483eab91ab9122" level="item"><did><unittitle>Watercolor landscape:  with building and windmill, undated and unidentified</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/archival_objects/41409</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="0000/0000">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b28abde3dafe1acec47210be44e63df" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_257e5913c133fb4012b0f7fc52d72f40" parent="aspace_8b28abde3dafe1acec47210be44e63df" type="volume">2</container><container id="aspace_dfd17ef142cbe5a29087875138a5d010" parent="aspace_257e5913c133fb4012b0f7fc52d72f40" type="page">[64-65]</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
